Chapter 1168: Return to Heavenly South

Han Li transformed into a streak of azure light and soon descended on a plateau halfway up a small mountain. He looked at the seemingly mundane and nondescript rock face in front of him before sweeping his sleeve through the air, sending a burst of azure light sweeping toward it.

A loud thump erupted as the azure light struck the rock face, following which a burst of light appeared over the mountain's rocky surface.

The rock face began to blur as if it were an illusion, following which a massive stone door several tens of feet tall appeared before Han Li. White spiritual light was flashing incessantly over the stone door, and it seemed that a restriction had been cast onto it.

Han Li surveyed the stone door for a while before releasing a burst of flames from his hand, which immediately disappeared into the door.

Moments later, an elated female voice was transmitted to him from the other side.

"Senior Han! We're so glad you're here! Please wait for a moment, my Dao Companion will come out to welcome you right away."

A few seconds later, the white light on the stone door flashed violently a few times before dimming completely. A loud rumbling sound then rang out as the stone door was slowly opened, while two women and one man emerged from the cave abode within.

They were none other than Wen Siyue's couple and their young daughter.

Han Li turned his attention to the young girl, and was slightly taken aback by what he saw.

The young girl had been stickly thin with a sickly yellow pallor on their previous encounter but since then, she had grown into a gorgeous young woman who bore more than a hint of resemblance to her beautiful mother.

It appeared that she had recovered quite well after the poison had been expelled from her body. This was what her appearance should have been like had she not been afflicted by her conditions.

Wen Siyue was the most familiar with Han Li among the three, so she came forward with a captivating smile on her face and extended a respectful curtsey as she said, "We pay our respects to Senior Han! We didn't think that you would arrive so quickly, so we made no preparations in advance; please forgive us for our oversight, Senior!"

"My trip went relatively smoothly, so I arrived here a little earlier than I planned." Han Li waved a hand, indicating for them to skip the formalities.

"We've been eagerly awaiting your arrival, Senior. Please come in and have a seat in our humble cave abode." Wen Siyue stepped aside with a dainty smile to allow Han Li passage into the cave abode.

"Sure. I also want to see the level of mastery your daughter has achieved in the formation spell book I left her. If she's reached a satisfactory level of mastery, then I'll take her under my wing." Han Li nodded in response before taking a glance at the young woman again.

A blush appeared on Tian Qin'er's face from Han Li's gaze, and she immediately ducked her head.

In contrast, Wen Siyue and her Dao Companion were ecstatic to hear this, and they hurriedly led Han Li into their cave abode.

Han Li spent a day and a night inside the cave abode. During this time, Wen Siyue and her Dao Companion, as well as their Foundation Establishment disciples, had all come to pay their respects to Han Li at different points. The elderly man from earlier had brought along a young boy who appeared to be around seven or eight years old to see Han Li, and they also entered the cave abode, but they didn't immediately come out.

Another day later, a streak of silver light shot forth into the air from the small mountain, within which the figures of a man and a woman could be indistinctly identified. A few flashes later, the azure streak of light had disappeared from view.

A month later, within the Heavenly South Region, which was countless kilometers away from the Scattered Star Seas. Within a massive barren valley, several black-robed cultivators were flying through their air on their respective treasures. They all appeared to be quite graceful in flight, but they were absurdly slow and it was quite apparent that none of them were high-grade cultivators.

After flying for a while, the black-robed cultivators suddenly flew toward the rock face beside them and disappeared into an extremely well-concealed cave.

They traveled over 100 feet into the cave, upon which they arrived at a stone door that was shimmering with spiritual light, indicating the presence of a restriction.

The group was led by an intimidating and brawny black-robed man and he strode over to the stone door before making a hand seal and chanting something at the same time. After a long while, he raised a hand and cast an incantation seal, which disappeared into the stone door in a flash, sending ripples running through the flashing spiritual light as a result.

The stone door wobbled slightly before slowly rising into the air.

"Which Junior Martial Brother is it?" Before the group had passed through the entrance, a lazy voice sounded from within. A ball of black Qi then flew out from the cave and reached the brawny man in a flash, following which the Yin Qi dissipated to reveal an elderly man with pale features.

"Oh? If it isn't Junior Martial Brother Meng. Are you here to take over from me?" The elderly man initially wore a dark expression on his face, but he faltered slightly upon seeing the brawny man before immediately putting on a smile.

The brawny man was a mid-Foundation Establishment cultivator while the elderly man was only an early-Foundation Establishment cultivator, so he naturally didn't dare to treat this junior martial brother of his with disdain.

"That's right, Senior Martial Brother Fan! I've been deployed here to guard this spirit mine in your place. Is this cave the entrance of the mine?" the brawny man asked expressionlessly.

"Haha, you sure do have a straightforward personality, Junior Martial Brother Meng. Indeed, the entrance to the spirit mine is in here. However, is this all the people that you have with you? It doesn't appear to be enough." The elderly man was rather perplexed by the lack of numbers in this small group.

"Our Ghost Spirit Sect isn't as powerful as it once was. Most of our disciples have to contribute to the effort to ward off the Controlling Spirit Sect and Devil Flame Sect; I had to work very hard just to gather this group of people. Thankfully, this is the core region of our sect and we're only overseeing some mortals, so this should be enough," the brawny man harrumphed in response, seemingly also very displeased with the current situation.

"That makes sense. You'll just have to work slightly harder, Junior Martial Brother Meng." The elderly man could only nod with a resigned expression upon hearing this.

"That's enough of this depressing conversation. Senior Martial Brother, please take me to the mines and show me around first," the brawny man said as he cast his gaze into the cave.

"Of course. Please come with me, Junior Martial Brother." The elderly man nodded and made a hand seal to close the stone door again before leading the group of black-robed cultivators deeper into the cave.

After a few twists and turns, the group appeared in front of a massive fissure in the ground that several tens of feet wide. There was faint light flashing within the rift and it appeared to be leading to the underground.

There were two black-robed Qi Condensation cultivators sitting with their legs crossed on either side of the entrance to the rift. The two of them hurriedly rose to their feet and extended respectful salutes at the sight of their approaching Foundation Establishment martial brothers.

The elderly man waved a hand in a calm manner before leading the brawny man and his group directly into the rift.

15 minutes later, the elderly man had led the brawny man on a tour of almost the entire mine. There were many passageways within the mine that were rather complex and convoluted, within which there were many young and fit mortal men that had been hired to mine for spirit stones. The elderly man led the way while providing an introduction like a tour guide, seemingly very familiar with every single inch of this place.

It was no wonder that this was the case; if anyone were to stay in this place for over 10 consecutive years, they would most likely be able to navigate the passageways even with their eyes closed.

The brawny man and his group listened carefully, but didn't say much.

After the group made another turn, another passageway appeared before them, this one leading downward, seemingly reaching even deeper underground.

The elderly man's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this passageway and he shook his head to himself. Instead of leading the group down that passageway, he turned and prepared to lead them back in the way that they had come.

"Senior Martial Brother Fan, where does this lead to? Why aren't you taking us down there to have a look?" The brawny turned to his senior martial brother with a perplexed look.

"Many years ago, this was once a restricted area and the sect had deployed a few disciples solely to guard this place, but it's been abandoned long ago and all of the guards have been withdrawn," the elderly man replied in a casual manner.

"A restricted area? What's in there? And why was it abandoned in the end?" The brawny man was intrigued to hear this.

The elderly man hesitated momentarily before deciding that this was an inconsequential matter, and explained, "Nothing much; there's only an ancient teleportation formation in there, but it's been in disuse for a long time and isn't functional anymore. As for why this place was once a restricted area and why it was abandoned later on, I'm afraid I do not know. However, it seemed to have something to do with Martial Uncle Wang Chan."

"Martial Uncle Wang? So it's..." The brawny man was startled to hear this, and his voice abruptly cut off mid-sentence, as if he were extremely wary of something.

"Keep it to yourself, Junior Martial Brother. Martial Uncle Wang is not someone that the likes of us can express our opinion on," the elderly man said with a meaningful look.

The brawny man was silent for a moment before suddenly asking, "In that case, would you be able to take me down there, Senior Martial Brother? Truth be told, I've been studying the way of formation spells in the past few years, and I'm very curious about this ancient teleportation formation."

"You're learning about formation spells? Hmm, that place is rather far away and it'll be quite time-consuming to get there." The elderly man faltered slightly upon hearing this before a peculiar look appeared on his face.

"There's no need to be concerned, Senior Martial Brother Fan. I know the dangers of becoming a jack of all trades, yet a master none. However, I've encountered a bottleneck in my cultivation and can only try some different methods to stimulate myself for improvement. Perhaps I'll be able to glean something useful by studying formation spells," the brawny man sighed.

Seeing as the brawny man was being quite insistent, the elderly man could only agree. "If that's the case, then I'll be happy to lead the way. However, if you actually want to carefully examine the teleportation formation, it's best to do it at another time."

A smile appeared on the brawny man's face upon hearing this.

Thus, the group continued down this passageway.

In the blink of an eye, they had reached an even deeper underground level.

After passing through many twists and turns, they arrived in a limestone cave with passageways leading in all directions.

This place was like a small maze, but there were pronounced symbols along the way to guide them, so they were able to find their way to a small limestone cave eventually.

Within this cave, there was an ancient hexagonal teleportation formation.

"This is it, Junior Martial Brother," the elderly man said as he pointed to the teleportation formation.

"Tsk tsk, so this is an ancient teleportation formation. I've seen some basic descriptions of these formations in some tomes in the past, but I've never actually seen one in person." The brawny man's eyes were shimmering as he looked at the teleportation formation. He made his way over to the formation before walking in a few circles around it, staring at it with rapt focus the entire time.

The elderly man stroked his beard and looked on with a smile in silence.

As for the Qi Condensation disciples with them, they were also quite curious about the teleportation formation, but they didn't dare to stand next to their Foundation Establishment seniors, and could only stand guard by the entrance of the cave.

"I heard that this teleportation formation is actually in perfect condition. It's most likely only dysfunctional because there's something wrong with the teleportation formation on the other side. Otherwise, I'd also really like to teleport to the other side just to see where it leads to. In any case, you'll be guarding this place for many years from now, so you'll have plenty of time to study this formation. Let's go back for now." After a while, the elderly man felt as if they had spent enough time here, so he urged the brawny man to go back with him.

The brawny man still had his back to the elderly man, yet he said something that was very strange and unsettling. "Go back? There's no need for that. This is such a peaceful place; you should just stay here forever, Senior Martial Brother."

A chill immediately ran down the elderly man's spine upon hearing this, yet before he had a chance to react, he felt a cool sensation flash past his neck.

A sword had flashed through, decapitating him in one lightning-fast motion.

The headless body of the elderly man fell straight to the ground!

Translator's Thoughts

Merry Christmas, y'all!!! Might not be Christmas where you're from yet, but here in the land down under, our timezone is pretty much running ahead of the entire rest of the world LOL Making an executive decision to upload 4 chapters today as a Christmas present to everyone and to thank you for all your support. For those who don't celebrate Christmas, I hope you'll enjoy the double upload anyway!

Now for some more cliff notes from our friendly neighborhood Tofu, thanks for going to going to effort to type up these notes for everyone, it's much appreciated, buddy! Y'all know the drill, head down to the comments section and give him/her a big bump if you found his/her cliff notes helpful!

"Wang Chan is (I'm assuming) the same that chased Han Li down when they were both foundation establishment. Later on Han Li (in 703) used the Yin Devil Execution to blast off part of Wang Chan's arm during the betrayal of Marquis Nanlong for the treasures.

"Ghost Spirit is the same sect Wang Chan is from. Ghost spirit sect was responsible for opening devilfall valley for all the cultivators. Unfortunately, in 859, the sect master of ghost spirit sect (and I believe they lost almost all of their nascent soul cultivators as well) due to the devil being released.

"Controlling Spirit sect. In 345, during the Devil Dao invasion, it is said that Spirit beast mountain, once on the same side of Han Li's old sect, was the one responsible for betraying them and helping them win the war with ease. If you recall Doctor Mo in the very early chapter, he had 3 daughters. Eventually one of the daughters married someone who was affiliated with the Spirit beast mountain sect. The daughter would give birth to someone that Han Li meets in 730. It is mentioned that although controlling spirit sect played a big role in winning the war, they still lost to the Ghost Spirit sect as the ghost sect won the inner struggle and gained control of state of Yue."

"Anyway Controlling Spirit sect in 667 mentions "Han Yunzhi" whom Han Li traded for the cloth that could hide his jade bottle from glowing, thus ensuring no one would detect it as it "hid qi fluctuations". Jade bottle being the bottle responsible for all his herbs aging faster of course. They later met in the trial of blood and fire, but it's important because Han Yunzhi is from the same spirit beast mountain that betrayed the state of Yue. Thus she ended up as part of controlling spirit sect that later had the method to allow core formation cultivators to become nascent soul mentioned by Liu Lu in 669. Liu Yu is the girl Han Li took as in-name discliple in exchange for the Six-Winged Frost Centipede."

I'm going to add here that the Devilflame Sect is one of the six sects of the devil dao, first mentioned in (I think) Chapter 647, so check that out for a refresher if you're interested.

Wishing everyone a safe and Merry Christmas!

Chapter 1170: Wing Transformation Sect

"So Elder Cheng must've passed away already," Han Li murmured to himself. He stared up at the roof of the cave and seemed to have fallen into the deep thought.

The roof of the cave up above seemed to have been punctured by Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators in the past but after 100 years, there were no noticeable signs at all indicating it had been repaired.

The brawny man could see that Han Li was rather absentminded, but he still didn't dare to do anything and maintained a respectful expression on his face.

All of a sudden, Han Li raised a sleeve without any warning and burst of azure light swept toward the brawny man's head.

The latter's heart jolted with shock upon seeing this, but before he could do anything, he had already fallen onto the ground, having been completely knocked out.

Han Li took a glance at the unconscious man on the ground before suddenly flicking his fingers in quick succession, sending several streaks of golden sword Qi flying into the formation behind them.

A loud boom erupted and the formation was completely destroyed. Aside from the large crater that had been left in the ground, nothing remained to suggest that the teleportation formation had ever existed.

Seeing as the formation over in the Scattered Star Seas had been repaired by him, there was no need for the teleportation formation on this side to continue to exist. Otherwise, if someone else possessed a Greater Teleportation Medallion like he did, they would also be able to teleport to the Scattered Star Seas.

Han Li wanted this to be a shortcut that was exclusively available to him and had no intention of sharing it with anyone else. He was already extremely familiar with the structure and construction process of teleportation formations so if required, he could erect the same teleportation formation again in this place at any time.

In any case, with his current staggering wealth, the costs of materials for setting up teleportation formations, which had once seemed astronomical to him, were no longer a problem.

After doing all of that, Han Li reached out and feigned a grabbing motion toward the brawny man on the ground.

An immense suction force dragged the latter's head firmly into Han Li's hand. A flash of light then appeared in his eyes as he began to unleash his secret technique.

After a while, Han Li released his five fingers and the brawny man tumbled to the ground once again. Han Li murmured to himself expressionlessly, "You're lucky that you told the truth. I'm not a man who likes to eat his words, so I won't kill you, but I naturally have to wipe away your memories of seeing me appear from this teleportation formation."

Han Li had unleashed a secret technique to alter this man's memories. As such, he could only recall that an unidentifiable high-grade cultivator had seemingly descended from the heavens before killing all of the Devil Flame Sect cultivators, and the ancient teleportation formation had been unintentionally destroyed by the shockwaves radiating from their battle.

At Han Li's current cultivation base, unless if a Deity Transformation cultivator were to step in, no one would be able to break the restriction that he had set, so he could naturally rest assured.

After that, Han Li released a few fireballs to incinerate the bodies of the Devil Flame Sect cultivators into ashes. Brilliant azure light then erupted from his body, sweeping up the young girl behind him as they shot forth, directly upward.

An earthshattering boom rang out and the roof of the cave that had been repaired by the Ghost Spirit Sect was punctured again. The streak of azure light flashed once, and Han Li had already reached the surface of the ground up above. The streak of azure light then hurtled into the distance, completely disappearing after just a few flashes.

After a while, all of the Ghost Spirit Sect cultivators were drawn to the scene by the massive commotion that had just ensued, only to find the unconscious brawny man, and the limestone cave where he was located, which was in a state of complete turmoil. Unbeknownst to them, a sneak attack that the Devil Flame Sect had planned against the Ghost Spirit Sect had been foiled, just like that. Meanwhile, Han Li was already on his way to the State of Xi.

At Han Li's current cultivation, he was capable of traveling at extraordinary speeds. Even though he hadn't unleashed his full speed, the rate at which he flew was still quite astonishing.

Along the way, Han Li would encounter the occasional cultivator, and all of them felt as if they had only just seen a spot of azure light flash several times in the distance before it had passed them by in the blink of an eye, an observation that left many of them completely dumbstruck.

These cultivators were all naturally given a fright upon seeing this. Some of the cultivators with superior cultivation bases were aware that they had just encountered an unfathomably powerful senior, while the low-grade cultivators began to speculate about supernatural activity, thinking that they had just encountered some kind of monster in broad daylight.

It only took Han Li several days to fly out of the State of Yue and reach the State of Yuan Wu.

After flying for a further two days in the State of Yuan Wu, a thought suddenly occurred to Han Li, upon which he hesitated momentarily before flying in another direction with Tian Qin'er in two, temporarily altering his itinerary.

Near a secluded mountain on the border of the State of Yuan Wu, a spot of azure light flashed in the distance. A dazzling streak of azure light over 100 feet in length then shot forth and reached the air above the mountain in the blink of an eye, upon which the azure light receded. Han Li and Tian Qin'er were revealed as a result.

Han Li looked down at the mountain peak and a hint of emotion appeared in his eyes. He swept his spiritual sense downward, and a look of surprise suddenly appeared on his face.

This was the mountain where Xin Ruyin had once resided in hiding. The mountain itself looked no different compared to how it did back then, but Han Li could sense the auras of many cultivators down below, most of which were at the Qi Condensation and Foundation Establishment Stages, but there also appeared to be two Core Formation cultivators among them.

Some of the formation spell restrictions that Xin Ruyin had set up were still in place, creating a dense layer of white mist down below that made it impossible for anyone to see what was going on down below.

Han Li's eyes narrowed as he fell into deep thought.

"Master, is something wrong?" Tian Qin'er blinked and asked carefully.

"Not really. It's just that I haven't been here in a few years, and it seems that some unwelcome guests have settled in this place," Han Li replied indifferently. However, the young girl could see hints of displeasure on Han Li's face, and she immediately knew that it was best not to pry further into the matter.

However, Han Li suddenly turned to her, and asked her something that caught her completely off guard.

"What do you think of this mountain?"

Tian Qin'er was very confused by this question, and she carefully examined the small mountain down below before replying hesitantly, "This mountain? The spiritual Qi here isn't very abundant, but the scenery isn't bad."

"This was the residence of one of my past acquaintances." A hint of disappointment appeared on Han Li's face, but he soon recomposed himself before raising a hand.

A spluttering sound rang out as a crimson fireball abruptly emerged.

Right before Han Li's expressionless eyes, the fireball began to revolve incessantly above his palm, and it began to expand drastically at a phenomenal rate. Within the span of a breath, it had become as large as a washbasin. This was quite a startling transformation.

Han Li looked down with a cold expression before waving his hand through the air, upon which the fireball came hurtling down from above like a shooting star, disappearing into the mist in a flash.

The mist began to tumble violently as a loud boom erupted. A fiery cloud exploded within the white mist as waves of fire surged aggressively, puncturing a hole into the restriction that was over 100 feet in diameter, and this hole was still rapidly expanding, while the mist was reduced to water vapor.

The entire restriction had been destroyed by Han Li with ease using a mere fireball.

The white mist dissipated and the scenes down below were gradually revealed. A series of buildings and pavilions had been constructed on the mountain, yet the bamboo buildings that Xin Ruyin had constructed were nowhere to be seen.

Han Li's expression darkened upon seeing this.

All of the cultivators down below had naturally been alerted by such a loud commotion, and all of them instantly discovered Han Li and Tian Qin'er hovering in the air up above.

A dozen or so cultivators immediately rose into the air atop their treasures as they headed straight for Han Li.

However, right at this moment, a clear voice suddenly rang out from down below.

"Which esteemed senior has come to visit our Wing Transformation Sect? My name is Guan Qing, and I apologize for failing to offer a proper welcome." Just as this voice faded, a streak of red light shot forth from the mountain. The red light outsped the Foundation Establishment cultivators down below and instantly reached Han Li. The light receded to reveal a middle-aged man in a set of scholar robes.

This was one of the Core Formation cultivators that Han Li had detected earlier.

From within the tallest pavilion down below, a ball of yellow light also emerged. The yellow light was traveling just as quickly as the streak of red light and quickly reached Han Li as well before revealing a dark-skinned elderly man with an extremely well-built physique.

This was naturally the other Core Formation cultivator.

Only then did the Foundation Establishment cultivators reach converge at the scene, and all of them stayed behind the two Core Formation cultivators with grim expressions on their faces.

"Wing Transformation Sect? I've never heard of it. Is this a newly-founded sect?" Han Li raised an eyebrow as astonishing spiritual pressure erupted from his body, crashing directly toward the two Core Formation cultivators.

The scholar and the elderly man's expressions changed drastically, and they stumbled back several steps before finally arresting their momentum.

"A Nascent Soul cultivator?" the scholar exclaimed.

"Senior, you're a late-Nascent Soul great cultivator?" The dark-skinned elderly man swept his spiritual sense toward Han Li, upon which an incredulous look appeared on his face.

Han Li made no attempt to hide his cultivation base and this elderly man had quite a powerful spiritual sense for a cultivator of his caliber, so he was naturally able to detect Han Li's power.

"A late-Nascent Soul cultivator?" The scholar was given another fright as he also swept his spiritual sense toward Han Li.

Meanwhile, Han Li stood with his hands clasped behind his back, surveying the two of them expressionlessly.

After the scholar had ascertained Han Li's cultivation base with his spiritual sense, his expression had also become very strained. The two Core Formation cultivators glanced at one another before extending respectful bows in unison, and the elderly man said, "We pay our respects to the esteemed senior! Our sect is indeed a newly-founded one; may I ask for the purpose of your visit, Senior? If there's anything I can help you with, I'll be sure to do my best."

The scholar also wore a respectful look on his face.

This was a great cultivator that could destroy their entire sect with ease, and the two of them were feeling extremely uneasy.

After all, Han Li had just destroyed the restriction down below in an extremely violent manner, and that certainly didn't bode well for them.

Upon seeing their masters concede in such a tame manner and hearing the words "late-Nascent Soul cultivator", the Foundation Establishment cultivators behind them were also completely petrified.

After all, to low-grade cultivators like them, late-Nascent Soul cultivators were at the upper limit of power in the human world. It was everyone's dream to be able to reach such a lofty cultivation base.

"Seeing as this is a newly-founded sect, then you should have a Nascent Soul cultivator among your ranks. Where is your master?" Han Li asked coldly.

The elderly man mustered up his courage, and replied, "Our master is Huang Yao the Enlightened, and he left to visit a friend a month ago. The two of us are currently looking after the sect in his stead."

"He's not here? So be it, it doesn't matter anyway. When did all of you move into this place and where's the person that used to live here?" Han Li asked.

The elderly man was slightly taken aback by this question, and he turned to the scholar beside him as he replied, "Our sect moved here 70 years ago. As for the person who once lived here..."

The scholar was also surprised by this question, but without even turning his head, he immediately yelled, "Feng Zhi! Come here; this senior has something to ask you."

Right as his voice fell, all of the Foundation Establishment cultivators turned to one of their members in unison.

This was an elderly man with refined features who appeared to be over 60 years of age.

This cultivator by the name of Feng Zhi also wore a stunned look on his face.

Translator's Thoughts

More footnotes from our friendly neighborhood Tofu! ChampionTofu really has been putting in a lot of work, so make sure to show him/her your appreciation in the comments section below!

"Anyway more recap about Xin Ruyin. Xin Ruyin's Dao Companion (or husband) is Qi Yunxiao. In chapter 351 Han Li revisited Xin Ruyin's residence because he needed her help to restore the ancient teleportation formation that would later bring him to the Scatter Seas. Upon revisiting Xin Ruyin, it is learned Qi Yunxiao died to the Fu Clan. In exchange for Han LI's promise to avenge him, Xin Ruyin gave Han Li the tool refinement insights of Qi Yunxiao and her formation insights. It's one of the reasons why our protagonist is skilled in tool refinement and formations.

"In 656, it's revealed that Xin Ruyin's maid, Xiao Mei would carry on her will and leave behind descendants that would wait for Han Li's return to see if the promise would be fulfilled. Later on, we meet Xiao Mei's descendant that Han Li would later erase her memories of meeting him while imparting the pills for her son."

Chapter 1173: The Strange State of the Devilfall Valley

Han Li's heart eased slightly upon hearing this.

It appeared that the situation was just as he had anticipated; even without lifting the seal on Nangong Wan's body, she would still be fine. However, seeing as he had already obtained the method to lift the seal, he was naturally not going to waste it. It would be best to alleviate Nangong Wan's condition in case she was to be afflicted by any unforeseen troubles in the future.

Thus, Han Li quickly made his decision.

While chatting with one another, the three of them had already reached the restriction formation around the Drifting Cloud Sect.

On the way there, Lü Luo had already released a voice transmission talisman, so as soon as the two of them reached the formation, the mist permeating throughout the entire restriction tumbled before slowly dissipating.

The entire formation around the sect was being deactivated.

Han Li stirred slightly upon seeing this, but before he had a chance to say anything, hundreds of Foundation Establishment cultivators had been led out of the mountain by a dozen or so Core Formation cultivators, and they arranged themselves into orderly rows as they yelled in unison, "The disciples of the Drifting Cloud Sect pay our respects to Elder Han, and extend our heartfelt congratulations to your progression to the late-Nascent Soul Stage."

All of the cultivators then bowed toward Han Li with excited expressions on their faces. It was quite clear that Lü Luo had already disclosed the news of Han Li's progression to the late-Nascent Soul Stage in the voice transmission talisman that he had just release.

That was why these disciples had gathered together to present such a grand welcome to this "Elder Han".

After all, all of the Drifting Cloud Sect disciples were well aware of what it meant for a great cultivator to emerge in their sect. Their sect would immediately become one of the few super sects in the Heavenly South Region and as a result, the cultivation resources they would be entitled to would be far superior to what they had received in the past. As such, how could they not be ecstatic?

Han Li turned to Lü Luo with a wry smile, and said, "Senior Martial Brother Lü, was there really a need to kick up such a big fuss?"

"Haha, of course, Junior Martial Brother Han. You've become a great cultivator, so the sect disciples naturally have to gather here to present a warm welcome. We're also planning to hold a grand ceremony to celebrate this event, and we're going to invite all of the elders from the other sects to attend. Otherwise, it would be an insult to your lofty status, Junior Martial Brother," Lü Luo chortled.

"Do whatever you want, then. Don't expect to me participate in preparing these events, though; the most I'm willing to do is to be in attendance on the day," Han Li sighed in a resigned manner.

As per convention in the Heavenly South Region, if a cultivator were to reach the late-Nascent Soul Stage, a grand celebration was mandatory in order to inform the entire region of this news. In doing so, all of the other sects would be alerted to this news, and the Drifting Cloud Sect would establish itself as a super sect.

Han Li wasn't opposed to bolstering the reputation of the sect, so he didn't state any objections.

Thus, Han Li descended upon the Drifting Cloud Sect right before the admiring eyes of countless disciples, and entered a spacious hall within the sect.

Han Li sat in the main seat within the hall and Lü Luo sat next to him, but his seat was positioned slightly off-center, thereby indicating that Han Li was the star of the show.

Han Li didn't make any remark upon seeing this.

He was the only late-Nascent Soul great cultivator in the sect and if he weren't willing to take up the mantle, then major problems would arise. Not only would the disciples of the sect be concerned about whether Han Li was abandoning the sect, the other sects would also become suspicious about the situation in their sect. Sooner or later, trouble was going to be brewed.

As such, Han Li willingly sat down in the main seat within the hall, but he refrained from saying anything.

After all, it had been many years since he had returned to the sect and he was completely unfamiliar with the situation within the sect, so it was best to leave the logistics to Senior Martial Brother Lü.

As it turned out, Lü Luo was nowhere near a standout among Nascent Soul cultivators, yet he was very good at managing the sect's internal affairs. He organized all of the new Core Formation disciples in the sect to pay their respects to Han Li one after the other, then officially announced the news of Han Li's progression to the late-Nascent Soul Stage again. Then, he began to hand down some missions to all of the ecstatic disciples in preparation for the upcoming celebration.

Han Li said in his seat with an indifferent expression as he swept his gaze nonchalantly over the disciples before him.

Most of the disciples who had the right to be here were Core Formation disciples, and the rare Foundation Establishment disciples among them were all responsible for important duties within the sect.

No matter which disciple he turned his attention to, the disciple would always lower their head in order to avoid Han Li's gaze as a sign of respect.

After a while, Han Li discovered that his in-name disciple, Liu Yu, and that woman with the Song surname weren't present.

Han Li stirred slightly with a peculiar look on his face upon arriving at this realization.

After Lü Luo had finally finished delivering a long list of instructions to everyone, all of the disciples exited the hall in a respectful manner to make preparations for the upcoming celebration.

"Senior Martial Brother Lü, I don't think I saw Martial Niece Song, there; has she gone out on a mission?" Han Li asked.

Lü Luo chuckled in reply, "Hehe, Martial Niece Song has gone to the Devilfall Valley. She's trying to refine a type of pill, but she's missing a rare herb. This herb is already extinct, yet someone has recently discovered some in the Devilfall Valley."

"She went to the Devilfall Valley?" Han Li's expression changed upon hearing this.

"Don't worry, Junior Martial Brother, this type of herb can be found in the outskirts of the Devilfall Valley. Also, due to some unknown reason, ever since you last visited the Devilfall Valley, the inner valley is still fraught with peril, yet the restrictions in the outer valley are growing weaker year by year, and almost all of the spatial rifts there have also disappeared. On the outskirts of the valley, there are only a few areas where demon beasts may be lurking, but overall, it's not very dangerous. Many cultivators have traveled there in the past several decades and emerged from within with bountiful hauls. By the way, Martial Niece Liu and that concubine of yours also went together with her. The three of them are all Core Formation cultivators, and they brought several powerful treasures with them, so they should be fine," Lü Luo hurriedly explained.

"Is that so? Liu Yu and Mu Peiling also went to the Devilfall Valley?" Han Li was rather surprised to hear this.

"Indeed. I don't know what kind of miracle pill you left behind, but your concubine was able to reach the mid-Core Formation Stage in just a century. The rate of her cultivation was quite shocking, even to me. Perhaps she'll also have a chance to reach the Nascent Soul Stage." Lü Luo clicked his tongue in wonder.

"The pills I left behind was only a secondary factor; Peiling's attitude has always been exceptional," Han Li replied as he stroked his chin.

Back when he first left, he had thought that he would be able to return from the Great Jin in around a decade or so and as a result, he hadn't left behind all that many pills for her that would advance her cultivation base. Otherwise, if she had been given a larger supply of those pills, it was very much possible that she could've been able to reach the late-Core Formation Stage within a century.

However, he had now reached the late-Nascent Soul Stage and the Copulation Essence Arts were only effective for Nascent Soul cultivators, so he would have to think about what to do with this woman.

After all, everyone knew that this woman was his concubine , so even if he were to release her right away, there would be very few male cultivators who would dare to risk irking a great cultivator just to take her for themselves.

After chatting with Lü Luo for a while longer, Han Li suddenly got up and took his leave so he could visit Nangong Wan.

Lü Luo naturally wasn't going to try and stop him.

Thus, Han Li left Tian Qin'er in the hall for now while he headed to the forbidden area within the sect.

A short while later, Han Li appeared in front of the stone chamber within the forbidden area. His emotions were feeling slightly unstable as he lifted the restriction and slowly pushed the stone door open.

The stone chamber had been maintained in a pristine condition, and looked completely identical to when he had last left it. The shimmering wall of ice was still situated directly across from the stone door.

The only thing that was different was that Nangong Wan had turned from a little girl into an exquisite beauty again. However, her eyes were shut, and she appeared to still be in a deep slumber.

Han Li's body swayed and he instantly appeared in front of the ice wall.

He stared intently at the woman within the ice with a complex expression on his face.

Right at this moment, Nangong Wan's eyelashes tremored and she slowly opened her eyes, meeting Han Li's gaze with her own.

The two of them stared at each other in silence.

A short while later, a faint smile appeared on the woman's face as she said in a gentle voice, "I'm glad to see that you're back."

...

Within the depths of the Devilfall Valley's inner valley, an earthshattering boom suddenly erupted halfway up an unidentifiable mountain.

A burst of dense black Qi emerged from a cave before tumbling erratically, and proliferating over an area of several thousand feet in the blink of an eye. Almost half of the entire sky had been obscured by this black Qi, and it was as if an almighty fiendcelestial were descending into this world.

"Hehe, through the use of the devil Qi left behind by that ancient devil, I was able to reach the mid-Nascent Soul Stage in just over a century. I've even mastered the last two layers of Profound Yin Devil Qi. It looks like it really was the correct decision to take such a big risk in coming to this Devilfall Valley. Next, I just have to find a few powerful treasures within the valley and I'll have nothing to fear, even if that man comes again. After that, I'll find a way to enter the Myriad Depth Devilish Abyss, then draw upon the devilish Qi there to nurture this devilish corpse body. In that case, it won't be impossible for me to reach the late-Nascent Soul Stage. Haha, other devil cultivators are afraid of self-detonation from absorbing too much devilish Qi, but I have the body of a devilish corpse, so I have nothing to fear! When the time comes, I'll reach the late-Nascent Soul Stage and kill that man, then engulf his soul. I'll be only Han Li in this world, then, and that's how it should be..."

A coarse voice rang out from within the black Qi, followed by a burst of deranged laughter. All of a sudden, the black Qi surged violently toward a certain direction, disappearing in the blink of an eye.

...

Within a bamboo forest on the outskirts of the Devilfall Valley, a ball of red light suddenly shot forth before fleeing rapidly into the distance.

However, a delicate cry erupted and three streaks of lights of different colors hurtled through the bamboo forest at an even more incredible speed, catching up to the red light after just a few flashes.

The three streaks of light flashed toward the ball of red light, and a peculiar cry erupted from within as a strange bird over 10 feet in size plummeted to the ground.

A white streak of light then flew through the bamboo forest, reaching the fallen bird in a flash before revealing a beautiful woman in a white dress.

The woman feigned a grabbing motion, and a purple herb rose up from the bird's carcass before landing in her hand.

Chapter 1175: Subduing the Two Sects

Han Li was in seclusion in the secret chamber for four days and four nights.

When he finally emerged from the secret chamber with a pleased look on his face, he discovered that Lü Luo was sitting with his legs crossed outside the restriction of his cave abode, and it was unclear how long he had been waiting out there.

Han Li contemplated the situation for a moment, and he could roughly guess the purpose of Lü Luo's visit. As such, a faint smile appeared on his face as he opened the restriction outside his cave abode and strode out to meet him.

Lü Luo was ecstatic to see Han Li, and he hurriedly rose to his feet as he cupped his fist in a salute. "Junior Martial Brother Han, I heard from Martial Niece Tian that you went into seclusion to refine your treasures. I thought I'd have to wait a few more days, but you've come out already!"

"I obtained some things in the Great Jin, so I decided to refine my treasures again. I initially planned to be done in two or three days, but it took a little longer than I expected. My apologies for keeping you waiting, Senior Martial Brother. Have you come here to speak to me about the Ancient Sword Sect and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion?" Han Li asked in an unhurried manner.

"That's right. Almost all of the elders from those two sects have been deployed, and it seems that some of them don't believe you've actually reached the late-Nascent Soul Stage," Lü Luo replied with a smile.

"Alright, then let me meet them to dispel their suspicions," Han Li said in a calm manner.

"That would be best." Lü Luo was naturally very pleased with this proposal.

As such, the two of them immediately flew toward the Drifting Cloud Sect.

A short while later, the two of them appeared outside the main hall on the main peak of the sect.

There were a dozen or so Foundation Establishment Stage disciples guarding the hall, and all of them immediately rushed forward to greet Han Li and Lü Luo in a respectful manner. However, there were a few of them who couldn't but steal a few glances at Han Li.

Han Li's brows furrowed in response, and he harrumphed lightly.

The harrumph could easily be construed as Han Li merely clearing his throat, but to the disciples who were stealing furtive glances at him, it felt as if a thunderclap had erupted right beside their ears, and shivers ran down their spines as they hurriedly buried their heads into their chests.

Lü Luo paid no heed to Han Li's gesture as he asked, "Are he fellow Daoists still in the hall?"

"Yes, the seniors from the Ancient Sword Sect and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion have been meditating within the hall this entire time, and nothing has happened," one of the disciples quickly replied.

Lü Luo nodded in response.

Meanwhile, Han Li had already ascertained the cultivation bases of everyone in the hall with his spiritual sense.

There were two mid-Nascent Soul cultivators and three early-Nascent Soul cultivators in there. It appeared that the grand elders from both secs had arrived in person.

At his current power level, even a normal late-Nascent Soul cultivator would be no match for him, so he naturally didn't regard the cultivators in the hall as a threat.

Thus, he didn't say anything and strode directly toward the hall.

Lü Luo faltered slightly upon seeing this before hurriedly following along, making sure to walk a step behind Han Li as a gesture to highlight who the star of the show was.

Lü Luo had only taken a few steps when, to his surprise, he discovered that Han Li had "disappeared".

He could physically see Han Li, but if he were to use his spiritual sense to try and detect Han Li's presence, he would discover nothing but empty air.

Lü Luo immediately drew a sharp breath, yet at the same time, he was feeling slightly concerned.

This type of complete aura concealment technique could only be used by high-grade cultivators against cultivators of a lower caliber, whose spiritual sense were far inferior to their own.

As an early-Nascent Soul cultivator, even though he could clearly see Han Li walking right in front of him, he was still completely unable to sense his presence. This meant that if Han Li wanted to assassinate early-Nascent Soul cultivators like him, he could literally sneak up right next to them without drawing any attention to himself.

Of course, he was also rather concerned. After all, Han Li was unleashing this type of secret technique in order to intimidate the grand elders of the Ancient Sword Sect and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion, but he had only recently reached the late-Nascent Soul Stage, while the two grand elders were both seasoned mid-Nascent Soul cultivators. If it turned out that his spiritual sense wasn't powerful enough, his concealment technique would be seen through, and far from being intimidated, the two grand elders would scoff at him for playing a childish trick. At times, there was only a fine line between stamping one's authority and making a fool out of oneself.

Of course, Lü Luo was aware that Han Li wouldn't dare to use such a technique unless he had a high degree of confidence in his ability to pull it off.

Even so, he was still feeling rather uneasy, and his emotions were quite conflicted.

There was only a short corridor leading up to the hall, and before long, Han Li and Lü Luo had arrived at their destination.

Everyone immediately turned their attention to Lü Luo, then turned to appraise Han Li with astonishment in their eyes.

Lü Luo was greatly relieved upon seeing this.

It appeared that none of the five Nascent Soul cultivators had been able to detect Han Li's presence, after all.

The five cultivators' expressions changed drastically as they rose to their feet in quick succession.

An elderly man with a head of messy hair stood up, and the astonishment on his face was replaced by a slightly grave smile as he said, "Fellow Daoist Han really has become a late-Nascent Soul great cultivator already. Even with my mid-Nascent Soul Stage cultivation base, I was unable to detect your presence."

This man was none other than the grand elder of the Ancient Sword Sect, Eccentric Jin!

A purple-robed man quickly came to his senses as well as he said, "Indeed. It's only been just over a century, yet Brother Han has already reached the late-Nascent Soul Stage. The rate of your cultivation is simply unheard of."

This man was Eccentric Pyre of the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion.

Han Li had encountered both of these men back when he was attending a ceremony at the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion, and he had even fought Eccentric Jin once before.

In response, Han Li merely smiled, and said, "I was only fortunate to have stumbled upon some opportunities during my journey. I was unaware that all of you will be visiting, and I apologize for making you wait so long, Fellow Daoists."

"Haha, don't mention it. To cultivators like us, days pass by in the blink of an eye," Eccentric Jin chuckled.

Han Li smiled upon hearing his as he turned his attention to the other three cultivators. Two of them were new Nascent Soul cultivators from the two sects, while the final one was a young woman with a set of gentle facial features. This was the female Ancient Sword Sect cultivator he had also encountered during the ceremony at the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion.

This was quite a haughty woman who had once attempted to use a rather profound secret technique on him, but completely failed to assess the limits of his abilities. However, it did leave Han Li with a rather deep impression of this woman.

Han Li swept his spiritual sense toward her, and a hint of surprise appeared on his face as he said, "You look well, Fairy Brightscent. I can see that you've already reached the early-Nascent Soul Stage bottleneck. You should be able to progress to the mid-Nascent Soul Stage in about a decade."

The young woman's expression was slightly strained at the sight of Han Li turning his gaze toward her, and her face paled significantly upon hearing Han Li diagnose her recent cultivation progression to a fault.

Prior to meeting Han Li, the most skeptical among the five Nascent Soul cultivators about Han Li's progression to the late-Nascent Soul Stage wasn't Eccentric Jin or the other mid-Nascent Soul cultivator. Instead, it was none other than this young woman.

Over a century ago, during the ceremony held at the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion, this young woman had also only recently reached the Nascent Soul Stage. However, she possessed a treasure that allowed her to cultivate at several times the speed of a normal cultivator. Through the use of this treasure, she had made several breakthroughs in a short period of time, thereby allowing her to reach the Nascent Soul Stage at such a young age, and she was lauded as an exceptional prodigy in the Ancient Sword Sect.

However, during the ceremony, she had encountered Han Li, who had apparently been cultivating for a shorter span of time than her, yet possessed a superior cultivation base. As such, she couldn't help but want to test out Han Li's abilities. In the end, she was completely unable to verify the extent of Han Li's power, but she still wasn't willing to concede and settle for second-best. She thought that with the assistance of her special treasure, it would only be a matter of time before she caught up to Han Li.

However, only a century had passed by, and Han Li had returned from his travels as a late-Nascent Soul cultivator.

Fairy Brightscent was stunned upon hearing this, and refused to believe it to be true.

However, Han Li had just displayed the might of his spiritual sense, and when he cast his gaze toward her, the young woman had been struck by a sense of asphyxiation. Furthermore, he was able to easily identify her cultivation situation with unerring accuracy.

All of this was extremely shocking to her, and only after a few seconds did she manage to force a smile onto her face.

"As expected of Brother Han, your assessment of my cultivation base is completely spot on. Looks like you really have become a late-Nascent Soul great cultivator. With Brother Han overseeing the Dreamcloud Mountains, no one would dare to offend our three sects."

"Haha, indeed, Fairy Brightscent. At Junior Martial Brother Han's current age, our Dreamcloud Mountains will be safe for at least 700 to 800 years. As for other forces offending our three sects? Hehe, on the contrary, I think it's time for our three sects to expand out of the Dreamcloud Mountains," Lü Luo suddenly said.

Everyone stirred upon hearing this.

Han Li remained silent with a smile on his face, but he slowly withdrew his secret technique, and his aura reappeared before becoming more and more powerful. He was most definitely displaying the spiritual pressure of a late-Nascent Soul cultivator!

The five cultivators in the hall were feeling rather unsteady on their feet in the face of such devastating spiritual pressure, and there was no doubt in their hearts that Han Li had indeed reached the late-Nascent Soul Sage.

After that, Lü Luo began to discuss his plans for expansion with the cultivators from the other two sects. At the very least, they were planning to take over the entire cultivation world in the State of Xi.

From his words and mannerisms, it was clear that he was already regarding the Ancient Sword Sect and the Hundred Possibilities Pavilion as subsidiaries to the Drifting Cloud.

Eccentric Jin and the purple-robed man looked at one another, and they could both see their own resignation mirrored in each other's eyes. Lü Luo pretended to be completely oblivious to their dismay.

...

Somewhere within the outer valley of the Devilfall Valley, Mu Peiling's trio emerged from a rather obscure cave, and all three women wore urgent expressions of concern on their faces.

Liu Yu's footsteps faltered as her brows furrowed, and she said, "This is already the last possible place where Illusionary Spirit Herbs could be growing, but we still haven't found any. Could it be that all of the Illusionary Spirit Herbs on the outskirts of the valley have been picked already?"

The woman with the Song surname was also finding it difficult to maintain her former composure, and she replied, "That's not entirely impossible. If we were to enter the inner valley, we should definitely be able to find some of this herb."

"No, we definitely cannot venture into the inner valley. It would be far too dangerous for us with our cultivation bases." Mu Peiling's expression changed drastically upon hearing this.

Song Yu blinked with a contemplative look on her face, and said, "Not necessarily. I know an old friend of Martial Uncle Han's, and she gave me a map of a safe route into the inner valley. As long as we don't stray from that route, we should be able to minimize the risk of encountering spatial rifts in the inner valley."

Chapter 1176: Detained

"Martial Uncle Han? You're referring to..." Mu Peiling faltered upon hearing this and was beginning to stutter a little.

"That's right, I mentioned him to you once before, Junior Martial Sister Mu. Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit once ventured into this valley with Martial Uncle Han, which is how they were able to map out this safe route," Song Yu replied with a gentle smile.

"I met Fellow Daoist Violet Spirit once several decades ago. She really was an exquisite beauty; even a woman like me was entranced by her beauty. I heard that many prominent male cultivators have pursued her and many intense battles have taken place as they've attempted to compete over her. She's even being referred to by some as the most beautiful female cultivator in the Heavenly South Region. However, this woman is rather mysterious and Master seemed to have made her acquaintance very early on, so she's kind of like a close confidant of his. You're going to have to be careful, Sister Mu!" Liu Yu giggled in a teasing manner.

A faint blush appeared on Mu Peiling's face as she scoffed, "What do I have to be careful about?"

Song Yu adopted a serious expression as she asked, "Stop teasing Junior Martial Sister Mu, Junior Martial Sister Liu, let's get back to business. Are we going to venture into the inner valley or not?"

Mu Peiling and Liu Yu's smiles faded and they looked at one another to find their own hesitant expression mirrored in each other's eyes.

"Senior Martial Sister Song, is the map that this Violet Spirit gave you really a map of the route that Master once took? If that's the case, then we could certainly try it. After all, the Illusionary Spirit Herb is very important for both of our upcoming breakthroughs, and I really don't want to go back emptyhanded," Liu Yu said with furrowed brows.

Mu Peiling was rather hesitant, but she succumbed to the temptation in the end, and sighed, "If we're only searching for the herb close to the entrance of the inner valley, then I can come along as well."

Song Yu nodded before extending words of caution. "Alright, now that that's settled, it looks like we'll be taking a risk. Let me make this clear in advance, though; we'll only be searching the area within several hundred kilometers of the entrance, and if we still can't find the Illusionary Spirit Herb there, then we'll immediately exit the inner valley. No one is allowed to venture in any further. The pill is important, but not as important as our lives."

"Of course. If we were to venture deeper into the inner valley, even with a map at our disposal, it would still be akin to suicide for mere Core Formation cultivators like us. I heard that there are some ancient beasts within the inner valley that even Nascent Soul cultivators wouldn't dare to face in battle," Liu Yu said with a smile.

"Those ancient beasts normally lurk within the depths of the inner valley, so we should be fine if we stay near the entrance. Let's not waste any more time with words; we've already spent a lot of time here so we should make haste," Mu Peiling said in a decisive manner.

The other two women didn't want to delay any longer, either, and the three of them shot forth as streaks of light toward a certain direction.

Five days later, at the border of the inner valley, amid a world of ice and snow, three women appeared in the bone-chilling wind. Not far behind them was a massive ice crystal, and they were situated on the very same path that Han Li and Violet Spirit had taken with the other Ghost Spirit Sect disciples all those years ago.

The three women had already conjured up dense light barriers around their bodies, so they didn't have to fear these biting winds.

After discussing quietly among themselves for a while, the three women rose only several tens of feet above the ground before flying slowly toward the distance, not daring to speed up in the slightest.

This realm of ice and snow wasn't very large in area, so it only took the three of them less than half a day to fly out of this region, upon which an extremely lush mountain appeared before their eyes.

The three of them were ecstatic upon seeing this, and they split up to search for the herb again.

A day and a night later, the three women gathered once again on the mountain's summit. After looking at once another, wry smiles appeared on all of their faces.

"There are many spiritual medicines here on the mountain that can't be found in the outer valley, but there are no Illusionary Spirit Herbs here," Liu Yu said in a gloomy voice.

"Same story on my end. I didn't find the Illusionary Spirit Herb, but I gathered all of the ingredients required for another pill that I'm trying to make. At the very least, I won't be leaving this place completely empty-handed." Mu Peiling didn't know whether she should laugh or cry.

"It looks like we won't be finding the Illusionary Spirit Herb on this trip. Let's return to the sect," Song Yu heaved a dejected sigh.

"Let's do another thorough search. Perhaps we might've missed some places." Liu Yu was unwilling to give up.

Song Yu shook her head as she said in an implacable voice, "Let it go. Don't try to force the issue. The inner valley is too dangerous and even if we only stick to an area near the entrance, accidents could still happen if we stay here for too long. We're leaving right away."

A hint of reluctance appeared on Liu Yu's face and just as she was about to say something, a loud rumbling thunderclap suddenly erupted in the distance.

The three women faltered upon hearing this and they all turned toward that direction in unison.

There, they discovered a shadowy mass of dark clouds that were rapidly flying toward them, moving at such an incredible speed that it was expanding in their field of vision at a rate that was discernible to the naked eye. The dark clouds were tumbling erratically and loud thunderclaps were erupting from within, creating a very intimidating sight to behold.

The three women were naturally able to identify that something was amiss with that mass of dark clouds, and Song Yu immediately exclaimed, "This is bad! There's something wrong with those clouds! It could be an ancient beast!"

Thus, the three of them leaped into the air and immediately flew toward the direction they had come in.

The rumbling creature within the dark clouds seemed to have caught sight of the three women, and it sped up even further as it hurtled toward them. At the same time, a burst of cold cackled rang out from within.

"It's not an ancient beast; it appears to be a Devil Dao cultivator!" Liu Yu's roots lay in the Devil Dao herself, so she immediately managed to identify what these dark clouds were upon hearing the cold cackling.

"Regardless of what it is, it definitely doesn't harbor any benevolence toward us. We can't engage it in a direct battle!" At the sight of the approaching dark clouds, Song Yu was starting to get quite flustered. She hurriedly patted the storage pouch hanging from her waist, and a white bead appeared in her hand.

She then began to chant something, and the bead swayed before transforming into a ball of white clouds and mist that enshrouded the three of them within.

The white cloud then shuddered before flying through the air like a shooting star, traveling at a speed that wasn't inferior to that of the dark clouds behind them.

"You dare to use these pitiful tricks against me?" An eerie voice sounded from within the dark clouds before they tumbled and materialized into a massive black hand.

The hand disappeared in a flash, transforming into a streak of black light over 100 feet in length. Its speed also increased drastically and just a few flashes later, it had already gained significantly on the three women.

"That's a Nascent Soul devil cultivator behind us! We have to think of a way to impede him," Song Yu's urgent voice sounded from within the white cloud.

"I'll release my spirit insects. Even if I have to sacrifice my centipedes, I'll make sure to stop him in his tracks for now," Liu Yu offered.

As soon as her voice fell, seven or eight snowy white centipedes that were around half a foot in length shot forth from within the white cloud before throwing themselves at the pursuing black light.

"Huh? Six-Winged Frost Centipedes! Haha, if it isn't Liu Yu, you little brat! Are you trying to use these little bugs to hold me off?" The man within the black light began to chortle with amusement.

Several thin pitch-black tendrils suddenly shot forth from within the black light, puncturing the bodies of the white centipedes in a flash. Meanwhile, the streak of black light itself simply skirted around the centipedes without any pause or hesitation.

The centipedes were completely stationary as they hovered in mid-air. Only after a short while were they completely engulfed in black flames and were incinerated into nothingness.

The Six-Winged Frost Centipedes were somehow completely unable to withstand these peculiar black flames.

The three women within the white cloud were horrified upon seeing this. In particular, Liu Yu was extremely stunned. She didn't know who this devil cultivator was and his voice sounded very unfamiliar to her, but he had somehow managed to glean her identity just from seeing her centipedes.

The black streak of light was simply far too fast and before the three women could think of any strategies to keep it at bay, it was already upon them.

It circled through the air before transforming into a massive black hand again, reaching out toward the white cloud without any inhibition.

The three women cried out in unison as three swords, a long halberd, and a scepter shot forth from within the white cloud at the same time.

Black light flashed over the surface of the massive hand and it grabbed ahold of all of those treasures. When it spread open its fingers again, all of the treasures had disappeared.

However, in that split second of delay, the white cloud suddenly exploded and three streaks of light hurtled toward different directions.

The three women were splitting up so that at the very least, not all of them would be doomed. However, an incredible sequence of events then unfolded!

A large swath of black light suddenly erupted from the massive hand, sweeping toward all three women at once, and dragging them back despite the fact that they were all flying in different directions. Thus, the massive black hand captured all three of them at once.

The three women were stunned and horrified, and protective spiritual light was flashing desperately over their bodies as they attempted to free themselves with all their might.

However, right at this moment, a cold harrumph sounded beside their ears.

Bursts of black Qi wafted out from the massive hand, spraying the three women directly in the face, upon which all three of them immediately fell unconscious.

Only then did the black hand release the three women and transform into a vast expanse of black Qi. The black Qi then converged toward the center to form a tall and broad humanoid figure.

The humanoid figure's entire body was pitch-black in color, yet its eyes were shimmering with a harrowing green light.

The black figure looked at the three women and cackled, "Who would've thought that it would be these three? This is good; if I can capture them, then that man will be even more wary of me. Hehe, all three of these women are closely related to you; you probably won't sacrifice yourself to save them, but I'm sure I'll be able to extort you a little."

After an indeterminate period of time, Song Yu, who was the most powerful among the three women, awakened first.

She looked around to find that she was lying on the cold hard ground with stone pillars that were shimmering with white light all around her. A jolt of shock ran through her heart and she immediately sat up. At the same time, she made a hand seal in an attempt to unleash her protective spiritual light.

However, a cry of surprise erupted, and Song Yu slumped to the ground once again.

Translator's Thoughts

There's a popular Chinese Internet meme expression that goes "no zuo no die", which essentially means, you won't get into trouble unless you go out looking for trouble. Can I just say that these three have embodied this expression to perfection?

Also, anyone get flashbacks to the screaming goat meme from the "lying on the cold hard ground" part, or is that just me? LOL

Chapter 1196: Vajra Arts and Imperial Elixir

Han Li faltered upon hearing this. A hint of befuddlement flashed through his eyes, and he couldn't comprehend why the Endless Sky Beast was saying this.

"This cultivation art originates from Buddhist origins, but its something that everyone uses in the Spirit Realm. It's even more popular than the basic cultivation arts of the five elements used by Qi Condensation cultivators," the small child explained.

"Everyone uses this cultivation art? Could it be that you're also referring to..." Han Li was starting to read between the lines, and a hint of surprise appeared on his face.

"This Buddhist cultivation art can even be used by mortals in the Spirit Realm who possess no spiritual roots. If a mortal reaches the third layer or above in this cultivation art, then obtains some special weapons, they'll even be able to combat low-grade cultivators and demon beasts. If they can reach the fifth layer or above, hehe, even mid-grade cultivators and demon beasts wouldn't dare to mess with them for no good reason, then," the small child chuckled coldly.

Han Li was flabbergasted to hear this, and only after a long while did he respond in an incredulous manner, "Surely you jest, Fellow Daoist Endless Sky! You're telling me that mortals can combat us cultivators?"

"Hehe, you haven't ascended to the Spirit Realm yet, so there's no point for me tell you too much about it, but this is something that I wouldn't mind disclosing to you; in the Spirit Realm, the mortals are an extremely important force in the human race. Furthermore, there were some exceptionally intellectually-endowed figures among the mortals who studied some basic cultivation arts used by cultivators and demon beasts, and managed to discover ways to refine their own bodies using the spiritual Qi from their environment without having to rely on spiritual roots. In the end, they managed to devise a unique set of cultivation principles. There are even some particularly outstanding warriors among the mortals who have slain high-grade cultivators and demon beasts; this is not something that's uncommon in the Spirit Realm. The cultivation art I'm referring to is known as the Vajra Arts, and it's one of the cultivation arts used most regularly among the mortals."

"Even so, surely mortals still can't compare with cultivators. After all, the vast majority of cultivation arts and treasures are still unusable to them," Han Li countered with furrowed brows.

"Of course. Mortals are still mortals in the end, and no matter how powerful they become, without spiritual roots, they're still unable to pursue the Great Dao. Their lifespans reach a mere 100 years, and even if they can obtain some treasures or medicines that can extend their lifespans, it'll only give them 100 more years to live at most; that's their maximal limit. However, in the Spirit Realm, the postnatal acquirement of spiritual roots is possible. Among the three human sovereigns, the Heavenly Yuan Holy Sovereign was once an extremely prominent and renowned mortal. Only after encountering a miraculous opportunity was he able to attain a spiritual root and become a cultivator, but in terms of power and abilities, he's not inferior to his other two counterparts at all." The small child's expression became rather solemn as he spoke.

Han Li stroked his chin and was at a loss for words.

"Don't think too much about this matter. The mortals in the Spirit Realm are only able to achieve all of this due to the fact that the spiritual Qi density in the Spirit Realm is far superior to that of lower realms. Your human world has endured a devilish tribulation long ago, and the spiritual Qi density here is far inferior compared to the other lower realms. Even if mortals were to obtain the cultivation arts from the Spirit Realm that I mentioned, they wouldn't be able to absorb the world's origin Qi into their bodies anyway, so there's no way that they'd be able to cultivate," the small child explained.

"Other lower realms? Does that mean there are more lower realms than just the human world?" Han Li was very surprised to hear this.

A peculiar look appeared on the small child's face as he said, "Of course! There are hundreds, if not over 1,000 lower realms beneath our Spirit Realm. All of the most exceptional cultivators from these lower realms would ascend to the Spirit Realm, and barely any have ascended from the human world in the past years. However, there have been many cultivators ascending from other lower realms that haven't been invaded by elder devils. I decided to send my avatar to the human world, firstly, because the spiritual Qi is very sparse here. That makes it more difficult for my avatar to descend into this realm, but it makes it easier for me to avoid my great tribulation. Secondly, this is a realm dominated by the human race, so no one would suspect that I would send my avatar to this realm. Otherwise, if my enemies were to learn my backup plan and destroy this avatar of mine, all of my efforts would've been in vain."

Han Li was speechless once again.

He had always thought that the human world was a unique existence, which was why the Spirit Realm had gone to the effort of deploying cultivators into the human world to combat the invasion of the elder devils. However, after hearing the Endless Sky Beast's words, it was clear that there were other factors behind that decision.

"Alright, that's enough about the Spirit Realm. It won't benefit you to learn too much about it for now. Let's talk about the Vajra Arts first. This cultivation art can be used even by mortals without spiritual roots, but it's also renowned in the Spirit Realm for being extremely difficult to cultivate. There are very few people who can reach the third layer, let alone the fifth layer; most of the mortals in the Spirit Realm have only reached the first layer, which will somewhat enhance their bodies, but the effects won't be very useful. Reaching the second layer of the cultivation art requires the cleansing of the marrow, which is an excruciating process that not many people can withstand. However, there are many mortals within the Spirit Realm and reaching the second layer would allow one to become as powerful a low-grade demon beast, so there are always some who are willing and able to endure the painful process. I've never heard of your Brightjade Arts, but I'm sure it's very much related to this cultivation art. After all, there are only a handful of Buddhist body refinement cultivation arts, and this is most likely the only one among those cultivation arts that can be used in the human world." The small child was very confident in his judgment.

Han Li also felt like that was a very plausible notion, and he nodded as he said, "Perhaps that's true. It's indeed been rather difficult for me to cultivate the Brightjade Arts."

"Give me a jade slip; I'll give you a copy of the Vajra Arts for you to examine. If it's the same cultivation art as your Brightjade Arts, then it won't do you much good, but if they're not the same thing, you can choose one between them to cultivate." The small child was suddenly being very generous.

"Hehe, I'll have to thank you in advance then, Fellow Daoist Endless Sky." Han Li certainly wasn't going to decline such a tempting offer. A faint smile appeared on his face, and he flipped his hand over to produce a jade slip before tossing it to the small child.

The Endless Sky Beast caught the jade slip before slowly closing his eyes to replicate the cultivation art.

The smile on Han Li's face faded, and his brows furrowed as memories of a copper plate and another cultivation art surfaced in his mind.

They were none other than the Sacred Provenance Plate, as well as the Heavenbearing Devil Arts that he had obtained from Man Huzi.

There was nothing to be said about the Sacred Provenance Plate; he was already certain that this demonic cultivation art and the Brightjade Arts had both originated from the Elder Devil Realm. Furthermore, they were, respectively, the cultivation art required to unleash the technique, and the mandatory basic body refinement cultivation art. Unfortunately, there was a missing link in the middle, and that was the cultivation art for the transformation ability.

When he had obtained the Heavenbearing Devil Arts from Man Huzi, he had only inspected it briefly before ascertaining that this cultivation art was that missing link. He didn't know how it had become a top-grade devilish art, but that didn't really matter.

What was important was that he had somehow gathered the complete set of cultivation arts. Furthermore, the fact that the Nine Gale Transformations that Han Li wanted to cultivate required progression in the Brightjade Arts made him feel as if there were some kind of profound greater power at work, trying to make him cultivate the Sacred Provenance Plate.

A series of thoughts flashed through Han Li's mind and after about 10 minutes, the small child sitting atop the cauldron suddenly opened his eyes before raising a hand, sending a burst of yellow light flying toward Han Li.

Han Li immediately swept a sleeve through the air, catching the yellow light to reveal the jade slip within.

"The cultivation art has been recorded in there; you can have a look at it first," the small child said in a calm voice.

Han Li nodded and immediately seeped his spiritual sense into the jade slip to examine the cultivation art within.

After just a short while, Han Li heaved a faint sigh and withdrew his spiritual sense.

The small child's expression remained unchanged as he asked in an indifferent manner, "Is the same as your Brightjade Arts?"

Han Li was silent for a moment before replying, "It is. There are some additional spiritual Qi absorption methods detailed in the Vajra Arts, but everything else is completely identical."

The small child seemed to have expected this result, and he waved the aged hide book in his hand as he said, "That's settled, then; if you want to cultivate the Nine Gale Transformations, you'll have to progress to the third layer of the Brightjade Arts first. During that time, I'll alter the Nine Gale Transformations so it becomes suitable for you to use. The Thunderstorm Wings are only a pair of treasures, and not real wings, after all, so some adjustments to the cultivation art will be required. Don't forget that you promised to lend me the Golden Jade Tome after this."

Han Li smiled and pointed to the three container treasures before him as he said, "Rest assure, Fellow Daoist Endless Sky, I won't go back on my word. Before we begin, are you not going to consume any more of this Imperial Elixir?"

The small child glanced at the treasures before shaking his head as he replied, "The Imperial Elixir is indeed a fantastic medicine; it can help demon beasts develop intelligence, and is of the utmost importance for demon beasts going through metamorphosis to attain a human form. For human cultivators, consumption of the Imperial Elixir can also expand the meridians and greatly enhance the body. However, it's not advisable to consume too much of it at once, and it can't be stored for more than a month, so it's currently useless to me. Seeing as you're planning to cultivate the Brightjade Arts, this will be quite useful for you."

"If that's the case, then I'll be taking these for myself." Han Li smiled as he swept a sleeve through the air, upon which the bowl and the jade vial disappeared in unison, leaving only the gourd remaining on the ground.

He then made a hand seal and a faint light shimmered in his eyes. All of a sudden, silver light flashed from beside one of the walls of the secret chamber, and another "Han Li" appeared out of thin air.

As soon as this "Han Li" appeared in the secret chamber, it immediately feigned a grabbing motion toward the gourd lying on the ground. The treasure was instantly sucked into his grasp, and silver light flashed again as "Han Li" disappeared into the wall.

A hint of surprise appeared on the small child's face upon seeing this, but he didn't say anything. Instead, he merely cupped his fist toward Han Li as a salute before also vanishing into the cauldron.

Han Li took a glance at the jade slip in his hand before joining his palms, upon which the jade slip disappeared.

He then slowly closed his eyes and began to meditate in a seated position.

Almost at the exact same moment, a streak of silver light shot forth from the main peak that Han Li's cave abode was situated on. Following a few flashes, the silver streak of light had already disappeared into a certain restricted area within the Drifting Cloud Sect. Not long after that, the streak of silver light flew out from within the restricted area again and returned to the interconnected peaks.

Han Li continued to remain in the secret chamber, yet during this time, a streak of silver light would occasionally fly out from his cave abode before disappearing into the distance. However, the streak of silver light would always return to the interconnected peaks following intervals of several days to around a month, and no one knew what it was up to.

Time passed in a flash, and two years flew by in the blink of an eye.

Chapter 1203: News From the Star Palace

In the State of Yue, located in the center of the Heavenly South Region, there had been wars raging almost constantly among in the cultivation world, and rarely were there any prolonged periods of peace.

The six sects in the State of Yue were first vanquished by the Devil Dao, and following that was a war among the sects of the Devil Dao for supremacy and control over the State of Yue, a war that was won by the Ghost Spirit Sect in the end. However, around a century ago, the Ghost Spirit Sect had lost many of its high-grade cultivators during the battle in the Devilfall Valley, and the Controlling Spirit Sect took advantage of this opportunity, allying with the other sects to force the Ghost Spirit Sect out of the State of Yue.

As such, the State of Yue had since been split among the Devil Dao sects with the Controlling Spirit Sect as their new leader. The current might and influence of the Controlling Spirit Sect allowed them to take over close to half of the spirit veins and spirit mines in the State of Yue, and one of those spirit mines was situated underground beneath a certain large valley.

The spirit stone reserves here were initially quite abundant, but following relentless excavation for the past several centuries by the six sects of the State of Yue, then by the Ghost Spirit Sect and the Controlling Spirit Sect, the supply of spirit stones had finally begun to run dry, and the mine itself was in a semi-abandoned state.

Aside from two Qi Condensation disciples from the Controlling Spirit Sect, there were no other cultivators present to guard the spirit mine.

On that day, the two Controlling Spirit Sect disciples were standing at the underground entrance of the mine, chatting about some recent events that had taken place within the sect. Meanwhile, on the surface of the ground above their heads, an azure humanoid figure burrowed soundlessly into the earth using an earth movement technique, then appeared within a certain nondescript cave in the deepest part of the mine.

Throughout this entire process, the two Controlling Spirit Sect disciples were completely oblivious to his arrival.

Yellow light flashed, and the humanoid figure revealed himself to be a young man with a set of mundane features. He took a glance at an empty corner of the cave, and a faint smile appeared on his face.

This man was naturally none other than Han Li, who had traveled all the way from the State of Xi.

A month ago, after coming out of seclusion in the State of Xi, he hadn't encountered Nangong Wan.

Nangong Wan cultivated in a manner that was different from Han Li. During the past century, she had come out of seclusion on several occasions and traveled to all parts of the Heavenly South Region for extended periods of time in order to train her mind.

When Han Li had finally emerged from seclusion, Nangong Wan had re-entered her secret chamber several years prior to that, and was in the midst of her next spell of seclusion and cultivation.

Han Li was rather disappointed, but nor was he going to disrupt Nangong Wan's cultivation just to see her again. Instead, he merely sent her a voice transmission talisman, informing her of the fact that he was going to be embarking on a long journey, then visited Lü Luo and Liu Yu in the Drifting Cloud Sect.

The two of them were naturally ecstatic to see Han Li.

During the past century or so, the two had worked tirelessly to expand the Drifting Cloud Sect, and it had now become one of the handful of most renowned sects in the Heavenly South Region. During this time, Song Yu had already reached the Nascent Soul Stage, becoming the fourth Nascent Soul cultivator of the Drifting Cloud Sect.

Han Li was naturally quite pleased to hear this. What was surprising to him was that after many years of searching, Song Yu finally found a disciple who possessed an inherently powerful spiritual sense from birth over 10 years ago. However, due to the fact that Han Li was still in seclusion at the time, this disciple was left to cultivate in the sect on their own. Apparently, the disciple also possessed quite an exceptional spiritual root aptitude with a dual-attribute spiritual root.

Han Li's heart stirred upon hearing this, and he immediately requested to meet this disciple. He discovered that this disciple was a slightly thin and frail-looking 16 to 17-year-old young man with a set of delicate features.

Han Li examined the young man in person to find that he did indeed possess an inherently powerful spiritual sense from birth, one that was several times more powerful than cultivators of the same cultivation base. Most importantly, the young man had a very honest and steady personality, which Han Li was very pleased with.

Thus, he cut straight to the point and asked the young man if he were willing to become his disciple.

The young man's name was Shi Jian, and he was already aware of who Han Li was. As such, he was naturally overjoyed that the number one cultivator in the Heavenly South Region was willing to take him as his disciple. As such, he immediately fell to his knees and kowtowed to Han Li, officially becoming his disciple.

Han Li chortled heartily before taking the young man back to the interconnected peaks. He erected a new cave abode for the young man on one of the peaks, and also gave him a copy of the Great Development Treasure Scriptures.

He reinforced to the young man the importance of cultivating the Great Development Technique, but allowed him to choose any other cultivation art in the treasured scriptures that he wished to cultivate alongside the Great Development Technique. The Monarch of Soul Divergence was an extremely talented cultivator, so there were many cultivation arts enclosed in his treasured scriptures.

Shi Jian was still only a Qi Condensation Stage disciple, and Han Li left him a sufficient number of pills to support his cultivation. He also summoned his other disciple, Tian Qin'er, to instruct Shi Jian in his cultivation while he was away.

Even though Tian Qin'er possessed the Dragon Cry Physique, she was also able to cultivate her way to the mid-Foundation Establishment Stage during the past century with the assistance of the large number of pills given to her by the humanoid puppet. Just as Han Li had expected, it appeared that it wouldn't be impossible for her to reach the Core Formation Stage.

After accepting the young man as his disciple, Han Li felt as if a weight had been lifted from his shoulders.

Before the Monarch of Soul Divergence had passed away, he had asked Han Li to find a disciple in his stead to pass the Great Development Treasured Scriptures onto. As soon as the young man reached the Core Formation Stage or above, Han Li was planning to bestow upon him several powerful treasures, then send him to the Far West so he could take over as the Thousand Bamboo Sect Master and receive the inheritance left behind by the Monarch of Soul Divergence.

As for Mu Peiling, who was also residing in a cave abode on one of the interconnected peaks, Nangong Wan had bestowed upon her a secret technique from the Masked Moon Sect, and she had been able to cultivate it to make great strides in her cultivation, reaching the late-Core Formation Stage. She was in seclusion day and night, arduously cultivating her magic power so she could attempt to break through to the Nascent Soul Stage.

However, Han Li wasn't very optimistic about her future prospects. Mu Peiling's aptitude was far from mediocre, but almost every Nascent Soul cultivator had to encounter a miraculous opportunity that was unique to them before reaching the Nascent Soul Stage. Mu Peiling was working extremely hard in her cultivation, but if she didn't encounter such an opportunity, her chances of reaching the Nascent Soul Stage were quite abysmal.

After taking care of everything that required his attention in the sect as well as within his own cave abode, Han Li immediately departed from the Dreamcloud Mountains and headed straight for the State of Yue.

After all, from the message that Ling Yuling had sent him, the Star Palace was in a very perilous situation and was being completely dominated by the Starfall Coalition. Otherwise, she wouldn't have resorted to sending out a request for help using her Myriad Distance Talisman.

Han Li didn't want to delay for too long before getting to the Scattered Star Seas, only to find that Lin Yuling had already perished in battle.

Now, he was back in the underground cave that the ancient teleportation formation had been situated in.

Even though he had intentionally destroyed the teleportation formation on the previous occasion he had been here, he simply had to repair it before he could teleport to the Scattered Star Seas.

What came as quite a relief to Han Li was that there were only two Qi Condensation cultivators guarding this place. Even the most basic of concealment techniques could ensure that the two of them didn't notice that anything was amiss.

With that in mind, Han Li grabbed the storage pouch hanging from his waist before tossing it into the air.

The storage pouch spun in the air before the opening of the pouch turned upside-down, and a burst of white light erupted from within, heading directly toward the ground.

The white light receded, and a large pile of materials about half as tall as a grown man was revealed. The majority of the pile consisted of various types of strange rocks and stones.

Han Li waved a hand upward expressionlessly, and white light began to flash within the storage pouch again.

On this occasion, a dozen or so formation flags and several formation plates shot forth from within. All of the hovered in mid-air following their emergence, shimmering with spiritual light of all types of colors.

Han Li chanted something before gently sweeping his sleeve toward their formation tools.

All of a sudden, these treasures transformed into streaks of light of various different colors, flying in all directions before disappearing into the walls of the cave in a flash.

Large swathes of white mist then began to billow out from within the walls of the cave, concealing Han Li within in the blink of an eye.

If a cultivator were to walk past the cave at this moment, they would simply be greeted by the sight of an empty cave within which nothing was amiss.

The restriction created by the formation had completely concealed Han Li as well as that large pile of formation materials.

Meanwhile, Han Li was already busy at work.

With his current wealth of knowledge and experience, it was an extremely simple matter for Han Li to set up a small teleportation formation, provided that there were enough materials available.

As such, a brand new teleportation formation had been erected in the corner of the cave in just two days.

After examining the formation one last time, Han Li cast an incantation seal toward it.

White light flashed from the center of the formation, following which a burst of buzzing rang out. Immediately thereafter, spiritual light flashed over various spots on the teleportation formation before fading of their own accord.

It appeared that there were no issues with the teleportation formation, so Han Li could use it immediately.

Han Li was elated to see this, and his body swayed before appearing within the teleportation formation in the blink of an eye.

However, just as he was about to activate the formation, he cast his gaze around the cave, and a hesitant look appeared on his face. After a brief period of contemplation, he suddenly patted one of the spirit beast pouches hanging from his waist.

A hissing sound rang out, following which the pouch's opening widened, and a burst of white wind and snow erupted from within.

Immediately thereafter, 12 snowy white centipedes were revealed. Each of them had two pairs of wings on their backs, and they were all very menacing in appearance.

After releasing these Six-Winged Frost Centipede, Han Li chanted something before casting an incantation seal toward them.

All of these centipedes immediately shrank to around the size of a palm each at Han Li's behest. They then opened their mouths to blast out bursts of glacial Qi which enshrouded their bodies, sealing themselves in a block of ice.

Moments later, a series of remarkably translucent balls of ice appeared before Han Li.

Han Li flicked his 10 fingers toward the balls of ice in quick succession, and 12 azure threads shot forth, instantly disappearing into the balls of ice. The 12 ice balls then plummeted downward in unison, disappearing into the ground amid a flash of yellow light.

Only then did Han Li nod his head with a satisfied expression.

With 12 seventh grade demon beasts guarding this place, even a Nascent Soul cultivator wouldn't be able to easily destroy the teleportation formation here. As such, he was feeling a lot more reassured.

Han Li then immediately activated the teleportation formation beneath his feet, and disappeared amid a flash of white light.

Following a rush of dizziness, Han Li appeared on an island tens of millions of kilometers away.

He swept his gaze around him to find that everything remained the same as they had been during his last visit. It appeared that this place was quite obscure and hadn't been discovered by any other cultivators.

Han Li strode out of the teleportation formation, and slashed his hand through the air behind him without even turning his head.

A streak of golden flashed past, and the teleportation formation behind him was sliced in half amid a resounding boom.

Han Li then emerged expressionlessly from within the stone chamber.

Moments later, a streak of azure light rose up into the air from the island, then shot forth toward a certain direction and disappearing into the distance in the blink of an eye.

Chapter 1204: Trouble in the Scattered Star Seas

Han Li traveled directly toward Heavenly Star City, passing by a few islands along the way, but he showed no intention of stopping at any of them.

However, he soon discovered that all of the cultivators that he encountered along his journey were also all in a rush.

If two groups of unfamiliar cultivators bumped into one another, both sides would immediately adopt wary expressions, and the atmosphere would become extremely tense.

This observation made Han Li's brows furrow, and he could sense the turmoil brewing within the Scattered Star Seas.

As he approached the massive island upon which the Heavenly Star City was situated, he saw more and more traveling cultivators. Aside from groups of cultivators locked in tense confrontations, there were even some who were engaged in fierce battles, and it was quite apparent that all of the participants in those battles were not holding back at all, clearly intent on killing their enemies.

In the beginning, Han Li paid them no heed. However, as the instances of such battles increased in regularity, Han Li knew that this most likely had something to do with the conflict between the Starfall Coalition and the Star Palace.

Even though it appeared that the Starfall Coalition was dominating the battle, the Star Palace had been ruling over the Scattered Star Seas for such a long time, so they had to have some trump cards up their sleeves. Furthermore, they also shared close ties with many of the large sects in the Scattered Star Seas. Those ties were not very apparent under normal circumstances, but those powers would definitely step in when the Star Palace was truly on the cusp of destruction.

The fact that there were cultivators who clearly belonged to neither the Star Palace nor the Starfall Coalition participating in the battles seemed to indicate that the Star Palace really was at the end of the road. After all, none of the other major powers would step in unless their intervention was absolutely mandatory.

Of course, Han Li wasn't just going to plunge headfirst into the conflict between the Star Palace and the Starfall Coalition without doing some research first. However, it was difficult to acquire any useful information from low-grade cultivators as they simply didn't know much themselves. As such, even though he encountered many Foundation Establishment cultivators along the way, he didn't stop to interrogate any of them.

On that day, he was hurtling through the air as a streak of azure light when all of a sudden, his expression changed slightly, and he turned toward a certain direction in the distance.

He stalled briefly in his flight before flying toward that direction.

With Han Li's current cultivation base, it only took him several flashes while flying at full speed to cover a distance of over five kilometers.

There, he cast his gaze downward, and a hint of a smile appeared on his face.

In the air at a lower altitude down below, there was a black-robed elderly man and an intimidating burly man locked in a fierce battle with one another, while manipulating a shimmering yellow flying sword and an azure ring treasure respectively.

Coincidentally, these two were both at the mid-Core Formation Stage, and their treasures seemed to be roughly comparable in power as well. As such, they were completely evenly matched.

If neither of them had any other treasures or trump cards up their sleeves to vanquish their opponent in one fell swoop, Han Li estimated that it would take them at least most of a day to reach a decisive result in their battle. Furthermore, it didn't appear as if either man would be capable of killing the other, so the battle would most likely conclude with one side fleeing following a close defeat.

Han Li's sudden arrival naturally came as quite a surprise to both the elderly man and the burly middle-aged man. They reflexively stopped what they were doing and turned their attention to Han Li with wary expressions on their faces.

Both of them swept their spiritual sense toward Han Li, upon which their expressions changed drastically.

In order to draw less attention to himself, Han Li had concealed his cultivation base to only the early-Nascent Soul Stage. However, that was already enough to intimidate two Core Formation cultivators.

The two of them waved their hands through the air almost in unison to stow away their respective treasures, immediately following which the elderly man hurriedly extended a respectful bow toward Han Li, and said, "I am Bi Xun of Fallen Spirit Island. May I have the honor of knowing your esteemed name, Senior?"

The middle-aged man also extended a respectful bow to Han Li with a fawning expression on his face as he asked, "Do you require our assistance, Senior?"

Han Li crossed his arms with an indifferent expression, and said, "You don't need to know who I am. I haven't been here for many years, so I have some things to ask the two of you."

The two men were very relieved to hear that Han Li was merely coming to them for information, and the elderly immediately said, "We'll be sure to tell you everything we know, Senior!"

Han Li nodded upon hearing this, and immediately began to inquire about the events that had taken place in the Scattered Star Seas during the past century.

The two men naturally regarded Han Li as a Nascent Soul Stage senior who had been in an extended period of seclusion, and they hurriedly offered launched into a recount of the past events.

Over 100 years ago, the demon beast of the outer seas took over many islands inhabited by humans, and delivered an ultimatum for all human cultivators to vacate themselves from the outer seas. A battle between the humans and the demon beast naturally erupted as a result.

Strangely enough, neither the Star Palace nor the Starfall Coalition deployed many cultivators to participate in this battle. Instead, many itinerant cultivators and disciples from smaller sects who were benefitting directly from those islands gathered on a large island where teleportation formations had been set up, and engaged in a fierce battle with the demon beasts.

To call it a battle would actually be inaccurate as in reality, it was just a bunch of human cultivators on a few islands, desperately trying to keep the demon beasts at bay by making use of some of the restrictions on the islands.

Cultivators who dared to participate in this battle possessed Foundation Establishment Stage cultivation bases at a minimum. It was said that tens of thousands of cultivators were gathered, and even when split up, there were still around 5,000 to 6,000 human cultivators on each island.

However, as soon as the battle began, all of the islands were completely surrounded by countless low-grade demon beasts, thereby severely denting the morale of the human cultivators, who had initially been brimming with confidence. In the end, the human cultivators only lasted about half a month before all of the islands were conquered by the demon beasts.

Apparently, not even a single high-grade metamorphosis stage demon beast had participated in the battle. All of the restrictions on the islands had been vanquished by low-grade demon beasts, of which there seemed to be an almost infinite number, and just their efforts alone were enough to conquer all of the islands.

In the outer seas, the human cultivators were no match for the demon beasts, so they had no choice but to retreat back to the Inner Seas, then destroyed all of the teleportation formations leading to the outer seas, and temporarily relinquishing everything they had established there. At that point, the Outer Star Seas had once again become the domain of the demon beasts.

Of course, the human cultivators hadn't actually completely given up on the Outer Star Seas. After a few centuries or perhaps even a few millennia of recuperation, the humans were most likely going to return to the outer seas. After all, the countless demon beast in the outer seas provided a virtually endless supply of demon cores to be harvested, and that was simply far too important of a resource for the cultivators of the Scattered Star Seas to abandon.

Another piece of information that Han Li took note of was that the Heavenly Star Sages had passed away several decades ago.

However, prior to their deaths, they had invaded the main base of the Starfall Coalition, using the might of their Divine Essencefused Light to kill several Starfall Coalition Nascent Soul cultivators. The Archsaint of the Six Paths and Wan Sangu were in a secret chamber, discussing some important matters at the time, and they were forced to emerge and face the Heavenly Star Sages in battle.

The two of them had thought that the Heavenly Star Sages were bound to Heavenly Star City as they couldn't distance themselves from the Divine Essencefused Mountains, which was why they had been caught completely off guard by this surprise attack.

After that, a series of events that stunned the entire Scattered Star Seas unfolded.

The Heavenly Star Sages had no intention of engaging the Archsaint of the Six Paths and Wan Sangu in a prolonged battle. Instead, they unleashed some type of secret technique from the get-go, detonating all of the Divine Essencefused Light that they had arduously cultivated for several centuries at once, creating a doomsday-like explosion that had razed the entire main base of the Starfall Coalition to the ground.

The Archsaint of the Six Paths and Wan Sangu were situated closest to the epicenter of the explosion, and even their Nascent Souls didn't get a chance to escape before they were instantly reduced to nothingness.

As such, the most powerful beings of the Star Palace and the Starfall Coalition had been wiped off the face of the world in the blink of an eye. In comparison, the Starfall Coalition had been reduced to a far inferior state compared to the Star Palace.

After all, the Archsaint of the Six Paths and Wan Sangu weren't the only ones who had perished during the attack. At the time, there were several elders and a high number of Core Formation cultivators present at the main base as well, and they had also been killed.

As expected, in the following two to three decades, Ling Yuling took over the Star Palace and forced the Starfall Coalition into a steady decline, making the latter lose a lot of territory in the process.

All of the sects that were a part of the Starfall Coalition had been placed on the Star Palace's hit list, so they had no choice but to grit their teeth and try to weather the storm. Otherwise, it was quite possible that the Starfall Coalition would’ve been disbanded a long time ago.

Just as it appeared as if the Starfall Coalition were about to be vanquished, an astonishing event suddenly took place, heralding the resurgence of the Starfall Coalition.

The Sect Master of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment, Wan Tianming, progressed to the late-Nascent Soul Stage amid the crisis, becoming the newest great cultivator on the Scattered Star Seas.

As such, the Starfall Coalition was immediately able to turn the tables. As a late-Nascent Soul cultivator, Wan Tianming was able to unite the entire coalition, becoming the undisputed coalition leader. After that, he slew several Star Palace elders in battle, and forged a resounding reputation for himself.

In the following few decades, the Star Palace was no match for Wan Tianming's aggressive assaults as they had no great cultivators to stand against him. Thus, the Starfall Coalition stormed back with a vengeance, recovering all of their lost territories, then claiming some more. Soon, the Star Palace had been plunged into an even more perilous situation than when the Archsaint of the Six Paths and Wan Sangu were still alive. Not long ago, the Starfall Coalition had opened up a pathway into the Heavenly Star City, and sent out a batch of their Ghost Crests again. All sects and powers that received the crests had to confirm to whom they pledged their allegiance. If they didn't join the Starfall Coalition in their assault against the Star Palace, then they would be regarded as enemies of the Starfall Coalition, and would be eradicated as a result. The Starfall Coalition was all set to attack the Star Palace, and were taking no prisoners.

Sure enough, Wan Tianming backed up his threat by actually destroying a few sects that were allied with the Star Palace, and the entire Scattered Star Seas was completely riled up as a result.

The sects that had pledged their allegiance to the Star Palace and the Starfall Coalition, as well as the sect that simply wanted to take a neutral stance, were all forced to take action. Some of them completely shut off their sects and hid within their restrictions, some of them fled to the Heavenly Star City for refuge, and there were many that took this opportunity to expand by taking over abandon territories.

In any case, the Scattered Star Seas was in complete turmoil.

The Starfall Coalition's army of cultivators took this opportunity to gather on a few islands near the Heavenly Star City, and it appeared that they had deployed all of their most powerful cultivators in preparation for the final battle.

it appeared that Wan Tianming didn't want to prolong this battle any longer. He simply wanted to destroy the Star Palace and end this conflict once and for all.

However, when was the battle going to commence? And how many cultivators had been gathered on the islands near Heavenly Star City?

Neither the elderly man nor the middle-aged man could provide answers to those questions.

Most of the cultivators in the Scattered Star Seas wanted nothing better than to avoid this battle altogether, but many of them were simply unable to do so and were forced to take a side.

As for whether they had joined the Star Palace or the Starfall Coalition, that was only something that they themselves knew.

As such, there were spies all over the place trying to ascertain which side everyone was allied to, plunging the area around the Heavenly Star City into complete turmoil.

Furthermore, it only became more and more chaotic as one approached the Heavenly Star City.

Han Li had heard all of the information he wanted to hear, and he fell into deep thought, sparing the two Core Formation cultivators from further interrogation.

Chapter 1209: Battle at the Star Palace (5)

The brightness of the blue light barrier immediately increased, following which a circular passageway around 10 feet in diameter appeared.

Han Li briefly examined the passageway that had opened up in front of him before flying into it as a streak of azure light, appeared on the other side in the blink of an eye.

The light barrier shuddered again, and the passageway disappeared.

Ling Yuling turned to Han Li with an elated smile on her face as she said, "Fellow Daoist Han, you're finally here."

"I made a promise to your parents, so I certainly couldn't ignore your request for help in your time of need," Han Li replied with a smile.

"I'm extremely grateful for your assistance, Brother Han. With you here, there's no need for us to fear those Starfall Coalition clowns. This is not the place to talk; come with me to the sacred mountain, Fellow Daoist Han. Elder Sun, inform all of the elders who aren't currently on duty to gather at the sacred palace; I have important matters to discuss with them." Ling Yuling extended an invitation to Han Li before issuing some instructions to the yellow-robed cultivator beside her.

"Yes, Palace Master!"

The yellow-robed cultivator was an early-Nascent Soul cultivator, and as soon as Han Li had passed through the light barrier, he had tried to ascertain Han Li's cultivation base using his spiritual sense. What he discovered was that Han Li's cultivation base was completely unfathomable to him, and a hint of awe and veneration intermingled with shock appeared on his face. After hearing Ling Yuling's orders, he immediate cupped his fist in a salute before pulling out a stack of voice transmission talisman to inform the Star Palace elders of the palace master's instructions.

At this moment, Han Li turned toward the white-haired elderly man, and said, "Long time no see, Fellow Daoist Zhao; you're looking quite well. Not only that, but your cultivation base has also improved drastically. I must congratulate you."

The elderly man was none other than the very same Elder Zhao who had approached Han Li with that dual cultivation proposal on Silver Shark Island. It had been more than a century since Han Li had last seen him, and he had reached the mid-Nascent Soul Stage as well, just as Ling Yuling had.

However, a wry smile appeared on Elder Zhao's face upon hearing this, indicating that there were some hidden circumstances involved behind his breakthrough. "Hehe, I wouldn't have been able to take this step by myself. It's all thanks to the two former palace masters that I was able to take another strike in my cultivation base."

"Oh, I see." A contemplative look appeared on Han Li's face after hearing this.

"So you and Elder Zhao are old acquaintances as well; I'm glad to see that. Let's head to the sacred palace first, and we'll continue our conversation there," Ling Yuling suggested with a smile.

Han Li naturally had no objections to this, and he nodded in response.

Thus, the group rose into the air and flew toward the sacred mountain at the center of Heavenly Star City.

Under the guidance of Ling Yuling and the others, Han Li flew directly toward the highest level of the sacred mountain before descending in front of what appeared to be a very nondescript bluestone palace.

Han Li appraised the stone palace with a hint of surprise on his face.

"Do you find our sacred palace to be too mundane, Brother Han?" Ling Yuling turned to Han Li with a dainty smile.

"It's indeed not what I was expecting." Han Li made no effort to deny this.

"It does indeed look quite ordinary, but all of our past palace masters have cultivated here before, so it was preserved and is regarded as one of the most important places in our Star Palace. We normally wouldn't let outsiders set foot into this palace, but you came from afar to help us in our time of need, so you're naturally exempt from this rule, Brother Han," Ling Yuling explained with a smile.

"The palace itself does look quite mundane, but there's a remarkable abundance of spiritual Qi in the surrounding area, so it's an exceptional place to cultivate in. I doubt there would be many islands on the Inner Star Seas that could provide a cultivation environment comparable to this one." Han Li nodded in response.

Ling Yuling's smile widened upon hearing this, and she immediately led Han Li toward the gates of the stone palace.

The dozen or so Star Palace disciples guarding the gate hurriedly extended respectful bows toward their group, and all of them wore rather curious expressions at the sight of Han Li.

Ling Yuling naturally wasn't going to waste time providing an explanation to these guards as she led Han Li into the palace. Their group filed into a short corridor before arriving in an antiquated hall, where all of them took a seat.

"Brother Han, you must've learned about our Star Palace's situation on your way here, right?" Ling Yuling cut straight to the point.

"Of course. It appears that the Star Palace is in a rather perilous situation," Han Li replied calmly.

"Then I suppose you're also aware of the fact that our Star Palace had initially gained the upper hand, and we've only been plunged into this situation because that Wan Tianming suddenly reached the late-Nascent Soul Stage. Only after he became a great cultivator did the Starfall Coalition manage to turn the tables, so he is the key in this battle. Brother Han, as long as you can hold off that man, I'm confident that our Star Palace would be able to destroy the Starfall Coalition again!" A cold look appeared in Ling Yuling's eyes as she spoke.

"So you want me to fight that Sect Master Wan?" Han Li asked.

Ling Yuling faltered slightly, and a hesitant look appeared on her face as she asked, "Are you unhappy with that arrangement, Brother Han?"

Han Li raised an eyebrow, and replied, "It's not that; I just think there seems to be a misunderstanding here, Fairy Ling."

"A misunderstanding? Could it be that you're not here to help me, Brother Han?" Ling Yuling's expression changed slightly upon hearing this.

"Of course I'm here to help you, it's just that..." Han Li was just about to explain when his words came to a halt, and he suddenly turned toward the entrance of the hall.

Ling Yuling naturally also cast her gaze toward the same direction.

Moments later, three cultivators strode into palace, one of which was a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator, while the other two were at the early-Nascent Soul Stage.

The mid-Nascent Soul cultivator was a purple-robed man with a pockmarked face. After entering the hall, he refrained from extending a salute toward Ling Yuling, and instead turned toward Han Li with an unfriendly expression, giving off a rather uncouth and antagonistic demeanor.

However, his pupils immediately contracted as he swept his spiritual sense toward Han Li, and his expression became quite strained.

At this moment, Ling Yuling smiled, and said, "Elder Ma, I didn't think you'd get here so quickly. Have a seat. When all of the other elders get here as well, I'll introduce to everyone an esteemed guest of our Star Palace!"

"Indeed, I can sense that this fellow Daoist possesses an unfathomable cultivation base, so a warm welcome is very much necessary." The purple-robed man quickly composed himself before giving Han Li a forced smile and taking a seat. After assessing Han Li's cultivation base, he was clearly a lot more subdued than he was just a second ago.

The other two Star Palace elders were naturally unable to identify Han Li's cultivation base, but the purple-robed man's reaction told them everything they needed to know. As such, they exchanged an astonished glance with one another before cupping their fists in a salute toward Ling Yuling and also taking a seat.

However, in response to this, Ling Yuling merely tucked a few stray strands of hair behind her ear as a cold light flashed through her eyes.

Han Li was observing all of these minor details, and a hint of a smile appeared on her face.

It was quite clear that this Elder Ma wasn't content to serve this new master of the Star Palace, and Ling Yuling was using him to intimidate these elders and keep them in check. Han Li was feeling both rather amused and a little speechless.

However, Ling Yuling was an old acquaintance of his, so he didn't take this to heart. After all, what she was doing wasn't causing harm to him in any way.

Following the arrival of Elder Ma's trio, the rest of the Star Palace elders also began to arrive at the sacred palace one after the other. All of them were immediately given quite a surprise by the sight of the unfamiliar great cultivator present among their ranks.

Even though none of these Nascent Soul Stage elders could ascertain Han Li's true cultivation base, all of them turned to Elder Ma as a litmus test for Han Li's power, and all of them were quite stunned by what they saw.

Before long, over 20 Star Palace elders had gathered in the hall. Aside from three mid-Nascent Soul cultivators, Elder Zhao, Elder Ma, and Ling Yuling, all of the rest were at the early-Nascent Soul Stage.

Ling Yuling slowly rose to her feet and pointed at Han Li with a smile as she announced, "Seeing as everyone's here, let me introduce to you all an esteemed guest. This is the guest elder appointed by the former palace masters, Han Li!"

All of the elders present had naturally heard of Han Li before, and Ling Yuling's announcement created quite a stir among them, to the extent that one of them couldn't help but exclaim, "Han Li?!"Han Li turned toward the Star Palace elder who had spoken to find that it was a benevolent-looking white-robed elderly man.

Han Li's eyes narrowed as a contemplative look appeared in his eyes. All of a sudden, a thought seemed to have occurred to him as his expression darkened.

"It appears that we've met in the Heavenvoid Hall before. I recall that there were two fellow Daoists responsible for opening the Heavenvoid Hall back then; may I ask where he is?" Han Li's voice had become rather cold and unforgiving.

Meanwhile, the white-robed elder's face had turned deathly pale.

This man was none other than the Star Palace enforcement elder who had almost stabbed Han Li through the heart in the Heavenvoid Hall. Back when he had just entered the hall, he had found Han Li to be rather familiar, but he failed to immediately identify him. However, Ling Yuling's introduction made him recall the memories of the events that had taken place in the Heavenvoid Hall, and he naturally managed to identify Han Li.

Ling Yuling could naturally glean the cold look in Han Li's eyes, and her heart sank in response, but she could only muster up her courage, and ask, "Do you recognize Elder Ximen, Brother Han?"

A series of emotions quickly flashed through Han Li's eyes, and he seemed to have arrived at some sort of decision as he reverted back to his normal calm expression, and replied, "I'm not very familiar with him. It's just that Fellow Daoist Ximen had caused some trouble for me back when I hadn't reached the Nascent Soul Stage."

Ling Yuling was quite relieved that Han Li was making light of the matter, and she hurriedly changed the subject as she said, "I see. If Elder Ximen caused you any offense in the past, I hope you may forgive him, Brother Han. Let's get back to our discussion about Wan Tianming, shall we? After all, the top priority for our Star Palace is to eradicate the Starfall Coalition!"

The white-robed elder was also slightly relieved after hearing Han Li's words, but he was still unable to completely quell the fear in his heart.

"I don't know what the late sages told you, Fellow Daoist Ling, but the promise I made to them was that I would only step in if and when your life is under direct threat, and I'll do everything in my power to save you. I didn't promise them that I would fight for the Star Palace against a cultivator of the same cultivation base as mine to the death," Han Li said in a slow voice.

His words were met with complete silence.

Chapter 1214: Battle at the Star Palace (10)

“Double the price? Fellow Daoist Wan is truly generous!” Han Li laughed and wore a mysterious smile on his face.

“Do you feel it isn’t enough?” Wan Tianming asked with a calm tone.

“Oh, it’s enough, plenty enough. It is a pity that I am fighting this war due to a promise I made many years ago, and I’m not fond of breaking my promises. But if you were to peacefully withdraw, I’ll consider your offer for the next time.” Han Li lazily replied with a clear mocking tone.

These words left the cultivators on both sides flabbergasted.

Wan Tianming’s smile disappeared to be replaced with a gloomy expression.

“Since Brother Han has made his decision, then we will have to test our might. However, our battle will bring disaster to our juniors nearby. Wouldn’t it be better to fight somewhere farther?” Wan Tianming said icily.

“Yes, I had that in mind as well.” Han Li promptly agreed without the slightest consideration.

This had surprised Wan Tianming, but after he gloomily examined Han Li, he held his hands in an incantation gesture and turned into a purple streak, flying in the direction away from Heavenly Star City.

Han Li turned around and took a glance at Ling Yuling and the others. He nodded with a smile and closely followed after him in an azure streak.

In the blink of an eye, the two late-Nascent Soul cultivators tore through the air and disappeared out of sight.

Ling Yuling and Old Man Chao exchanged a glance, both revealing a trace of worry from their faces.

Wan Tianming had already known about Han Li’s existence and took the initiative to challenge him to a fight. Could it be he had another plan in mind? However, Han Li didn’t hesitate in following him. This only added to their apprehension as dissuading him would only damage their morale.

The man from the Lan Devils extended a scarlet tongue and licked his lips before letting out a bewildering cackle. “Hehe, since Fellow Daoist Wan is gone, its time to take action. Let’s see how your abilities stand up, junior. Tch tch, it's been several hundred years since I’ve killed a Nascent Soul-grade cultivator.”

Afterward, he held his hands in an incantation gesture and spouted out a white bone band. At that same time, a blood mist was released from his body, filling the nearby hundred meters in an instant. Ghost shrieks loudly wailed from within it as it moved to engulf the Star Palace cultivators.

Following that, the dainty woman at the large man’s side let out a giggle of ecstasy and waved her sleeve, producing a fragrant pink fog. Those who smelled it would lose their sense of self.

Old Man Long and the old woman exchanged a glance before spitting out a golden ball and thirteen green blades respectively before sending it off in an attack.

When the Star Palace cultivators saw this, they didn’t dare to delay and made use of their own abilities, releasing their light in return.

Several of the Star Palace’s early Nascent Soul cultivators met the attacks of the mid-Nascent Soul stage Lan Devils. Various lights met the devilish Qi, followed by violent explosions. The attacks found themselves in a deadlock.

When the lower-grade cultivators saw this, they all shouted and rallied themselves, releasing their own magic tools and treasures as they charged forward, officially starting the melee.

Of course, these cultivators all kept their distance from the battles of the Nascent Soul-grade cultivators taking place at the center.

For a time, sounds of explosions and murder filled the air. The chaos prevented anyone from seeing which side had the advantage, and it was clear the battle wouldn’t end anytime soon.

Meanwhile, Han Li and Wan Tianming turned to streaks of light and traveled nearly five hundred kilometers in a single breath before eventually coming to a stop.

Han Li appeared from the azure light and observed him with his hands behind his back, not the slightest expression betrayed from his face.

With his vast spiritual sense as of current, he could tell if there were any cultivators hiding nearby. He wouldn’t have allowed Wan Tianming to lead him otherwise.

After sweeping his spiritual sense in a radius of fifty kilometers, he found nobody nor did he find any spell formation or restrictions. When he glanced again at Wan Tianming, he saw a calm expression on his face.

As thoughts churned in his mind, he found the situation quite funny.

It appeared Wan Tianming was the same as himself, with complete trust in their combat abilities.

Wan Tianming looked around him before turning his gaze back to Han Li. With a demeanor similar to an iceberg, he coldly said, “This should be far enough. If we use this as your gravesite, it shouldn’t disgrace your status as a grand cultivator.”

“My gravesite?” Han Li remained unshaken and simply smiled.

Wan Tianming snorted and asked, “What? Do you feel that I am talking too highly of myself?”

Han Li chuckled unperturbed and leisurely said, “No, I only feel that there is something amiss with your recent cultivation. You might’ve progressed your magic power so quickly that you damaged your head.”

“We’ll see if my words hold true when I scatter your soul. But before that, there are two people I wish to introduce to you.”

Han Li coldly smiled and replied with a blunt tone, “Do you think I am a child? There is no one here apart from you and me. I’ll have your head and give it to you as a gift.”

Wan Tianming narrowed his eyes, “Is that so? Then it is my mistake. These two aren’t considered people after all.”

With that said, he didn’t wait for Han Li to respond. He took a black leather pouch at his waist and tossed it into his air. Then with his hands in an incantation gesture, he began to chant.

Suddenly, the bag opened itself, spitting out a black mist. A tall and a skinny silhouette appeared there, drifting erratically in the mist as if they were ghosts.

“Refined corpses?” Han Li frowned. As experienced as he was, he immediately recognized the mist before him to be an extremely potent corpse Qi.

Wan Tianming coldly smiled when he heard it and cast a spell seal.

The two silhouettes raised their arms, absorbing the nearby corpse Qi in great force, turning the mist into snakes that burrowed into their bodies.

In the blink of an eye, the black corpse Qi disappeared and the corpses' true faces were revealed.

Han Li glanced at the two corpses with indifference.

This was to be expected. He was rather unfamiliar with the appearance of these corpses.

Of the two corpses, one was tall and had a tense expression. It appeared over forty years of age, but its arms had an extra extension and reached down to its knees. Its palms were exceptionally large as well and they sparkled as if they were carved from fine white jade.

The smaller refined corpse was a woman of about thirty years. She had a slim face, deep eyes, and a rough brow. One of her shoulders had three differently styled swords nailed into it, creating a warped appearance.

When Wan Tianming saw Han Li disregard the two refined corpses, a harsh expression appeared on his face.

He took a deep breath and his hand gesture changed. Suddenly, frightful sounds of breaking bones snapped from his body and he promptly grew several inches. He then opened his mouth and violently spouted out mists of purple Qi, enveloping himself in a ten-meter-wide cloud in the blink of an eye.

Soon after, the cloud fiercely turned and began to shine of ever-changing colors.

When Han Li saw this, he stroked his chin and he broke into a smirk. He dropped his hands, summoning a three-colored fiery streak from one of them and a green light from the other.

Han Li remained indifferent. His plan was to use pure force and a full-powered assault to beat down the enemy, no matter what methods they used. First, he would use the Eight Spirit Ruler to trap him, and then approach closer to him, finishing him off with a full-powered attack of the Triflame Fan.

Having thought that, blue light flickered from his eyes and muffled thunder rang from his back, summoning a pair of azure-white wings.

Just as he thought to use his wings to approach him, he was stunned by what he witnessed!

His appearance completely changed within the cloud and the sounds of snapping bones came to a stop. Afterward, astonishing devilish Qi pressured the air and the cloud turned sinisterly grey and icy cold.

Han Li’s pupils narrowed and his heart thumped.

Wasn’t Wan Tianming the sect master of the Myriad Gates of Enlightenment? How could he cultivate Devil Dao Arts? Rather, this devilish Qi was quite familiar and was somewhat similar to the Elder Devil’s true devil Qi. Soon, something came to mind, but he couldn't fully recall as he wasn’t in a position to take his time.

As Han Li was bewildered, a series of wild laughs echoed from the devilish Qi as a silhouette warped in front of him.

Behind this person was six distinct phantoms that appeared solid, each with a horn on their head or fangs. All of them were frightening to the eye and had scales on their body, appearing like the devils that once appeared in this world.

“The Six Apex Devils Art!” Han Li cried out.

“Oh? You recognize this lord’s devil art? You aren’t so stupid after all!” His laughter came to a stop and he coldly looked at Han Li with an attitude of complete arrogance, derision clear on his face.

He still wore Wan Tianming’s clothes but his face was completely different.

When Han Li saw his face, he couldn't help but betray his shock.

Chapter 1218: Battle at the Star Palace (14)

As Archsaint Six Paths split into two, the two-headed serpent spat out a torrent of inky liquid beneath it, creating a toxic mist that enveloped everything thirty meters below it.

Explosions relentlessly exploded. Black light and the knife struck and erupted in a ball of blinding black light.

It was unknown what treasure Six Paths released, but it managed to block the Devil Essence Diamond knife.

Silver light flashed and the puppet strangely appeared at the old devil’s original position. The roiling toxic mist enveloped it completely.

Following its appearance, the two-headed snake rocked its head and dived at the puppet.

But in the next moment, a silver lotus appeared above the serpent’s head without warning. It was a foot-large and glowed brightly with seven-colored Buddhist light.

The black serpent’s movements immediately slowed as the Buddhist light trapped it and stopped it immediately. Only its two pairs of green eyes were moving.

Immediately after, two silver threads swiftly cut through the green mist and wrapped around the serpent’s two heads, only for them to topple off.

Then as the green mist roiled, the human puppet slowly flew out without displaying the slightest damage.

In truth, the serpent was actually an exceptional beast. The toxic mist was on par with the Ten Absolute Poisons of the cultivation world. If common cultivators touched it, they would immediately perish.

But this wasn’t the most vicious part of the poison. Rather, it is able to penetrate most elemental barriers without any warning or sensation. Any Nascent Soul cultivator that didn’t guard against this would meet their end.

This was the reason the old devil labored over nurturing the spirit beast.

Contrary to expectations, the puppet didn’t possess any flesh, thus making the poison ineffective no matter how powerful and allowing the serpent to be killed with ease.

One of Six Paths’ phantoms had a mental connection with the black serpent; Having immediately felt when the serpent died, he betrayed a trace of fear on his face.

Without even turning around, he pointed to the bone banner and then fled with all his might.

The banner trembled before black light brightly glowed as if about to take to the sky.

It was at that moment, an arc of azure lightning flashed above the phantom as Han Li came into view.

With blue light flickering from his eyes, he looked down and waved his hand, creating a net of lightning underneath him. Then, he summoned a small azure cauldron with a flip of his other hand, releasing countless azure threads in a simultaneous barrage.

Although the old devil had a miraculous doppelganger technique displaying hardly any difference in their spiritual sense, Han Li’s Brightsight Spirit Eyes were able to see right through them and instantly recognized minute differences, as well as which was the true Archsaint.

Both of the phantoms loudly yelled with trembling shoulders upon seeing Han Li launched an attack. The attack arrived right before one of the phantoms in an instant.

At this moment, the phantom appeared much dimmer and vague than just a moment before.

The true Archsaint shook his sleeve and summoned a blue jade umbrella over his head.

It quickly expanded several times its original size in an instant, protecting the old devil entirely from above.

Several thuds sounded as the cauldron’s azure threads struck Six Path’s phantom. The threads paused for only a second before piercing cleanly through.

Shortly after, arcs of golden lightning burst struck, immediately wiping away the phantom without any resistance.

Soon after, the lightning and threads fused together with dazzling flashes, and in a blur struck the top of the umbrella.

Following a bright storm of light, the umbrella remained unscathed, neither did it move the slightest from the attack.

When Han Li saw this, his expression sank and he reached his hand out, summoning a golden meter-long sword in his grasp.

Soon after, the wings on his back stirred and dived down, disappearing in a white line.

The old devil was quick to react and attempted to dodge. But before he could act, golden light flashed from the surface of the umbrella. Zap, the center of the umbrella was cleaved through the center.

“Ah!” The old devil shouted. He immediately surrounded himself in black light as he fled.

But just as he took off, the space in front of him warped where a white thread appeared, coiling around the old devil like lightning.

His escape denied, the next thing he felt was a chill on his back. In a flash, a pale of purple flames broke through his barrier of devilish Qi and pierced through him from behind.

The treasure armor that he wore close on his body wasn’t able to block the attack in the slightest.

Apart from sharp pain, the old man could only hear a faint sigh from behind him. Then, he looked down to find a palm of purple flames jutting out from him, soon quickly spreading a layer of purple flames all around him. In the blink of an eye, it covered most of his body and sealed him in ice.

Despite having his face sealed in ice, he twisted it into a grimace and gritted his teeth.

A muffled boom sounded. The bottom half of his body that had yet to be frozen suddenly exploded.

As a cloud of blood and gore sprinkled the air, crimson light flashed. The blood ignited and charged towards Han Li.

At that same moment, a ball of green light shot out from the corpse and flickered over a hundred meters away.

The green light wrapped around a pitch-black Nascent Soul. Its hands were holding tightly onto a green jade bottle.

Han Li shook his sleeve, releasing a torrent of purple flames that promptly extinguished the devilish flames. However, he took no further actions to chase after the old devil.

Han Li’s calm demeanor only caused the old devil’s Nascent Soul to flee in a panic.

After flickering from view several times, the Nascent Soul appeared hundreds of meters away and turned around, stunned to see that Han Li remained completely still. He couldn't help but stop.

At that moment, the air above the Nascent Soul flashed, followed by the silent appearance of a pitch-black knife.

It was only when the knife arrived right above its head did the Nascent Soul discover it.

By that time, it was already too late. A black streak flashed and the Nascent Soul was cleaved into two.

Then with a bright flourish of silver, Han Li leisurely made his way over.

When the human-like puppet disposed of the two-headed snake, Han Li had it remain in position nearby. Then with his command, it intercepted the Nascent Soul’s escape.

Following that, a strange scene followed.

The Nascent Soul hadn’t disappeared after it was cleaved into two. Rather, it turned into clouds of roiling black Qi, separating into six lines that show off in different directions.

The puppet was alarmed and immediately flicked its fingers.

Suddenly, thunder clapped and a dozen fine arcs of lightning were quickly released, striking the black Qi in a flash.

Several muffled claps of thunder followed a chain of golden explosions.

The black Qi was evaporated.

The devil cultivator known to shake the Scattered Star Seas for hundred of years met his end.

The human puppet took a glance at the area of the explosions. After making certain there were no more remnants of the Nascent Soul, it promptly reached out and summoned the small bottle into its grasp.

It didn’t immediately open the bottle, but instead slowly floated towards Han Li.

The old devil was truly out of luck.

The secret technique to turn a Nascent Soul into a ghost was incredibly rare. Against an ordinary cultivator, one of the ghosts formed from the Nascent Soul may have been able to escape, allowing him the opportunity to return again.

But as it so happened, Han Li experienced such a technique once before during his time in the Moulan Plains and was prepared for such a thing to happen. As such, the human-like puppet made use of the Divine Devilbane Lightning from the bamboo arrow to strike down all the ghost fragments.

If there was even a single moment of hesitation, it would’ve been greatly troublesome. After a ghost fragment hid itself, it will be incredibly difficult to find.

When the human-like puppet flew up to Han Li, it tossed the green bottle over to him.

Han Li caught it and examined it for a moment before revealing excitement on his face.

But before he opened the bottle, ghostly cries shrieked from the distance.

Han Li raised his head and looked over to the Unbreakable Cinque Devils.

Without the old devil controlling the bone banner, its power greatly decreased, allowing the cinque devils to regain the advantage. However, the three skulls embedded on the banner belonged to no ordinary cultivators. Although they were no match for the cinque devils, their desperate flaming rage appeared exceptionally brutal.

When Han Li saw this, he frowned and ordered the cinque devils with an incantation gesture.

Suddenly, three of Unbreakable Cinque Devils flew off, returning to their original skeletal form. The two devils that were fighting with the mist flood dragons also withdrew.

Before the flood dragons and the three skulls from the banner could resume their attack, the cinque devils all formed incantation gestures and opened their mouths.

Five differently-colored icy flames rushed out and fused together, creating a torrent of rainbow flames.

The flood dragon of black Qi was the first to meet the flame, and the result was as expected.

Under the rainbow flames, the black flood dragon’s movements slowed. In the blink of an eye, its movements gradually grew increasingly sluggish until it became nearly still.

The cinque devils then let out a long whistle. Countless palm-sized blades of rainbow ice leaped out from the flames, shredding the black flood dragon until it was only black Qi, only for it to be burned away by the flames.

Chapter 1219: Five Elements as One

The three skulls were faring even worse than the flood dragon.

When the skull’s black Qi contacted the rainbow flame, it slowed and was soon wiped away by the flame.

When the skulls saw the flames slowly draw closer, a trace of fear appeared from their eyes and their whimpers grew louder.

The cinque devils sinisterly cackled at this display and soon they stopped spitting icy flames from their mouths, instead suddenly turning to five grey streaks into the sea of flame.

In that next moment, when the rainbow flames nearly arrived at the top of the bone banner where the three skulls resided, five clouds of grey Qi flew out from the flames and took the form of malevolent ghost heads.

They bared their fangs with excitement and sped forward without any abilities.

Crack! The five ghost heads fiercely bit down on the three skulls.

Of course, the three skulls weren’t about to accept their fate. They bit back at the cinque devils.

Suddenly, strange howls and violent screams sounded as the ghost heads and skulls tore at each other with their teeth.

Due to the vast amount of black Qi they earlier released, the three skulls’ vitality was drained. And their position was even worse since they were outnumbered.

In the blink of an eye, the two of the three skulls were torn apart by four of the ghost heads and devoured in large mouthfuls. It took all the strength of the last skull to ward off the fifth ghost head for the time being.

When Han Li saw this, he smiled with satisfaction.

Meanwhile, the small cauldron he held in his hand let out a faint sigh.

“What? Does Fellow Daoist Endless Sky have any suggestions for my rainbow glacial flames?”

“Nonsense! But your rainbow glacial flames remind me of many five elemental type techniques from the Spirit Realm. After these techniques are fully used, they are divided into five colors like your glacial flames. However, your glacial flames are incredibly cold. If an opponent mistook your flames for an elemental technique, they would suffer quite a bit.”

(The Five Elements refer to Wood, Fire, Earth, Metal, and Water)

Azure light flashed and an azure-robed young boy appeared on top of the Heavenvoid Cauldron. He had red lips, white teeth, and a pair of plump white feet. He spoke leisurely as he glanced in the direction of the cinque devils.

“An elemental technique?” Han Li asked with a start.

“That’s right,” the boy smiled with a trace of mockery, “Since I’ve arrived in your mortal realm, I’ve discovered that there are few cultivators that learn multiple elements; most only learn one. Hehe, if any of those people ascended to the Spirit Realm, I fear they will have no hope of ascending to the Spatial Tempering stage.”

“What do you mean?” Han Li quickly asked with a shaken heart.

“It’s nothing much. It’s still too early to speak with you about the Spatial Tempering stage. However, I will mention that a crucial point of ascending to the Spatial Tempering stage is fusion of the five elements into one. If you manage to raise yourself to the Deity Transformation stage, it would be best for you to primarily cultivate as many of the five elements as you can. Peculiar elements such as wind and lightning are too difficult to fuse together. With the cultivation of the five elements as a priority, you’ll have a greater chance of breaking through to Spatial Tempering . Of course, cultivation methods with multiple techniques are far more difficult to cultivate than ordinary techniques. The rate at which magic power gathers will be inferior to single element techniques as well. If you don’t have high hopes for reaching Spatial Tempering , it would be better to only cultivate a single element. With the increased rate at which you gain magic power with a single element, you’ll be able to more easily survive the minor heavenly tribulations that occur every three hundred years!”

Han Li was left stunned by these words. After a long while, he eventually brought himself to say,

“Five elements into one? That will be quite troublesome. My Azure Essence Sword Art is only a wood-attributed technique. As for the wind and lightning attributed techniques, that is understandable. After all, they are variant elements that are formed by combining others. But shouldn’t I cultivate techniques that conform to my body’s spiritual roots? Could it be that heavenly spiritual roots are ordinary in the Spirit Realm? And what is this minor heavenly tribulation that you mentioned? Do humans in the Spirit Realm experience similar tribulation to metamorphosed demon beasts?”

The boy flashed a mysterious smile and chuckled, “I didn’t expect that a few of my words would attract so many questions. In that case, I’ll give you a bit of an explanation.”

“Heavenly spiritual roots are also remarkably rare in our Spirit Realm. Powers and sects of all sizes do their utmost to attract these disciples. After all, those with single elemental spiritual roots would have difficulty entering Spatial Tempering Stage. And Heavenly Spirit Roots may be far more difficult to cultivate, but the Spatial Tempering cultivators they produce are hegemons and sect leaders. When those with Heavenly Spirit Roots breakthrough to Spatial Tempering , a majority of them will be cultivating techniques with two or more attributes. As for the problem with a person's number of spiritual roots, that is easily solved. The humans in the Spirit Realm devised a method to use particular demon beast cores to substitute their lack of spiritual roots. This ‘Core Spiritual Root’ method is somewhat inferior to genuine spiritual roots, there should be no problem in cultivating techniques of other elements. Of course, the core spiritual root method can only be used with preexisting spiritual roots. Mortals cannot use them. In fact, there was a method in the past that used magic tools and treasures as a substitution for spiritual roots. However, this method is incredibly dangerous and slow, so this method is hardly being used. There are cultivators with anywhere from three or four elemental spirit roots that do manage to breakthrough to Spatial Tempering Stage, but they all possess incredible perseverance. They can’t be compared to ordinary cultivators, haha! The so-called minor heavenly tribulation is something that all cultivators above Core Formation stage much experience.”

The boy briefly paused before continuing.

“In the lower realm, Nascent Soul and Deity Transformation cultivators experience a tribulation every three hundred years, thus earning the name ‘minor heavenly tribulation’. At the middle realm, Spatial Tempering , Integration, and Grand Ascension level cultivators experience a grand tribulation every three thousand years. As for cultivators in the very last stage that ascended to the true Immortal realm, they experience Immortal tribulation. Normally, if your cultivation no longer progresses, the following tribulation will be far more powerful than the last. In addition, the increased abundance of spiritual Qi in the spirit realm leads to greater speeds in cultivation, but once one condenses a Nascent Soul, it is a race against time. Each year, many famous cultivators die from tribulation. Fellow Daoist Han shouldn’t think that you will have no problems past Spatial Tempering Stage. Although these cultivator techniques technically have a limitless lifespan provided enough worldly essence, their lives aren’t so peaceful or long. So long as you ascend to the spirit realm, death by heavenly tribulation is only a matter of time.” With that said, the boy’s face grew sullen and his eyes possessed a deep fear.

Han Li wore a grave expression.

The boy didn’t speak much, but his words clearly illustrated that the spirit realm was no paradise. But when Han Li heard that Spatial Tempering Stage cultivators didn’t have a lifespan, Han Li was overjoyed.

Although he already read through a few records mentioning the limitless lifespan of a Spatial Tempering cultivator, he now possessed the full and certain truth.

From his tone, it appeared that a limitless lifespan can only be achieved after he ascended to the spirit realm. Even if he managed to achieve Spatial Tempering in the mortal realm, the worldly essence is lacking, thus limiting his lifespan. At the Deity Transformation stage, one is able to join with worldly essence. Their span won’t be limited by two thousand years once they entered the Spirit Realm. It was no wonder why these Deity Transformation eccentrics were so desperate to find a method to ascend.

As for the tribulations that he mentioned, Han Li was somewhat cautious of them, but he didn’t take them too much to heart.

The matter was a bit too far away from him for his consideration.

After Han Li asked a few more questions related to core spiritual roots and artifact spiritual roots, he eventually grew silent, his eyes twinkling in deep thought.

A short moment later, Han Li fiddled with the dark-green bottle in his hand and flicked off its cap.

Azure light flashed and the bottle rumbled before the cap shot off.

In the next moment, he found that there was absolutely nothing inside of it.

In his surprise, as he thought about what action to take next, a green light abruptly streaked out from the bottle and flew off.

Although Han Li was caught unprepared, he wasn’t about to allow it to escape. With a cold snort, he reached his hand out.

A large azure hand appeared above the green light and slipped down to grab it.

The escaping green light seemed to have already been weakened. Although it was fleeing with utmost speed, the large hand easily grabbed it from the air.

Within the flickering green light, one could see the vague appearance of a female Nascent Soul.

Han Li couldn't help but stroke his chin at the sight.

He stared at the Nascent Soul and slowly asked, “Who is your esteemed self? Why has Six Paths trapped you inside the bottle?”

“Who are you? Where is that devil Six Paths?” Although the Nascent Soul was trapped, it replied boldly.

Facing a mere Nascent Soul, Han Li simply smiled and lazily replied, “If you’re thinking about seeing him, I fear you will be disappointed. I already sent him to the underworld.”

“What? You killed that old devil? How is that possible? Yi! You’re...” The Nascent Soul trembled and spoke with a tone of disbelief.

Translator's Thoughts

Hey everyone, apologies once again for the delay, I was informed on rather short notice yesterday that I had to take over chapters 1233 and 1234, (the next two advance chapters in the sequence), but I already planned to work on a couple of other projects today and yesterday, so I was struggling a little to meet all the deadlines, and I didn't want to a repeat of the situation with the now infamous chapter 1221 LOL In any case, this the first chapter update for the day, I'll try to get the next chapter published within the next two hours. Thanks for your patience, everyone, and happy reading!

Chapter 1220: Breaking the Formation

“You know me?” Han Li said with a tone of bafflement.

Although he knew many female cultivators, he didn’t know any at Nascent Soul-stage apart from Ling Yuling.

After a long pause, the Nascent Soul eventually spoke with an odd tone, “You’re Han Li? When Heavenvoid Hall opened, I saw you once before. It was later said that you acquired the Heavenvoid Cauldron. I didn’t expect that you could’ve escaped the pursuit from those old eccentrics and reach cultivation of this level.”

When he heard her mention Heavenvoid Hall, he recalled where he heard her voice before. A flash of realization sparked in his mind and he doubtfully asked, “You’re... Lady Wen?”

“I didn’t expect that you’d remember me.” She let out a long sigh.

When she confirmed her identity, Han Li wore an astonished expression.

This female Nascent Soul belonged to a woman named Lady Wen, who he originally saw at Heavenvoid Hall. Although her cultivation at the time was significant to begin with, she must’ve acquired quite a few medicines in Heavenvoid Hall and made much progress.

He also remembered what relationship she had with Six Paths.

“If I remember correctly, you should’ve been his Dao Companion!”

Lady Wen resentfully snorted and hesitantly asked, “His Dao Companion? Have you ever seen someone seal their Dao Companion’s Nascent Soul in a magic treasure? But more importantly, you truly killed that wretch Six Paths?”

Han Li smiled and wordlessly extended his finger.

After a brief pause, Lady Wen’s eyes followed where he pointed.

Not far away, there was a block of purple ice that sealed a ruined corpse. It originally belonged to Archsaint Six Paths.

Then, the azure hand holding down Lady Wen wildly flickered before disappearing without a trace.

Lady Wen’s Nascent Soul was now freed.

With her freedom restored, Lady Wen quickly shot forward and flew several circles around the corpse before letting out a frigid laugh to the sky, “It really is that old wretch! As scheming as you are, I didn’t expect that you would die first!”

Han Li frowned. Although he didn’t know what happened for Six Paths and Lady Wen to fall out, he had no interest in hearing about it. Soon after, he began to consider what he should do next.

The Nascent Soul’s laughter eventually came to a stop and she looked over to find Han Li wearing a pensive expression. “There is no need for Fellow Daoist Han to trouble himself. I’ve been kept inside that magic treasure for such a long period of time that I’ve weakened to the point where I can no longer possess a body.

My Nascent Soul will have to immediately dissipate for a chance of reincarnation. I am truly grateful that Fellow Daoist Han managed to eliminate my enemy, but with my current abilities, I have no way to compensate you. I can only hope to repay you in my next life.”

With that said, she abruptly slapped the top of her head.

A blinding red light shined and covered the Nascent Soul entirely. Gradually, the Nascent Soul scattered inch by inch before hl until it was no more.

Han Li was shocked.

He didn’t think that Lady Wen would be so decisive that she would end herself without speaking another word to him. Was what happened so disastrous that she would keep this secret to the grave? But even if she didn’t want to tell him what happened, he could fancy a guess.

Although he was somewhat gloomy over what happened, it was better things ended this way. It would’ve been troublesome to figure out what to do with her.

Han Li shook his head and sighed. He raised his hand and summoned the green bottle back into his grasp before placing it into his storage pouch.

Then, he released an arc of golden lightning from his hand and pulverized the purple ice and the rest of Six Paths’ corpse, turning it into nothing more than shining specks.

As for his storage pouch, Han Li simply took it into his possession.

He quickly swept over its contents and found that most of them didn’t catch his attention at his current level, despite many treasures being amongst them. But there were a few slips detailing Devil Dao techniques that piqued his interest. It is a pity that he didn’t have the time to look at them.

With all that done, Han Li beckoned to his puppet and directly head over to the bone banner. The puppet blurred and strangely disappeared.

When he arrived at the bone banner, the five ghost heads cleanly devoured the skulls and had nearly devoured the entirety of the banner itself.

When Han Li arrived in front of it, he shook his head.

Although the bone banner was somewhat famous, it possessed too much fiendish Qi and wasn’t suitable for him. As such, he made no attempt to stop them.

A short moment later, the cinque devils finally finished destroying the banner and they let out odd screams as if in an expression of joy. The devil Qi they emitted seemed to be more concentrated than before.

When Han Li saw this, his expression remained unchanged. He waited until their laughs finished before commanding them with a single hand.

Although the cinque devils were somewhat unwilling, they didn’t dare to disobey and obediently arrived at Han Li’s side, having experienced the pain from Han Li’s restrictions several times before.

Rather than withdrawing them, he calmly flew back in the direction of Heavenly Star City and had the cinque devils closely follow after him.

The battle between him and the old devil didn’t last very long. Victory was achieved in only the time it took to finish a meal.

If the city fell in that amount of time, Han Li would simply turn around and leave without care for anything else.

It would simply illustrate that the city wasn’t worthy of his help!

Fortunately, this matter didn’t come to pass.

By the time Han Li let the Cinque Devils back to the Heavenly Windfire Formation’s core, the vast battle between the Star Palace and the Starfall Coalition was still being fought with great intensity.

Truthfully, it appeared the Starfall Coalition had somewhat of an upper hand.

This was because the Twin Lan Devils were truly formidable. As the blue devilish Qi and the pink fragrant mist spread forward, it pushed back the Star Palace cultivators. The two original elders of the Starfall Coalition were clearly superior to Old Man Zhao and the large purple-robed man. They could barely hold them back, let alone deal with the Lan Devils.

The lower-grade cultivators, on the other hand, would be immediately shredded to mist upon contact with the blue Qi, or fall as if drunk upon touching the pink mist.

As a result, the Lan Devils wreaked havoc unchecked.

In such turbulent fighting, Han Li’s silent return hadn’t caught anybody’s attention.

Han Li first swept his gaze at the huge windfire pillar and then glanced at the eye-catching display of the Twin Lan Devils. He sneered and wore a fierce expression on his face.

He wordlessly pointed at the Lan Devils. The cinque devils at his side let out a series of low roars and soon charged towards them in five grey streaks.

Then, Han Li slapped a spirit beast pouch at his waist and produced a ball of golden insects above him.

Han Li raised his hand and let out a soft yell. The insect swarm loudly buzzed and with a bang, turned into a dozen smaller clouds before dispersing.

After Han Li was done with that, he waved the wings on his back and disappeared in a gust of wind.

Although the Nascent Soul cultivators of the Starfall Coalition were fighting away from the formation core, there were still several Core Formation stage cultivators standing on guard above it.

This was to prevent the Star Palace from destroying the formation core in a surprise attack.

The guards whispered to each other on top of the pillar and they couldn't help but reveal their delight upon seeing that the Starfall Coalition held the slight advantage in the battle.

One of them turned around to speak to another cultivator, but then they saw something that made his complexion bloodlessly pale.

When the other guards saw this, they turned around in fright and immediately let out frightened shouts.

Thirty meters in the air behind them, there was a youth silently floating there. He had his arms crossed and he wore a mysterious smile.

This youth was the same grand cultivator that left the battle with their alliance leader. How could he be here?

These Core Formation cultivators suddenly felt an icy chill down their backs. Before these cultivators could even think of running or calling out for help, Han Li’s expression suddenly sank and he flicked his hand several times from within his sleeve.

Suddenly, golden sword streaks shot towards them.

The many Core Formation cultivators trembled in fright, each moving to flee away.

But several flashes later, the sword streaks flew past them and the guards fell down, all of their bodies riddled with holes.

There were a few that managed to summon their magic treasures, but they promptly exploded and their owners fell without resistance.

The sword Qi Han Li produced from the Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords were incredibly sharp, rivaling the power of even a top-grade magic treasure. Even Nascent Soul cultivators wouldn’t dare to casually receive them, let alone trifling Core Formation cultivators.

In a single breath, the Core Formation cultivators were extinguished. He retained a calm expression and indifferently looked at the giant pillar before him. Then with a wave of his sleeve, a clear sound rang.

Several small golden swords flew out from his sleeve like a school of fish and swelled to the size of a meter before fusing together.

In flourishing golden radiance, a ten-meter-long golden sword appeared above the pillar.

Translator's Thoughts

Second chapter of the day is finally here! Big thank you to everyone for your patience during this delay, and I hope you enjoy the chapter :)

Chapter 1234: Plotting Against the Yin Sifting Sect

That streak of black light was naturally none other than the Devil Essence Dagger!

Even though this dagger was extremely powerful and had exceptional concealment properties, a great cultivator would always be able to sense it at such close quarters.

As such, Han Li used the Spirit Stun Thorn first, forcing the Yin Sifting Sect Master to reflexively withdraw his spiritual sense back into his body as a result of the excruciating pain. The Devil Essence Dagger was then able to take advantage of this opportunity, flying around to behind its target before easily slicing off his head.

It could be said that victory was decided in an instant. Otherwise, even though Han Li was confident in his ability to bring down his opponent, it would take quite a long time and require a lot of effort.

The Yin Sifting Sect Master was overly confident in the suit of armor that he was wearing, and never would he have thought that Han Li would possess a treasure like the Devil Essence Dagger, which could completely disregard devilish Qi. As a result, his armor proved to be completely ineffective, and he was insta-killed on the spot.

Immediately following the Yin Sifting Sect Master's decapitation, Han Li suddenly spread his Thunderstorm wings and disappeared as an arc of azure lightning.

In the next instant, Han Li appeared in the air above the headless body.

However, right at this moment, the headless body suddenly began to expand drastically before exploding violently, sending a burst of blood mist hurtling toward Han Li.

Han Li was given a massive fright and immediately raised both hands at once.

Two thick arcs of golden lightning immediately shot forth amid a resounding thunderclap, splitting up to form a large golden net before retaliating against the crimson mist.

This crimson mist had to be some kind of sinister secret technique that allowed a cultivator to use its body as a weapon, but the Divine Devilbane Lightning just so happened to be able to completely nullify it. As such, as soon as the two clashed, the oncoming cloud of crimson mist was immediately vanquished amid flashes of golden light.

However, a tiny black humanoid figure had taken advantage of this opportunity to flee into the distance.

This miniature humanoid figure was naturally none other than the Yin Sifting Sect Master's Nascent Soul.

It sped to over 300 feet away in the blink of an eye, then began to unleash a teleportation technique. After two flashes in quick succession, it appeared a further several hundred feet away, thereby taking it to over 1,000 feet away from Han Li, and it appeared that it was going to escape.

Han Li's expression darkened upon seeing this before a cold smile appeared on his face. A loud thunderclap suddenly rang out behind him as two thick bolts of azure and white lightning surfaced on both of his wings at the same time. Immediately thereafter, balls of lightning appeared behind him before revolving around his wings.

He flapped his Thunderstorm Wings, and all of the balls of lightning exploded at once, injecting arcs of azure and white lightning into his wings.

Han Li transformed into an arc of lightning and disappeared amid another resounding thunderclap.

In the next instant, he had appeared 300 feet away before abruptly vanishing once again amid another thunderclap. On the next occasion, the arc of lightning appeared several hundred feet away, and it was close to catching up to the fleeing Nascent Soul.

The Yin Sifting Sect Master turned around just in time to witness Han Li unleashing his extraordinary movement technique, and a surge of panic immediately ran through his heart.

He knew that he couldn't afford to conserve his power any longer as he made a hand seal, and his Nascent Soul disappeared as a streak of crimson light, attempting to flee by using his teleportation technique in quick succession.

At this moment, Han Li appeared around 400 feet behind the Nascent Soul, and he harrumphed coldly upon seeing this.

A thin gash appeared on his glabella, following which black light flashed and an inky-black eyeball surfaced.

This was none other than Han Li's Law Destruction Eye.

As soon as the eye appeared, a flash of black light shot forth from within, disappearing into a certain spot in the air.

Immediately thereafter, a loud explosion erupted as the Nascent Soul stumbled out of empty space amid a flash of black light, looking as if its teleportation technique had been forcibly cut off midway.

The Nascent Soul wore a panicked expression of incredulity, as if it were yet to come to terms with the fact that Han Li had a method to foil its teleportation technique.

It gritted its teeth and disappeared again after making a hand seal.

Han Li's brows furrowed as his expression completley darkened. Another burst of black light was blasted out of his Law Destruction Eye, and he flapped his wings as he disappeared as an arc of azure lightning.

As such, when the Nascent Soul was forced to reveal itself again, Han Li was able to appear just over 100 feet away from it.

The Nascent Soul was shocked to see this, and it immediately raised its hands to send several green threads hurtling toward Han Li.

Han Li also raised a hand to summon several fiery threads, which were sent flying through the air. As soon as the threads clashed, the green threads revealed their true forms to be hair-thin green flying needles.

Meanwhile, the Nascent Soul tried to take advantage of this opportunity to flee again.

However, Han Li was already prepared on this occasion. He swept his sleeve through the air in an expressionless manner as he blasted forth an arc of golden lightning, which then disappeared on the spot.

In the next instant, a loud thunderclap erupted up ahead, and the Yin Sifting Sect Master's Nascent Soul let loose a cry of anguish before clasping its hands over its chest. A tiny golden sword that was several inches in length was protruding from its chest, but it didn't seem to have completely punctured the Nascent Soul's body.

However, the arcs of lightning emanating from the tiny sword were well and truly striking the Nascent Soul.

The cultivation art used by this Yin Sifting Sect Master was clearly also a type of ancient devilish art. After the Nascent Soul was struck by the arc of golden lightning, an expression of agony appeared on its face, and it appeared to be on the brink of falling apart.

Han Li's body swayed and he appeared in the air directly above the Nascent Soul. He then rubbed his hands together to produce another thick bolt of golden lightning amid an astonishing burst of rumbling.

"Please wait, Fellow Daoist; I have something to say!" the Nascent Soul cried out as its face turned deathly pale.

"I have no interest in hearing what you have to say." Han Li harrumphed coldly as he raised a hand, following which the golden arc of lightning transformed into a massive golden python before crashing down from above.

The Yin Sifting Sect Master was absolutely horrified.

However, even though its Nascent Soul had suffered severe wounds, it naturally wasn't going to give up without a fight. As such, spiritual light flashed from its body as it prepared to unleash some kind of secret technique as a final roll of the dice.

However, right at this moment, a clump of azure threads suddenly appeared out of thin air several tens of feet beside it, catching it completely off guard and tightly binding its body.

On the other side of the azure threads, azure light flashed as a tiny cauldron appeared.

It was none other than the Heavenvoid Cauldron!

As soon as the Yin Sifting Sect Master was bound by these azure threads, the magic power within its body congealed, and its heart immediately sank.

The massive golden lightning python was unavoidable, and as the Nascent Soul looked on from down below, its horrified face paled even further.

Just as it closed its eyes to await its inevitable death, a loud explosion suddenly erupted behind it while the Nascent Soul itself remained unscathed.

It opened its eyes with a dumbstruck expression before its heart jolted with surprise.

Han Li had appeared right before it and was inspecting it at close quarters.

"You..."

The Yin Sifting Sect Master's heart stirred, and he was just about to say something when Han Li flicked several fingers through the air in an expressionless manner. Several streaks of silver light shot forth, all of which disappeared into the Nascent Soul's body.

The Yin Sifting Sect Master's Nascent Soul was completely powerless to resist, and before it could say anything else, it had fallen unconscious.

Han Li flipped over his hand to produce several restriction talismans, which he plastered all over the Nascent Soul's body before pointing a finger toward the tiny cauldron.

A crisp ringing sound immediately erupted from within the Heavenvoid Cauldron as those azure threads were withdrawn, pulling the Nascent Soul into the cauldron.

Han Li's expression finally eased after seeing this, and he turned his attention to the five devils and the three corpses.

At this point, the three devils were still completely trapped by the glacial flames being expelled by the five ghostly heads. The five ghostly heads rushed into the sea of five-colored flames at Han Li's behest before hurtling directly toward the three corpses, which were still moving as slowly as snails.

Han Li smiled as he stowed away all of the treasures in the air, regardless of whether they were his or if they belonged to his enemy. He then waved a hand toward the humanoid puppet before carrying the tiny cauldron as he descended toward a secluded mountain down below.

The humanoid puppet followed along behind him completely expressionlessly.

Just as the five devils were dominating their three opponents, Han Li returned, this time without his Heavenvoid Cauldron.

He looked at the three corpses, which had almost been completely devoured by the five devils, and he waited for the conclusion of their "battle" in silence with a contemplative look on his face.

"Have you really decided to infiltrate the Yin Sifting Sect alone?" The voice of a small child sounded.

"It shouldn't be a very dangerous endeavor. After using my soul search technique on that Nascent Soul, I already know where the most powerful restrictions in the sect are situated. As long as I avoid those, nothing can touch me in the Yin Sifting Sect. There seem to only be five or six elders stationed in the sect while all of the others are out fighting enemies from other powers. This is a good opportunity for me to take care of all of the elders in the sect, then make a move against the elders outside of the sect. Even though I can't ascertain the exact location of the elders outside the sect from the information I derived using the soul search technique, I know roughly where they are, and I'll make sure that the remaining Yin Sifting Sect elders won't get a chance to join forces against me," Han Li replied in a calm manner.

"If that's the case, then I have nothing to say. However, are you only trying to take their banners or do you intend to completely destroy the Yin Sifting Sect?" the small child asked.

Han Li paused for a moment before replying with a cold smile, "It doesn't matter what my intentions are! They'll be losing six or seven Nascent Soul Stage elders on top of their late-Nascent Soul Stage sect master. Do you think they'll still be able to maintain their position as one of the 10 great Devil Dao sects? When that time comes, all of their enemies will destroy them in my stead; I won't need to dirty my hands at all."

Chapter 1237: Encountering Xiang Zhili Again

Meanwhile, Han Li was also becoming quite enraged by Eccentric Wind's relentless pursuit.

Ever since he had progressed to the late-Nascent Soul Stage, he hadn't yet unleashed his two Divine Spirit Treasures. On top of that, he had infused Auric Essence into all 72 of his flying swords, and even he didn't know how powerful his Aureate Sword Formation would be. However, he was confident that even a Deity Transformation cultivator wouldn't be able to remain unscathed if they were to be trapped in it.

In any case, he also had those two Immortal Vanquishing Beads as his trump cards.

Thus, after taking all of that into account, Han Li decided that he had the resources to engage his pursuer in battle. As such, when the massive yellow hand came hurtling toward him again, he didn't use his Thunderstorm Wings to evade any longer. Instead, piercing golden light flashed as a sword projection sliced the massive hand in half, instantly vanquishing it on the spot.

Han Li's retaliation came as a surprise to Eccentric Wind, and his eyes narrowed in contemplation.

He was already rather confounded by the fact that Han Li was no longer fleeing the scene, so the attack that he had just unleashed was merely something to test the waters with. Now that Han Li was actively retaliating, he immediately realized that this late-Nascent Soul cultivator seemed to have decided to face him in a direct battle.

Eccentric Wind's expression remained unchanged, but a sense of elation welled up in his heart.

If Han Li were to continue to flee, he'd have to reconsider whether it was worth sacrificing more of his lifespan to continue in his pursuit. However, now that Han Li had decided to face him in battle, he'd have an opportunity to kill him before taking his treasures.

As such, Eccentric Wind exhaled and wasted no further time with words as he laid a hand onto the top of his own head.

Blue light flashed, and a hexagonal jade plate appeared. It appeared to be an antiquated treasure with mysterious runes of different colors shimmering over its surface.

As soon as this treasure appeared, a sinister smile appeared on Eccentric Wind's face.

In order to end this battle as quickly as possible, he was naturally going to crush his opponent in one fell swoop, thereby minimizing the amount of lifespan he'd have to sacrifice. During his previous brief scuffles with Han Li, he knew that Han Li had some powerful abilities and treasures. As such, he didn't dare to underestimate Han Li, and immediately summoned his most powerful treasure.

The jade plate began to rotate in mid-air before rapidly expanding amid a loud ringing sound. In the blink of an eye, it had transformed into a massive plate that was several tens of feet in size before tipping over to face Han Li.

Piercing blue light flashed from the plate, and it appeared that something was about to reveal itself.

Han Li's heart stirred upon seeing this, and he immediately swept both sleeves through the air. Several tens of small golden swords shot forth from within, instantly transforming into 72 golden flying swords, all of which were around a foot in length.

He then made a hand seal, and the 72 flying swords swayed before manifesting hundreds of identical swords. These swords danced through the air before transforming into a vast expanse of golden light, creating a rather formidable sight to behold.

Eccentric Wind faltered slightly at the sight of the vast number of flying swords that Han Li had summoned, but a cold smile then appeared on his face as he said, "No matter how many flying swords you have, it'll be nowhere near the number of my flying sabers. Let me show you the might of my Myriad Blade Plate!"

Han Li's eyes flashed as he turned his gaze toward the hexagonal jade plate.

The runes on the plate flashed and a blue pillar of light shot forth, then dispersed into several streaks of blue light. Those streaks of blue light then flashed before instantly transforming into shimmering blue flying sabers, each of which was several inches in length. Blue pillars of light were still erupting incessantly from the jade plate, creating countless flying sabers that hovered above Eccentric Wind's head like a mountain of blades.

It was quite an intimidating sight for anyone to behold!

Han Li's expression changed drastically upon seeing this.

There had to be more than 4,000 flying sabers lined up in the air before him.

Right at this moment, Eccentric Wind swept a sleeve toward Han Li, and all of the blue sabers began to emanate brilliant spiritual light.

They then shot forth toward Han Li as streaks of blue light, and due to the sheer number of blades, the entire sky was obscured by blue light, making it appear as if there were a vast lethal wall of blue blades rushing toward Han Li.

Han Li's golden flying swords created an impressive spectacle, but it was nothing compared to the oncoming mountain of blades.

Han Li took a deep breath as his expression returned to normal. At the same time, he let loose a loud cry, yet instead of unleashing his flying swords to clash with the oncoming sabers, he raised a hand instead, A ball of green light slipped out of his palm, within which a green wooden ruler could be seen.

It was none other than the Eight Spirit Ruler!

As soon as the ruler left his hand, it began to dance through the air of its own accord. The projection of a silver lotus flower appeared on the ruler, and following an injection of magic power from Han Li, it expanded further and further, and the silver light emanating from it also became more and more scintillating.

Moments later, the silver lotus flower had reached over 100 feet in size, completing shielding Han Li behind it.

"That's the Eight Spirit Ruler! You're that Han brat that appeared on the Kunwu Mountains!" Eccentric Wind immediately exclaimed as he identified the spirit treasure.

At the same time, the mountain of blue blades faltered in mid-air, and didn't immediately come crashing down toward the massive lotus flower.

"You recognize me?" Han Li asked with furrowed brows.

"I don't, but Fellow Daoist Xiang once mentioned you to me. I heard that you're very familiar with Devilish Concubine Ling Long of the Spirit Realm?" Eccentric Wind's eyes flashed with a contemplative light as he spoke.

"I wouldn't say that, but I am indeed acquainted with her. When you say Fellow Daoist Xiang, are you referring to Xiang Zhili?" A peculiar look had also appeared on Han Li's face.

"Hmph, who else could I be referring to? Setting that aside for now, let me ask you this; before Devilish Concubine Ling Long returned to the Spirit Realm, did she mention anything about the spatial node to you or leave you any shortcuts to the Spirit Realm?" Eccentric Wind asked with his gaze focused intently on Han Li.

"Why are you asking that? Didn't Fellow Daoist Ling Long already offer guidance in this area to Master Xiong of the Myriad Demon Valley? Seeing as you're familiar with Brother Xiang, there's no way you wouldn't be aware of this." Han Li's heart jolted with surprise, but his expression remained calm and collected.

Eccentric Wind didn't believe Han Li in the slightest as he said in a cold voice, "There's no need for you to try and play dumb. I did a lot of research on what happened at the time, and that Devilish Concubine Ling Long was clearly very close with you. There's no way that she wouldn't have left you with a shortcut to the Spirit Realm. Hand over what she gave you, and I can let bygones be bygones."

"Hmph! Setting aside whether I actually do have what you're looking for, do you really think a mere Myriad Blade Plate can bring me down?" Han Li retorted in a bullish manner.

He wasn't a three-year-old kid; he wouldn't be that easy to fool. If he were to admit to this, then even he could survive this ordeal, the other Deity Transformation cultivators of the human world would definitely try to track him down, and he'd be in a world of trouble then.

A vicious light appeared in Eccentric Wind's eyes upon hearing this. He immediately made a hand seal, seemingly as if he were going to activate the mountain of blue blades again.

Han Li's heart tightened as he also injected more power into the massive lotus flower around him.

A fierce battle appeared to be imminent. However, right at this moment, a gentle voice suddenly sounded in the ears of Eccentric Wind and Han Li at the same time.

"Brother Feng, Fellow Daoist Han, please wait."

Han Li faltered slightly upon hearing this familiar voice, following which a peculiar look appeared on his face.

Eccentric Wind also stopped what he was doing as a hint of surprise surfaced in his eyes. He then suddenly turned toward a certain direction and harrumphed coldly. "Hmph, you sure got here just in the nick of time, Old Bastard Xiang."

"Hehe, I just so happen to be in a nearby state, and I found my way here after receiving your message, but I didn't think that the person you're hunting down is Fellow Daoist Han. I must say, I'm not sure who I should side with in this situation." the owner of the voice chuckled.

A flash of yellow light then appeared in the distant sky, following which a streak of yellow shot forth toward them like lightning, reaching them in just a few flashes.

The light receded to reveal an elderly man with a set of wizened features. His eyes were quite small, and he wore a faint smile on his face. This man was none other than Xiang Zhili, whom Han Li had met on several occasions in the past.

"Senior Martial Brother Xiang!" Han Li immediately cupped his fist in salute.

"I was at the Yellow Maple Valley of the Heavenly South Region for several years, so it's indeed not incorrect for you to be referring to me as Senior Martial Brother. However, you sure are full of surprises, Junior Martial Brother Han! I didn't think that mere Qi Condensation cultivator from back then would've cultivated to such staggering heights. It looks like even I can be susceptible to misjudging character from time to time. I wanted to have a good chat with you when we last met at the Kunwu Mountains, but the unexpected troubles that befell us at the time prevented me from being able to do so," Xiang Zhili said to Han Li with a benevolent expression.

"I also didn't think that I would meet you again, Senior Martial Brother Xiang," Han Li replied with a wry smile.

"Fellow Daoist Feng, can you do me a favor and spare Junior Martial Brother Han? After all, he merely killed a descendant of one of your juniors; it's not worth engaging Junior Martial Brother Han in a battle to the death over such a trifling matter. Your Myriad Blade Plate is indeed a spirit treasure replica, but it's still no match for a true Divine Spirit Treasure," Xiang Zhili mediated with a smile.

"Hmph! He's just a Nascent Soul cultivator. Even with a Divine Spirit Treasure in his possession, he wouldn't be capable of unleashing its full power; how is he going to be a match for me?" Eccentric Wind chuckled coldly in a disdainful manner.

"Indeed, with just a single spirit treasure, Junior Martial Brother Han would naturally be no match for Brother Feng, but what if he possesses two Divine Spirit Treasures and several spirit treasure replicas?" Xiang Zhili asked.

Eccentric Wind's expression finally changed upon hearing this.

Chapter 1250: Capturing the Flame Essence

The pegasus had been chasing the Fire Raven for so long, so it was naturally unwilling to give up. As such, it hurriedly spread its wings and also flew upward toward the surface.

Both of them were fire spirits, so they were naturally unobstructed by the thick layers of earth that stood in their way.

Moments later, the two fire spirits emerged from the ground one after another, appearing right within the massive cage of light.

As soon as the Puresun Flame Essence appeared, it sensed that something was amiss. However, it was already too late. The humanoid puppet was already prepared in advance, and it abruptly stomped down onto the Celestial Blue Cauldron beneath its feet. A burst of blue flames immediately shot forth from within, transforming into a blue glacial wyrm in the blink of an eye.

The Greatyin Fire Raven also launched a counterattack, turning around before opening its beak to expel the Snow Crystal Pearl.

At the same time, the entire formation was activated by the humanoid puppet.

The Puresun Flame Essence immediately attempted to flee back into the lava upon seeing this. The volcanic crater where it and the Greatyin Fire Raven were was the only area that had been left intentionally free of blue ice. However, as the formation was activated, blue ice was also beginning to seal up that crater.

However, the rate at which the ice as spreading over the crater was far inferior to the speed of the Puresun Flame Essence's retreat.

Just as the miniature pegasus was about to disappear into the ground, a horrified look suddenly appeared in its eyes, and it abruptly spread its wings, vanishing before appearing again over 200 feet away.

Almost at the exact same moment, five pillars of light of different colors shot forth into the air from the ground below.

Five bursts of greyish-white devilish Qi then emerged, transforming into five ghostly heads, each of which was around a foot in size. They were none other than the Unbroken Cinque Devils!

Han Li was also slowly rising up from the ground.

At this point, the entire crater had been covered in a thick layer of blue ice due to the effect of the formation.

Han Li stood upon the blue ice and raised his head with a serious look on his face.

The glacial wyrm manifested from Celestial Blue Flames, the Greatyin Fire Raven, and the five ghostly heads were all converging toward the pegasus.

However, just as Master Arctic Dragon's memories had revealed, the Puresun Flame Essence was extremely nimble and agile, flashing through the air as a completely untraceable streak of silver light.

The Greatyin Fire Raven was the only one that could match its speed, while the five devils and the glacial wyrm were clearly unable to keep up.

However, on this occasion, the pegasus was the one being debilitated by the glacial Qi emanating from the cage of Celestial Blue Flames, and with the enhancement of Han Li's Snow Crystal Pearl, the Greatyin Fire Raven was now slightly faster than the Puresun Flame Essence.

If it weren't for the fact that the pegasus' movement techniques were truly extremely agile and unpredictable, it would've been captured by the Fire Raven long ago.

Even so, the pegasus was still struck on several occasions in a short period of time by the crimson light being blasted out of the Fire Raven's mouth, thereby inflicting a few minor injuries upon it. However, the pegasus would rather allow itself to be struck by attacks rather than retaliate, as doing so would force it to slow down, thereby giving the five devils and the glacial wyrm a chance to chase it down.

Han Li stood down below with his hands clasped behind his back, seeming content just to spectate. Meanwhile, the humanoid puppet was maintaining the function of the formation while expressionlessly manipulating the glacial wyrm.

All of a sudden, the pegasus identified an opportunity and came hurtling down toward the ground after allowing itself to be struck by another one of the Greatyin Fire Raven's attacks. It reached the ground down below in a flash without any warning , then attempted to unleash a movement technique to flee the scene.

However, the pegasus' body faltered as soon as it came into contact with the blue ice down below.

During this split second of delay, a streak of crimson light and a burst of blue glacial mist suddenly hurtled toward it. At the same time, a strange unsettling cry rang out.

A flash of horror appeared in the pegasus' eyes, but it was clearly too late to evade. However, it managed to react extremely quickly, flapping its wings desperately to create a series of silver flowers. These flowers instantly enshrouded its entire body, and it appeared that it was planning to take these attacks head-on.

Two muffled thumps rang out, and the crimson light and blue glacial mist struck the silver flowers in quick succession.

Much to Han Li's surprise, the pegasus borrowed the power from the impact of the attacks, flying rapidly through the air to appear over 100 feet away in the blink of an eye. It stumbled slightly to arrest its momentum before escaping toward another direction in the cage as a streak of silver light.

Even though the pegasus was still traveling extremely quickly, Han Li was able to identify using his Brightsight Spirit Eyes that it was clearly missing a chunk of one of its wings, and a section of one of its legs also appeared to be have been dismembered.

A smile appeared on Han Li's face and he finally sprang into action.

Azure and white light flashed behind him, upon which a pair of wings appeared on his back. He gently flapped those wings and a light breeze was swept up, following which he completely vanished.

The Greatyin Fire Raven was also throwing itself at the Puresun Flame Essence again.

However, the pegasus had already opened up some distance between them by borrowing the momentum of the attacks from earlier, and it unleashed its maximal speed as it reached the border of the cage after a few successive flashes of silver light.

A pillar of blue light stood in its way, so the pegasus decided to fly around it.

However, the humanoid puppet up above immediately made a hand seal upon seeing this, and brilliant light erupted from all of the pillars as strands of light shot forth, creating a dense net that cut off the pegasus' route of escape.

The pegasus was startled by this development, but it was too late to turn back. As such, it blasted several tens of silver flowers toward the net while continuing to fly full speed ahead.

It was planning to puncture the net through brute force.

However, what the pegasus had failed to notice was that two clouds of white mist had already appeared above its head. The white mist suddenly surged as two gusts of white glacial winds swept forth. Immediately thereafter, two snowy white centipedes shot forth like lightning.

These were none other than two of the Six-Winged Frost Centipedes Han Li had set up in advance.

As such, the pegasus could only evade the two gusts of glacial winds and fly toward another direction. At this moment, the Fire Raven, five devils, and glacial wyrm converged toward it once again.

However, as soon as the pegasus had changed directions, black light suddenly appeared before its eyes, and a glittering and translucent black blade instantly flashed through its body.

An expression of shock and horror appeared in its eyes as its body was sliced cleanly in half.

The two halves of its body reverted back to their silver flame form before instantly merging back together to form a miniature pegasus again.

However, its body was quite blurry and insubstantial, clearly indicating that it was unable to immediately take on its original form again.

It was quite apparent that the surprise attack from the Devil Essence Dagger had proven to be very effective. Right at this moment, a dull thunderclap suddenly rang out overhead. An azure arc of lightning flashed, following which Han Li abruptly appeared and immediately flicked his 10 fingers in quick succession.

10 fiery threads hurtled through the air, puncturing the pegasus' body in a flash.

At the same time, Han Li began to chant something, and the fiery threads instantly bound the pegasus tightly.

It was completely powerless to resist against Han Li's surprise attacks.

Han Li was naturally ecstatic upon seeing this.

He flipped his hand over to summon a stack of restriction talismans that he had prepared well in advance, and a dozen or so streaks of light of different colors flew toward the Puresun Flame Essence as he flung the talismans through the air.

If these restriction talismans could plaster themselves to the pegasus' body, it would definitely be unable to escape, despite the fact that it possessed the body of a fire spirit.

However, a surprising turn of events unfolded!

The tightly-bound pegasus suddenly let loose a desperate neigh as brilliant silver light erupted all over its body. The fiery threads detached themselves from its body, flashing toward the oncoming restriction talismans instead.

Loud explosions erupted as all of the talismans were reduced to dust, while the fiery threads continued to hurtle toward Han Li.

Even the perpetually calm and collected Han Li was quite startled by this development. However, he immediately decided on a course of action, raising an arm before waving his hand toward the fiery threads.

The threads immediately stiffened before disappearing into his hand in a slightly reluctant manner.

Meanwhile, the pegasus was taking advantage of the situation to try and escape again.

Han Li's expression darkened as he harrumphed coldly.

Upon hearing his harrumph, the pegasus suddenly shuddered as its body plummeted involuntarily toward the ground.

Han Li had unleashed his Spirit Stun Thorn secret technique!

Han Li flapped his wings and abruptly vanished, appearing directly below the falling pegasus in the next instant. On this occasion, he merely made a grabbing motion toward the pegasus rather than rely on any treasures. A large hand constructed from purple flames appeared out of thin air, forcibly locking the miniature pegasus in a tight grasp.

Brilliant purple glacial light erupted as a massive block of purple ice sealed the fire spirit's body within.

At this moment, the Greatyin Fire Raven and the glacial wyrm also finally arrived. Both of them plunged into the purple ice without any hesitation, quickly fusing as one with the block of ice amid flashes of spiritual light.

Almost at the exact same moment, the pegasus within the block of ice seemed to have recovered from the effect of the Spirit Stun Thorn, and silver flames immediately erupted violently all over its body as it attempted to escape.

However, with the infusion of the Greatyin True Flame into the block of ice, there was no way that it would be able to escape in a short period of time. The blue glacial wyrm and the Greatyin Fire Raven were like fish in water as they surrounded the pegasus, blasting out gusts of glacial Qi from their mouths to forcibly repress its silver flames.

The five devils also arrived at this moment.

Each of them blasted a type of glacial flame out of their mouths, which then converged to form a five-colored glacial flame that hurtled toward the miniature pegasus. Upon coming into contact with this five-colored glacial flame, the miniature pegasus immediately became extremely slow and sluggish. On the contrary, the glacial wyrm and Greatyin Fire Raven were seemingly completely unaffected even though the five-colored glacial flames had also washed over them. Instead, the glacial Qi billowing out of their mouths had become even more powerful.

The Puresun Flame Essence was unable to withstand such a ferocious assault, and it gradually began to slow down even further as its aura became more and more feeble.

Han Li immediately swept his sleeve through the air upon seeing this, summoning a dozen or so talismans. These talismans immediately punctured the block of ice before plastering themselves to the pegasus' body.

The fire spirit finally relinquished its resistance with a look of despair on its face. The silver light emanating from its body dimmed, and it was unable to maintain its pegasus form any longer as it reverted back to a ball of shimmering silver flames.

Chapter 1252: Profound Heavenly Tree

When Han Li acquired this information from his puppet, his mind underwent a massive shock.

Before he secluded himself, he did pour a few drops of the Returning Sun Water on the Profound Goddess’ Palm out of curiosity, but it remained as dead as ever. But with the news of its revival, he could hardly believe it.

Han Li promptly made his way into the medicine garden.

The Profound Goddess’ Palm was placed next to several other precious spirit medicines such as the Ninecurl Ginseng.

When he arrived, he clearly saw the current condition of the Profound Goddess’ Palm. Despite what mental preparations he made, he was fully shocked.

Originally, the green liquid from the small mysterious bottle only changed its color green slightly but it remained completely dry. But now, its palms spread throughout the ground and climbed up on many white jade stone pillars. It was lush, green, and filled with life. The vine emitted a faint scent that exceeded the qualities of the medicines in the garden. Even the Ninecurl Spirit Ginseng’s white rabbit incarnation felt at ease sleeping on one of the vine roots.

When Han Li arrived near it, the white rabbit’s ears moved and its fire-red eyes opened a sliver and resumed its nap after seeing it was Han Li.

After several hundred years of contact with Han Li, the Ninecurl Ginseng’s incarnation had begun to treat Han Li’s garden as its own. Under his protection, the rabbit hadn’t encountered the slightest danger and no longer felt any danger towards him.

Han Li remained silent and didn’t bother it. Rather, he began to examine the vine.

Apart from emitting an astonishing spiritual Qi, the revived Profound Goddess’ Palm appeared no different from ordinary vines. But under careful examination, one could find a few peculiar differences.

The vine’s color was emerald green, but its surface seemed to give off a metallic sheen. Additionally, the veins of the vine’s leaves were bizarre. Each one was distinct but were somewhat familiar.

Han Li silently gazed at the leaves and his heart stirred as something came to mind.

The vein patterns had a faint resemblance to the silver runes on the golden jade tome.

He frowned and examined a dozen more leaves before eventually discovering something wondrous.

The leave patterns were written in half of the silver rune scripts as if they were written only to half completion.

Han Li was amazed for a long while. Eventually, he brought himself to touch the leaves with his fingers.

They were sleek and smooth as if he touched fine jade.

He stroked his chin and began to wear a pensive expression.

At that moment, he thought to call out to the Soaring Sky Beast and ask it a few questions related to the profound spirit trees, but he finally decided not to.

As of current, the child was most likely cultivating inside the Heavenvoid Cauldron. He was completely ignorant of what was happening.

Even since he returned to his cave residence, he wanted to make use of the cauldron’s power and completely severed the demon’s connection to the outside.

So long as he remained in secluded cultivation, he wouldn’t release the demon beast to prevent any of his secrets from being made known.

As such, the Soaring Sky Beast didn't have any knowledge of the small mysterious bottle.

As for any rumors or legends regarding the Profound Goddess’ Palm, Han Li had already researched them.

According to a few creation myths, when life sprung from primal chaos, the profound heavens came, being lifted with the appearance of spirit trees. Regardless of the spirit tree, it would spring flowers and grow fruit that granted inconceivable abilities that ignored the laws of the world. They were true heaven-defying treasures.

However, these were only rumors during ancient times. He had never seen it for himself.

However, for this to be mentioned several times in ancient records could be considered to be substantial. Furthermore, they had unique growth cycles that spanned a hundred thousand years, but their flowers would bloom and bear fruits that lasted only a few days or even a few hours.

Under such a time, their ripeness would deteriorate quickly, meaning that it would only be wishful thinking for anyone to harvest them.

Only the flowers and fruits of profound heavenly trees are the only ones that possess heaven-breaking abilities that can ignore the laws of the world. As for vines and wood, they could only be materials for tool refinement. They were nowhere near as valuable.

Although Han Li didn’t have the child know of the small portion of the Profound Goddess’ Palm root in his possession, he didn’t plan on having him know of its revival with the Returning Sun Water Either.

Even if the Profound Goddess’ Palm found its way into someone else’s possession, it would be of little value as they couldn't acquire its flowers or fruit. But it would tempt others nevertheless and cause huge problems. And with his small mysterious bottle, if he could use it to mature the vine, he should be able to acquire its fruits and flowers after two or three hundred years. He wasn’t about to give up on such a grand opportunity.

If he allowed the child to know of this matter, who knows if he could get that information to his main body in the spirit realm. That was just asking for trouble.

In any case though, the Soaring Sky Beast should know far more about the tree than he did. But with further thought, he gave up on the idea.

Having come to his decision, he let out a long sigh and placed down several profound restrictions around the plant, causing the medicine garden to resume its original appearance.

Three days later, Han Li left the puppet at the cave residence as he called out to Lu Luo and his other sect elders, informing them of his departure.

He later appeared above a nameless mountain in the Scattered Star Seas and disappeared past the horizon in an azure streak.

One night several months later, in the Star Palace temple at the top of Heavenly Star City, a beautiful woman in white palace robes was sitting down on a mat in a hidden room. Her eyes were closed, her hands were in an incantation gesture and white light roamed across her body as if she were cultivating something.

As the spiritual light flickered continuously a trace of pain appeared on the woman’s face.

The white light pulsed in brightness and just as it appeared to lose control, the woman ceased her incantation gesture and halted her cultivation.

Following that, the white light from her body eventually dissipated.

She let out a sigh and opened her eyes, unconsciously looked around her.

The woman was immediately frightened and shock appeared on her face.

Sitting at the corner of the room was a person with their arms behind his back. He was looking at her with a mysterious smile.

“Brother Han, so it is you.” The woman relaxed after clearly seeing his face and sweetly smiled. But through the depth of her beauty was a faint trace of fear.

This was an important area for the Star Palace. There were over thirty layers of restrictions present but he was able to sneak in without alerting her.

“Fellow Daoist Ling, in the years we haven’t seen each other, your grace remains strong. However, your cultivation technique seems unsuitable.” Han Li spoke with a slight smile.

“As you’ve said, there must be a problem with my cultivation. I’ve been meaning to seek some guidance from an expert. Now that you’re here, I’ll have to make a request.”

Han Li chuckled, “Oh? Guidance will be out of the question, but I’ll give you my thoughts after you speak. But before that, I want to retrieve the Essensefuse Mountain.”

Ling Yuling was stunned and hesitantly asked, “Of course, it was something you left in our care after all. However, how do you intend on moving it?”

“I have a way, but I don’t know if it will truly work. I can only give it a try.” Han Li slowly replied.

With surprise briefly appearing on her face, she answered, “In that case, I’ll guide you there.”

“Thank you for your trouble, Fellow Daoist Ling!” Han Li nodded with satisfaction.

Two hours later, the two arrived in a passage underneath the mountain, arriving in front of a large jade door.

Ling Yuling released the seal on the door with the command medallion in her hand and it slowly opened.

Han Li let out a sigh and slowly walked in.

Ling Yuling followed after some hesitation.

The past scene appeared once more.

As they walked past the gate, the elemental power immediately immersed them and violently stirred the spiritual power in their bodies to rush out.

However, Han Li was now at the peak of late-Nascent Soul stage with far denser and purer magic power than before. He wasn’t about to allow his spiritual power to be absorbed.

He immediately circulated his cultivation art and suppressed the oddities occurring in his body. Then with his hands held in an incantation gesture, he slowly focused on the center of his chest.

A crackle sounded. An egg-sized ball of light appeared, glowing with five-colored light that roamed across its surface.

Suddenly, nearby elemental light coiling around Han Li immediately dimmed by a third.

Standing behind him, Ling Yuling could sense the changes of elemental power and smiled, “Congratulations Brother Han, you’ve completed the first layer of the Divine Essensefuse Light.”

“If I hadn’t refined the light to this point, I wouldn’t have been able to shift the mountain,” Han Li casually replied with a chuckle.

Ling Yuling couldn't help but urge, “Although you only cultivated the first layer of the Divine Essensefused Light, you can move the mountain. But I fear it won’t be an easy matter to take it. If Brother Han’s method isn’t effective, wouldn’t it be better to join our palace? You have my guarantee that no one will disturb your cultivation and that you will have priority over our resources.”

Han Li glanced at Ling Yuling and indifferently said, “Fellow Daoist Ling doesn’t need to mention it again. If I intended on entering the palace, I would’ve already done so. As for whether my method will work, I’ll have to give it a try first.”

Chapter 1253: Island Ambush

Han Li tossed the ball of spiritual light in his hand which is suspended itself in midair.

He reached to his waist with his other hand, summoning a small flag that was several inches long.

The flag was entirely crimson and released bursts of scarlet light that contained ghostly wails.

Ling Yuling glanced at the item in surprise and shot an odd glance at Han Li.

However, Han Li had no intention of explaining anything. He simply muttered to himself and tossed the flag above him.

Light flashed and a small flag massively surged in size, turning three meters tall in the blink of an eye. The surface of the flag glistened crimson as if it were coated with blood.

When he pointed at the huge flag, it spread open, emitting a mist until it was only a crimson cloud, and rushed to the top of Essencefused Mountain.

The cloud roiled as it stopped over its destination and began to slowly expand, covering most of the top and filling the air with a stench as if blood were mixed into the air.

Ling Yuling swept her spiritual sense through the cloud and sensed an unfathomable amount of Yin souls. In a start, she hastily withdrew her spiritual sense, a sense of dread lingering in her mind.

At that moment, Han Li took large steps towards the Essensefused Mountain and waved his hand into the air.

A ball of light flashed and shot towards the small mountain, vanishing from sight.

Han Li waved his hand again, this time reaching his hand out and grabbing at the air.

The small mountain flickered with rainbow light and swayed several times. Its rumbling shook the air, and it eventually lifted off from the ground, slowly floating up to the blood cloud.

Lin Yuling looked on in astonishment. The mountain entered the cloud and vanished.

Han Li then released a spell seal from his hand.

The blood cloud roiled before it eventually shrunk and returned to its form as a crimson banner several inches large. It fell back into Han Li’s hand only a moment later.

The mountain was now as empty as could be as if the Essensefused Mountain was never there.

“A spatial treasure!”

Ling Yuling eventually regained her bearings, shock still clear on her face.

“The treasure does have some spatial abilities, and it seems I’ve given you quite a show!” Han Li smiled in satisfaction, having swept his spiritual sense through the Crimson Soul Banner.

Ling Yuling gasped in surprise and let “It has spatial abilities and can even take in the Essensefused Mountain. I fear only a few exist in the mortal world. How fortunate that Fellow Daoist Han was able to acquire one.”

Back when the Star Palace Sages left behind the method to control Han Li, they believed that cultivating the Divine Essensefused Light would’ve kept him tied to the Star Palace. But now, Han Li rendered her completely powerless with this ingenious move.

The woman inwardly sighed, finally giving up on having Han Li joined the Star Palace.

Crimson light flashed from his hand and the small flag disappeared. Following that, Han Li pondered to himself for a moment and smiled at her, “I can stay at the palace for a short amount of time, exchange a few cultivation insights with you, and take a look at what is causing you problems with your cultivation. But during this time, I still have something I need your help with.”

Although Ling Yuling blanked for a second, she immediately replied with a smile, “Brother Han has already treated out palace with much kindness. It is only natural for us to help you as best we can. There is no need to be so polite.”

“It is a small matter. I want to know the most recent whereabouts of the golden wyrm in the outer seas. The more accurate its position, the better.” Han Li calmly spoke as if it were a trivial matter, but Ling Yuling was astonished upon hearing him. Her eyes grew wide.

With a hesitant tone, she muttered, “Brother Han wishes to know the whereabouts of that old demon? Could it be you...”

Han Li shot a glance at the girl and raised his eyebrow, “Of course I have reasons for finding the Golden Wyrm King. You don’t need to think too much as to why. I will not involve your palace. Or do you mean to say the matter is too difficult?”

Ling Yuling shook her head and replied with a solemn expression, “Brother Han has shown much kindness to the palace. Even with a more difficult request, I still wouldn’t decline it. However, these past few years the palace has completely withdrawn our men from the outer seas. And as the golden wyrm is a grade ten demon cultivation, I fear it will take more than just a few days to find its whereabouts.”

“Time is no matter. I don’t mind waiting for several years for this information,” Han Li casually replied.

Ling Yuling wiped away her hesitation and stated, “In that case, we will immediately make arrangements. Fellow Daoist, you can stay as long as you wish.”

Han Li nodded, satisfied to hear of her agreement.

The two then chatted a while longer and departed from the cave.

...

Two years later, a man and a woman floated above an unnamed island in the Outer Star Seas. the man had a common appearance but also bright and intelligent eyes. The woman had a delicate and dainty appearance.

The two appeared both quite young, but the woman appeared to treat the man with the utmost respect. The young man appeared completely indifferent.

“From what you said, the Golden Wyrm King should arrive at this island! Could it have changed its mind and decided to go elsewhere?”

The man’s voice wasn’t loud, but the woman replied with the utmost respect, “Elder Han, please be at ease. I’ve already made several inquiries. It is information acquired from the soul search of a high-grade demon cultivator. At the depths of this island should be an extremely rare spirit fruit. Although it isn’t very useful to humans, it is beloved by the wyrm clan. The Golden Wyrm King comes here every ten years when the spirit fruit is ripe and eats it below the island no matter what obstruction. If the location of the fruit didn’t change or if it died, the wyrm clan would’ve moved elsewhere. It should be the period where the spirit fruit is ripe. The Golden Wyrm King should definitely come under normal circumstances.”

“Hm, then I will wait a few more days.” The man said with a sullen voice.

Of course, the man was Han Li, and the woman was a disciple Ling Yuling sent to guide him.

After two years of searching with the complete might of the Star Palace, they finally found the whereabouts of the Golden Wyrm King. Han Li remained at the palace during this time, until this woman led him outside the city to a secret teleportation formation, quietly bringing him to the outer seas where he waited on the island for several months.

Until now, he had yet to see any trace of the Golden Wyrm King, leading to Han Li to ask the woman again out of impatience.

And with the woman giving a confident reply, Han Li’s expression relaxed.

Just when Han Li sighed and thought to ask her for more details, his expression suddenly changed and he turned his head to look at the distant sea.

“Good, it finally arrived. From its aura, there is no doubt it is the Golden Wyrm King.” Delight briefly appeared on Han Li’s face. Then he turned to the girl and commanded, “You should leave now and take yourself out of danger.”

When the disciples heard him, she felt her heart tremble and gave him a quick curtsey before flying away in a white streak.

When Han Li saw the woman leave, he shook his sleeve, summoning forth a small black bottle.

A white demonic wind blew past, followed by the gradual appearance of five skeletons.

“Go.”

With Han Li’s mental command, the five skeletons immediately scattered, riding away on demonic winds and vanishing in an instant.

Soon after, a spirit beast pouch flew out, and a dozen four-winged centipedes buzzed out. Han Li then commanded them to burrow themselves into the sea underneath the island.

Han Li took another look at the distant sea and sneered, before suddenly fading from sight.

Despite the many techniques he released, this all happened in an instant.

In the blink of an eye, the island was completely barren as if no one had ever been there.

In the time it took to finish a meal, light flashed from the horizon. A golden and an azure streak tore through the air, quickly making their way past the vast ocean. Their light faded to reveal two silhouettes.

One of them had a tall and sturdy body, wore a golden embroidered gown, and a green beard. The other had a thinner body, a silver hat, and azure robes.

As soon as the two appeared, the large man with golden robes wore a hesitant expression over his dignified face. He quickly looked around him but discovered nothing odd.

When the azure-robed cultivators saw this, he wore an odd expression and asked, “What? Did Fellow Daoist Jin discover something amiss?”

The gold-robed man frowned and doubtfully said, “When we were farther, it appeared there was someone that swept past us with their spiritual sense. However, that spiritual sense was somewhat weak so it could’ve been a trick of the mind.”

The azure-robed man laughed, “If that was truly the case, wouldn’t that mean their spiritual sense is far more powerful than Brother Jin’s? How can that be possible?”

“Brother Feng thinks too highly of me. Although I am known as the Golden Wyrm King, that is only in the nearby seas that shake from my might. Outside, I’m nothing much.” The golden-robed man shook his head and quickly swept his spiritual sense past the island. He felt relieved at having found nothing.

Of course, he couldn't have known that the cinque devils had already scattered to the far edges of the sky and the six-winged frost centipedes were hidden a kilometer below. As for Han Li, his spiritual sense was indeed far superior to the wyrm, so detection was impossible.

The azure-robed cultivator disapproved the large man’s carefulness, but he smiled and praised, “Brother Jin is truly modest. Apart from Deity Transformation cultivators, what could possibly threaten you? However, this place is quite desolate. If you haven’t brought me here, I couldn't have known that the Dragon Scale Fruit grows here.”

Translator's Thoughts

Have some stuff going on today, so uploading a little earlier than the normal upload schedule, enjoy :)

Chapter 1254: Dragon Scale Fruit

“I found the tree unintentionally in the past. From then on, I came here to pick the fruit once every ten years. In human records, the fruit is said to be wondrous. Once eaten, it would allow one to soar the skies. High-grade cultivators may see it as worthless, but it is rather delicious for those from the wyrm clan like me. But who could’ve known that the spirit fruit is beyond what the human records have described. If one eats it often, it can strengthen one’s body, granting limitless strength. However, this won’t occur without periodic consumption. Very few of these fruits exist in this world, so human cultivators weren’t able to figure this out. However, I’m quite surprised that Fellow Daoist Feng knows many secrets, including the method transport the fruit tree.” The large golden-robed man looked at the azure-robed cultivator with an odd expression.

The azure-robed cultivator calmly replied, “I merely found the ancient remains belonging to an ancient demon. The secrets of the fruit and its method of moving it was left behind on it. It also mentioned that each time a fruit was taken, it would change one’s body very slightly where one wouldn’t notice any effects. But if one were to eat one every day over a long time, one’s body would become as tyrannical as that of a true dragon. But there is no way of knowing that is true.”

“In theory it certainly is possible, but in truth, that can't happen. Even if we gathered together all of the Dragon Scale Fruit trees, there is no way for one person to eat that many of the fruit. Even a single tree is extremely previous to our wyrm clan. Actually, if it weren’t for your complete confidence in the method to transplant the fruit tree, I wouldn’t have brought you here.” The large man said with a solemn expression.

“Hehe, I admire many of the Fellow Daoists in your clan. I wouldn’t dare to deceive you. However, you’ve agreed to my...”

The azure-robed demon cultivator was Feng Xi, the grade-nine Windbreaker Beast that pursued Han Li in the past, the same one who he acquired the Thunderstorm Wings from. And that large man was the Golden Wyrm King. As of current, he didn’t appear to be in his half-dragon form from Green Spirit Island but had the appearance of a normal cultivator.

The wyrm king waved his arm, “So long as Fellow Daoist Feng’s information is correct, I won’t go back on my word. I will present several of the fruit to you.”

Feng Xi revealed joy upon hearing this and saluted him with both hands, “These fruits are greatly useful to me. I’ll have to thank you ahead of time.”

“Enough chatter. We’ll first have to see if your method will work,” the large man said calmly.

“Be at ease. If I weren’t certain, I wouldn’t dare to seek you out. This transplant method was something the ancient demon spent all his life researching. Not only is it useful for the Dragon Scale Fruit tree, but it is also useful for other spirit plants.” Feng Xi said confidently.

The large man chuckled, “I hope that is the case!”

Feng Xi smiled and said nothing else. His body flickered with azure light and flew downward.

“Wait!”

Feng Xi couldn't help but stop the shout.

With a sullen expression, the large man said, “I still feel there is something a miss. I have a faint sensation of dread. I will use a secret technique to examine the area again to make sure there is nothing wrong.”

Feng Xi felt unhappy when he heard this, but he naturally kept quiet. He had no choice but to comply.

With that said, the large man spat out a sparkling golden pearl. With it in his hand, he placed it against his forehead and closed his eyes.

Soon after, light passed by and the light from the pearl gradually shined and strain appeared on the man’s face.

The pearl was a rare supplementary treasure that could greatly increase the power of a cultivator’s spiritual sense.

When the wyrm released his spiritual sense, it was strengthened by nearly a half. It also strengthened the range of his spiritual sense farther than before.

A short while later, the wyrm’s expression changed and he looked around him with sharp eyes. He withdrew the pearl and loudly shouted, “Who dares to sneak up on me!? Reveal yourself!”

His voice shook the air like thunder.

Feng Xi was greatly shocked to hear this and bewilderedly released his spiritual sense.

The wyrm had continued to look at a certain spot on the island with an icy expression.

“I didn’t expect your esteemed self to be in possession of such a treasure. It seems I’ve miscalculated.”

A voice spoke from where the wyrm was looking. Then, an azure streak shot forward, arriving a hundred meters away from them in the blink of an eye. Han Li calmly looked at the two.

“It’s you!”

“That youth named Li!”

The wyrm king and Feng Xi both shouted out following Han Li’s appearance, but the expressions on their faces greatly differed. Feng Xi had delight on his face, while the wyrm appeared cautious.

The large man narrowed his eyes and coldly asked, “What? Does Fellow Daoist Feng know this person?”

“Brother Jin, this is the human cultivator who killed your descendant in the past and stole away a treasure I refined. I didn’t expect him to see him again in the outer seas after so many years. This time, we cannot allow him to escape. Yi! His cultivation...” In his excitement, Feng Xi swept his spiritual sense past Han Li and his expression vastly changed to disbelief.

A golden light flashed from the large man’s eyes and he sullenly said, “Hmph, escape? Haven’t you noticed? This person took the initiative to come to us!”

“Impossible, when I last saw him, he was only a Core Formation cultivator. How has he acquired the fearsome power of a grand cultivator?”

When Feng Xi sensed Han Li’s unrestrained cultivation, his mind grew blank from shock.

“Fellow Daoist Feng spent several hundred years in secluded cultivation. It seems you haven’t heard what happened at Green Spirit Island. There is no doubt that this person is a grand cultivator. His arrival is far from good. We’ll have to deal with him carefully.” The Golden Wyrm King said through a voice transmission.

Feng Xi licked his lips and nodded without a thought.

As the two demons looked at Han Li with hostile expressions, Han Li spoke, “Originally I was only waiting for Fellow Daoist Jin. I didn’t expect the pleasant surprise of finding another old friend. It seems this trip has been well worth it.” He had his hands held behind his back and wore a cold smile after taking a look at the azure-robed demon cultivator.

The large man fiercely smiled and boldly asked, “You wished to find me? Could it be you felt that peak-grade spirit stone was too much for you to handle and you wished to hand it over to me?”

“It is still useful to me, so I’m afraid I can’t let you have it. This time, I’ve come to take your demon core. If you spit it out for me, we won’t have to fight.” Han Li’s calm words left the two demons completely stunned.

The Golden Wyrm King grinned in his fury and bellowed in savage laughter. “You want my core? You dare you to say such words in front of this king? Good, very good! If you want it, come get it!” A layer of dazzling light suddenly shined from his robes, instantly revealing glistening gold armor.

Meanwhile, a blinding light appeared from the old devil and glistening scales appeared on his cheek. A dragon’s tail appeared from the back of his body.

The demon king was sharp, quickly turning his body into a half-demon state for combat.

He flipped his hand, summoning a golden halberd in his hand, silver lightning arcing from its surface. The halberd let out a roll of thunder before blurring out of sight, appearing in front of Han Li just a moment later.

It fiercely struck while covered in lightning.

The demon king attacked immediately without another word.

Han Li’s heart trembled but he was already prepared. Without a thought, he waved the item he hid in his sleeve.

Silver light flashed in front of him followed by the strange appearance of a meter-large lotus.

The golden halberd struck the lotus at its center.

A huge eruption sounded and the silver lotus violently swayed, seven-colored Buddhist light shooting out from its center. The spear was blocked, and the light from the lotus faded, but it appeared undisturbed.

Han Li quickly formed an incantation gesture with his hands as thunder suddenly rang out from his back where a pair of azure and white wings appeared. With a gentle flap, he appeared over thirty meters away. A sneer appeared on his face as he looked at the two demons.

“The Thunderstorm Wings!” Feng Xi shouted in fury upon seeing them and his body shook. Red light flashed in his hands, summoning a pair of short axes.

He waved them, sending them off to Han Li in crimson streaks.

Han Li coldly glanced at the demon and snorted. He opened his mouth and spat out an azure mist. It contained a cauldron that was several inches large, the Heavenvoid Cauldron.

Han Li uttered the Artifact Imprint Technique in his mind and a clear ring sounded from the cauldron. Its lid flew off.

Winds tore towards Han Li as the two crimson streaks arrived above his head. They spun, just as they were about to cleave down, almost certainly about to tear him to pieces.

But Han Li simply extended his finger to the cauldron in front of him and flicked it.

Bang. A mass of azure threads shot out, filling the air with azure light and wrapping around the two crimson streaks.

Feng Xi was greatly alarmed and hastily commanded his treasures to free themselves. But despite his commands, he watched as the axes were dragged into the small cauldron and away from sight, his mental connection to them severed.

When Feng Xi saw this, he was left dumbstruck!

Chapter 1258: The Five Dragon Seas

Before his departure, Han Li brought Shi Jian back to the Heavenly South, so he could go to the Far West and fight for leadership for the Thousand Bamboo School.

As Han Li had already told Shi Jian about inheriting the legacy of Monarch Soul Divergence, he naturally didn’t object to the matter.

When they arrived back at the Heavenly South, Shi Jian left for the Far West of his own accord.

With his current cultivation, it was a trivial matter to take ahold of the Thousand Bamboo School. Han Li also had no worries about this.

As soon as Han Li returned to Devilfall Valley, he immediately resumed his cultivation. Because of the three transplant techniques that Feng Xi had given him, the spirit medicines that were originally restrained in the spatial pocket could now be taken outside. With this, the Fuchisa Cloud Pill no longer had any restrictions for its refinement.

Although the Fuchisa Cloud Pill was a medicine pill for Nascent Soul cultivators, it had overbearing medicinal strength and was quite useful for Deity Transformation cultivators as well.

With this medicine pill freely refined, the originally difficult cultivation of early-Deity Transformation stage passed by quickly.

After a hundred years of bitter cultivation, he reached the peak of early-stage and reached the final stage of the Azure Essence Sword Art, fulfilling it to grand completion.

At this point, taking any further Fuschia Cloud Pills no longer had an effect. And since the spiritual Qi in the mortal world was too sparse, it was impossible for him to enter mid-Deity Transformation stage.

As such, he had no qualms about leaving seclusion.

During his time in seclusion, he encountered several bottlenecks in his cultivation and used the Myriad Distance Talismans to contact that old eccentric Xiang Zhili many times. He also began to divulge some of the information that Silvermoon had left behind for him.

As a result, after countless years of persistent searching, Xiang Zhili finally found a usable spatial node.

This caused the old Deity Transformation cultivators to rejoice. Han Li joined in their celebrations upon hearing the news as well.

As a result, Xiang Zhili, Old Eccentric Feng, Old Devil Hu, and Old Demon Che joined together in a hundred years of preparation and entered the spatial node.

But not long after, three of the four primal soul lanterns that were left behind were soon extinguished. And the one belonging to Old Devil Hu was still lit but it was extremely dim.

Several days later, his primal soul lantern was extinguished as well.

It was unknown if the old devil managed to successfully ascend to the spirit realm, severing its connection to the lantern, or if it dropped into the spatial node.

Eventually, Han Li was informed by a Myriad Distance Talisman of this news by the disciples of these great cultivators, and was left completely completely shocked.

It appeared the danger of these spatial nodes was greater than what he expected. Even with their vast ability, the Deity Transformation cultivators were completely wiped out.

This left him ill at ease.

It appeared Silvermoon’s warning over the dangers of the spatial nodes weren’t exaggerated. It truly was a path that would kill most who go through it.

Fortunately, Xiang Zhili also kept his promise and had already given him the location of the spatial node. Han Li didn’t have to worry about finding it.

As of current, since he wasn’t able to progress his cultivation even an iota further, he planned on taking a look at the spatial node and making full preparations.

After all, the more prepared he was, the greater his odds of successfully making it through.

The information passed through the Myriad Distance Talisman wasn’t something he could rely on.

However, the spatial node wasn’t located in the Great Jin, Heavenly South, or anywhere else he had been. It was in an unfamiliar territory called the Five Dragon Seas.

This was the place in the Great Jin that rarely anyone knew, but Xiang Zhili and the other old eccentrics managed to find a teleportation formation that led directly to the area. He would have to first go to the Great Jin to use this formation.

As this journey would take quite a long time, he decided he would first pay another visit to the Scattered Star Seas.

Having come to a decision, Han Li left behind his puppet to guard the spatial pocket and left Devilfall Valley.

...

On a small island with beautiful scenery, there were several Nascent Soul cultivators gathered together on a stone pavilion on top of a mountain. There were having a lively discussion.

A white-haired old man wearing wide grey robes twirled his beard and smiled at a green-robed woman sitting across from him, “Fairy Bi, I heard you refined a Sweet Fragrance Pill, a top-grade pill that can cleanse one’s essence. Do you think I could ask for some of them?”

Before the fair lady could reply, a middle-aged blue-robed cultivator laughed and said, “Brother Kan must be joking! Everyone knows of your skill in pill refinement. Why would you care for a few Sweet Fragrance Pills? Rather, I will trade for a few of them on behalf of my disciples.”

The old man took no offense, rather answering him with a beaming smile, “Fellow Daoist Zhao is mistaken! My mastery in medicine pills is only towards cultivation progression. Pills with regards to advancing magic power are beyond my expertise. Now that a seldom opportunity to acquire some has arrived, I must take it.”

The green-robed woman spoke with a gentle tone, more expected from that of a sheltered noblewoman, “There is no need to fight one another for them. We can participate in an exchange. I’ve brought most of the Sweet Fragrance Pills with me, enough for the both of you. Please bring out what you wish to trade for them. I hope you won’t disappoint me.”

The old man and the scholarly man both inwardly sighed and politely replied.

These cultivators were holding a small-scale trade meeting.

There were two more people sitting down that have yet to speak. When they saw this, they couldn't help but smile. One of them was a large yellow-skinned man who put a golden wooden box on the table. He pushed it to the center and solemnly stared at the old man. “This is something that I, Fan, and Fellow Daoist Sun used our strength to collect. I will exchange it for two of Brother Kan’s Wyrmshift Pills. Only with these pills can my Swift Wind Python evolve into a wyrm.”

The old man appeared displeased and shook his head, “You hadn’t mentioned it during the last trade. I will not let them go. I also need them for my own Green Spirit Serpent.”

The cultivator surnamed Fan smiled and confidently said, “Hehe, don’t refuse so quickly. You can give me an answer after you take a look.”

The old man felt his heart throb, but he relented, saying, “Apart from the Azure Spirit Mushroom and other such materials, I won’t be agreeing no matter how precious the box’s materials may be.” He then waved his hand and summoned the box into his hand.

He opened it to find a blue glistening pearl.

“A Thunder Whale’s core!” The old man shouted in surprise.

The others were shocked and couldn't help but look in their direction.

Cultivator Fan grinned and said, “Brother Kan is quite experienced to recognize it at a glance. It truly is the demon core of a grade-seven Thunder Whale. Although it is only a grade seven demon beast, it is incredibly rare. It is something Brother Sun and I pursued for three entire days. How do you feel about trading for it now?”

The old man stared at the box in his hand with longing, but the Wyrmshift Pills were something he also had great use for.

He hesitated for a time.

“The demon core of a Thunder Whale is quite rare. Do you think you could let me have a look at it?”

Suddenly, a man’s calm voice sounded from outside. None of the cultivators recognized it.

“Who is it?” Startled, the cultivators all looked outside.

It was unknown when he arrived, but an azure-robed man had appeared outside the pavilion. He appeared young and had a common face, but an exceptional intelligence shined from his eyes.

The cultivators in the pavilion couldn't help but take a look at one another.

None of them recognized this man. And while the pavilion didn’t appear out of the ordinary, it was concealed with restrictions. How could this unfamiliar man find them? And the reason why none of them turned hostile was that, at a glance, they couldn't detect a trace of magic power from his body. But since it was impossible for a mortal to be here, then...

Cultivator Fan hesitated and cautiously asked, “May I ask for your esteemed self...”

The youth saluted them, “It’s nothing. I only came here for directions. If I am bothering you I hope you won’t take offense.”

Of course, this was Han Li who now found himself in the Five Dragon Seas.

Han Li found this place unfamiliar and need to find the lay of the land. He needed to buy a map.

Although the illusion restrictions as of present were uncommon, they couldn't escape his Brightsight Spirit Eyes. As such, when he spotted a gathering of high-grade cultivators, he promptly descended.

“Directions?” Cultivator Fan asked with doubt of his face.

“Fellow Daoist, if any of you have maps of the nearby area, it would be great.” Han Li spoke casually and then glanced at the box and smiled, “Ah yes, the Thunder Whale’s demon core may look intact, but its demonic power has already scattered. Even if you use it to make medicine, it wouldn’t be very useful.”

“Is this true?”

“What nonsense are you saying!”

The old man was startled, but Cultivator Fan’s expression changed to that of fury.

“Whether you trust my words is up for you to decide. It's merely something I said in passing. However, if you are willing to sell me a map, I can answer several of your questions. I am also willing to present a Thunder Whale’s demon core as a gift. Although its grade is lower, it will have more medical potency.

Han Li took out a sparkling blue pearl that was clearly bigger than the one that was brought out before.

The cultivators in the pavilion were absolutely dumbstruck and odd expressions all appeared on their faces. There were a few with bright eyes and others wore disbelief as they all stared at Han Li’s face.

Cultivator Fan finally looked away from the demon core in his hand and shouted with a harsh expression, “May as I ask where you have come from? Have you come here to amuse yourself?”

Chapter 1260: Spatial Node

After flying for five kilometers, the three remained silent. Han Li swept his spiritual sense in the space in front of him and he increased his speed as if he detected something.

After flying for a moment more, the party eventually came to a stop.

Han Li narrowed his eyes and he saw a giant ball of grey light in the air. He felt a chill spread throughout his body.

The ball of light appeared to be mostly round and half a kilometer in diameter. Although it appeared dim and vague, it also appeared unfathomably deep. A halo of light slowly turned within it

Although Han Li already knew the answer, he took a quick breath and asked, “So this must be the spatial node?”

This time, the woman from the trio answered, “Yes, Senior! This is the spatial node that the master and the others entered. In order to maintain the stability of the entrance, the master and the others spent much strength to place a peculiar seal on it temporarily. This way, not only will the spatial node’s stability be preserved, but it will also minimize its spatial fluctuations, preventing the cultivators from the Five Dragon Seas from noticing.”

When she mentioned Xiang Zhili, her face turned somewhat sad. The three clearly understood what it meant for Xiang Zhili’s primal soul lantern to be extinguished.

So it was like that. I was wondering why the spatial fluctuations of this area were so weak. Fellow Daoist Xiang and the others have sealed it.” Han Li couldn't help but sigh when he looked at the ball of light in the air.

But when the three Core Formation cultivators saw this, they glanced at one another as if signalling to one another.

“There was something that I wish to tell you, Senior.” A male cultivator hesitantly said.

“What is it?” Surprised, Han Li looked at him.

“We protected this place for over two hundred years. Although Master Xiang sealed the spatial node, it began to fluctuate for small amounts of time since a hundred years ago. Each time, the intervals between fluctuations became increasingly shorter. Since several years ago, it had already begun to fluctuate once a year, each time lasting half a month.”

Alarmed, Han Li’s expression faintly changed, “So it was like that! You mean the seal on the spatial node won’t last much longer.”

The other man of the trio explained in a solemn tone, “I’m afraid it is so. According to the trend, after a hundred more years, the spatial node will become unstable, given that it doesn’t disappear. I fear that Senior won’t be able to enter the node as easily as Master Xiang and the others did.”

“In a hundred years? That quickly?” Han Li’s expression became unsightly.

“This was merely something we concluded after some thought. Perhaps it is unfounded.” The female cultivator quickly added with a smile.”

Han Li mulled over his thoughts and slowly said, “I can only stay here for a few years and find out for myself. I had better properly investigate the spatial node. I won’t be leaving for some time.”

Xiang Zhili’s disciples naturally didn’t raise any opposition to the matter and repeatedly called out to him.

Soon after, Han Li waved his hand and had the three first return to the island so that he could stay there alone.

In the blink of an eye, only Han Li remained in front of the huge ball of light.

His expression grew varied as he continued to stare at it. The words the trio had said left him deeply worried.

As Han Li pondered, his face grew sullen, ‘If those three were right, then I would have to enter the spatial node within a hundred years. It will be rushed and the danger of failing will certainly be higher. But if I don’t take this opportunity, I may never find another way to enter the Spirit Realm, even if I had another thousand years. The old eccentrics have been searching for one for a long while and didn’t hesitate to enter one as soon as they found one. I had already given them most of the information I had on spatial nodes. They didn’t have much hope of finding another spatial node they could use.’

Han Li remained underneath the huge ball of light for nearly a whole day before returning to the island.

When Han Li returned, the three disciples had already cleaned out the largest of the buildings for “Senior” Han’s use.

When Han Li saw this, he was very pleased. With the addition of their service of guarding the spatial node, he presented to them each a magic treasure and several bottles of medicine pills.

The Core Formation cultivators were overjoyed and expressed their ranks.

Soon after, Han Li used the Myriad Distance Talisman to tell Nangong Wan and the others to dispatch several reliable Core Formation cultivators to the island, also requesting Tian Qin’er to accompany them.

With Tian Qin’er cultivating with the aid of Han Li’s medicine pills, she now spent most of his time researching spell formation and restrictions. She was already astonishingly talented in the field and now that she spent even more time, she has made significant gains. Her mastery over spell formations was now far beyond that of Han Li’s.

He feared he would need the woman’s spell formation knowledge for his journey into the spatial node.

Afterwards, Han Li kept watch over the huge ball of light almost every day for some time. Then he would return to the island and contemplate over the changes he observed.

After a year, Tian Qin’er and three Core Formation cultivators had finally arrived at the island.

Han Li immediately released the three Core Formation cultivators originally guarding the island and assumed direct control of the area.

Although Tian Qin’er was struck at late-Core Formation stage, Han Li specifically gave a bottle of the Returning Sun water, allowing her more opportunities to condense a Nascent Soul.

When Han Li saw she finally arrived, he immediately brought her to look at the spatial node and see whether or not the seal could be strengthened, giving him more time to prepare.

Unfortunately, despite her inconceivable mastery over spell formation, she hadn’t touched upon the subjects involving spatial power. After several months of strenuous research, she eventually found a method to gradually strengthen the seal.

However, this method only had a thirty percent chance of success in stopping the entrance from collapsing.

Although the odds weren’t very high, he had no other options and could only give the method a try.

As for the rare materials it would require, Han Li could only journey throughout the Five Dragon Seas to find them.

This took him about six years with his abilities.

In this time, he discovered that the situation was exactly as Xiang Zhili’s disciples had described. The spatial node would fluctuate every year with each interval in between decreasing and each successive fluctuations becoming increasingly violent.

As a result, Han Li’s original joy from entering Deity Transformation had completely disappeared.

When Tian Qin’er finished her extremely complex spell formation and added another layer of seals on the spatial node, he began to ponder whether or not he should use the opportunity to scour the mortal realm of particular defensive treasures and techniques in preparation to enter the spatial node.

But several days prior from when he planned to leave, a sudden flash of light occurred from outside the sea mist and it arrived at the edge of the mist in an instant.

The light faded to reveal a silver-robed woman of peerless beauty. She appeared in her twenties with a fine brow and an exquisite nose. Her eyes shined brilliantly with silver light faintly stirring inside them.

She examined the mist in front of her a moment and flipped her hand, producing a jade slip. She read through it with her spiritual sense and wore a smile.

“This should be the spatial node that the Heavenly Devil Sect juniors mentioned.”

The woman muttered to herself. Knowing where the spatial node was, her body moved and flew towards in a streak of silver light.

The sea mist roiled and it completely concealed her from sight.

Currently, the island in the mist was no longer guarded as the day Han Li arrived. While Tian Qin’er was placing down the seal on the spatial node, she had also placed several profound spell formation nearby the small island. They possessed more than enough power to trap a Nascent Soul cultivator for a time.

As a result, the silver-robed woman was caught off guard and ran into the formations as soon as she arrived at the island.

When the restrictions were activated the countless lightning birds appeared in the nearby air and swooped down towards the woman. At the same time, a dense barrage of wind blades and ice spikes shot at her.

The silver-robed woman was startled, but she soon let out a cold snort and raised her hand.

An icy white wind suddenly blew out from her body, soon violently expanding in size until the winds blew all around her, creating a violent storm of awesome momentum.

Rolls of thunder erupted from the sky and the storm completely swept away all of the attacks, completely shattering them before they could touch her.

Such loud movements drew the attention of the four Core Formation cultivators stationed on the island, and in their alarm, they flew up from the island to figure out what was happening.

The silver-robed woman looked at all the cultivators that flew up from the island and couldn't help but show her hostility.

She raised her hand to the four cultivators as if she were about to launch something at them.

At that moment, the woman suddenly heard Han Li’s voice at her ear, “Fairy Feng, please show mercy! My subordinates were only following my orders. I hope you don’t take offense.”

“It’s you?” When the silver-robed woman heard this, her face greatly changed, but she was slow to lower her hand.

Chapter 1262: Plundering the Entire World

After opening the wooden box, Han Li discovered that it contained the half-page that he had requested. He then injected his spiritual sense into the green jade slip, and even though there was no way for him to immediately master its contents, it didn't appear to be fake.

Han Li stowed away the two items before turning to the small child with a smile, and he said, "You've upheld your promise, so I naturally won't go back on my word, either. I'll begin using a secret technique right away to slowly sever your avatar from the Heavenvoid Cauldron. However, this process will most likely take several decades, so you'll have to exercise some patience, Fellow Daoist Endless Sky."

"Of course. I'm happy with any arrangement as long as you can free me before your ascend." The small child seemed to be quite content with Han Li's promise, and the projection slowly disappeared.

A short while later, Han Li opened his mouth to expel a burst of green light, which swept toward the small cauldron.

The cauldron rapidly shrank within the azure light before being swallowed into his mouth.

Almost at the exact same moment, the Nascent Soul that was meditating within Han Li's body abruptly opened its eyes and waved its little hand, upon which the tiny azure cauldron appeared before it.

The cauldron was then tossed into the air, following which the Nascent Soul made a hand seal. Azure light immediately radiated from its body, enshrouding both the cauldron and the Nascent Soul within, creating a murky expanse of light that made it impossible to see what was going on inside.

Meanwhile, Han Li's expression remained unchanged as he accelerated slightly, disappearing into the distance in the blink of an eye.

After a while, a mysterious cultivator appeared at various cultivation sites all over the human world, and he specialized in collecting rare treasures, secret techniques, and cultivation arts. These items were either related to spatial abilities or possessed extremely powerful defensive properties.

However, this mysterious cultivator had a set of extremely lofty standards, and there were very few items of that nature that actually appealed to him. Furthermore, he came and left extremely quickly, altering his appearance and attire as he traveled from one place to the next. If he set his sights on an item, he would either forcibly purchase it or bypass any restriction guarding the item before disappearing without a trace.

The extent of everyone's knowledge about this mysterious cultivator was that he was unfathomably powerful, and even Nascent Soul cultivators were like powerless infants in the face of his astounding might. Thankfully, this mysterious cultivator was only interested in collecting treasures, and refrained from attacking people unless it was unavoidable.

As such, even though the sects and powers that had lost those items were extremely unwilling to part with them, they could only concede to their bad luck, and none of them dared to try and track down this unfathomably powerful being.

In contrast, normal cultivators were completely oblivious to the existence of this mysterious cultivator.

Thus, one year flew by after another.

One day, 70 years later, on the peak of a nameless mountain, a mysterious cultivator stood with a blank expression while two elderly men glowered at him from the air above.

The mysterious cultivator was a middle-aged scholar dressed in a set of inky-black robes.

The two elderly men facing him were an early-Nascent Soul cultivator and a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator respectively.

"I don't care who you are, but if you don't want to get hurt, then you better hand over the Shimmering Golden Ring that you stole. For you to be able to steal the ring despite all the restrictions we set around it indicates that you're at least a mid-Nascent Soul cultivator; why would you stoop to such a lowly act of thievery," an elderly man with bushy eyebrows interrogated in a cold voice.

The mysterious cultivator hadn't been traveling very quickly, so they were able to chase him down with ease. However, they were quite perplexed to find that they were unable to glean this man's cultivation base. As such, they refrained from attacking immediately, hoping to test him with their words first.

In response, the mysterious cultivator merely raised a hand and sent something flying toward the elderly man who had just spoken.

The latter faltered slightly before reflexively catching the object, only to find that it was a storage pouch.

A perplexed look appeared on his face.

"The Shimmering Golden Ring is very useful to me, so I'm willing to pay for it with the spirit stones in that pouch," the mysterious cultivator said in a flat and slightly coarse voice.

The elderly man was initially started by the immense number of spirit stones in the pouch, but a furious look then appeared on his face as he roared, "Nonsense! The Shimmering Golden Ring is the most important treasure of our sect! We won't sell it to you no matter how many spirit stones you offer!"

"In that case, I'm afraid I can't help you any further. I won't be returning this treasure," the mysterious cultivator continued in an indifferent voice.

"Hmph, then I'll just have to take back our treasure along with your life!" the other elderly man with a pair of slanted eyes harrumphed coldly. He then opened his mouth and blasted forth a streak of red light, which hurtled toward the mysterious cultivator's head at an alarming speed.

The man was clearly unwilling to return the treasure, so the mid-Nascent Soul cultivator was planning to take it back by force.

However, an incredible turn of events unfolded!

The mysterious cultivator didn't summon any treasures; he merely waved a hand through the air, and a burst of grey light swept up into the air.

As soon as the red light was struck by the grey light, the former immediately receded to reveal its true form, which was a small crimson sword that was several inches in length and shimmering with a cold light.

This sword was currently trapped within the grey light, seemingly having lost the ability to move.

The elderly man who had unleashed the flying sword was both shocked and enraged to discover that he had completley lost his connection with the sword. The elderly man beside him could see that something was amiss, and he immediately swept a sleeve through the air, letting loose a loud cry as a golden rectangular object was hurled forth.

The object swelled drastically in size, transforming into a massive golden brick that came crashing down viciously like a small mountain.

The mysterious cultivator seemed to be quite intrigued by the sight of this golden brick, and he slowly raised his other hand toward it.

An even larger burst of grey light swept forth, crashing directly into the golden brick.

The grey light had only just washed over the surface of the brick, upon which its spiritual light faded, and it rapidly shrank, having also lost the ability to move.

The mysterious cultivator then waved a hand through the air again, and both the crimson sword and the golden brick descended toward him.

The mid-Nascent Soul Stage elderly man was truly getting quite flustered now, and he immediately made a grabbing motion toward the mysterious cultivator.

A massive white hand abruptly appeared above the black-robed scholar before crashing down with devastating might. He was clearly trying to put an end to this mysterious cultivator's life!

However, the cultivator down below merely flicked a finger toward the massive white hand.

Golden light flashed, and a burst of sword Qi swept through the white palm, slicing it cleanly in half and reducing it to specks of white light that disintegrated into nothingness.

The mid-Nascent Soul Stage elderly man's face paled upon seeing this.

Meanwhile, the mysterious cultivator brandished the two treasures in his hands before looking up at the two elderly men with a cold expression.

"If you think I'm offering too many spirit stones, then I'll take these two treasures as well. Are you willing to make the exchange now?"

The elderly men's hearts sank in unison. It was completely incredible to them that this mysterious cultivator could take their treasures from them as if he were merely taking candy from a baby. Just what was that unfathomable grey light?

Neither of the elderly men dared to give a reply.

The mysterious cultivator chuckled upon seeing this before tossing the two treasures into the air and flying away as a streak of azure light.

The two elderly men faltered upon seeing this before hurriedly recovering their lost treasures. They then glanced at the streak of azure light in the distance before turning to look at one another.

After a while, the elderly man with bushy eyebrows hesitantly asked, "Senior Martial Brother, should we give chase?"

"Give chase? Do you want to die? He's clearly just spared our lives. If we continue to pester him, he might change his mind," the other elderly man heaved a resigned sigh.

"But the Shimmering Golden Ring is our sect's most important treasure! What are we going to tell the rest of the sect if we can't recover it?" The elderly man with bushy eyebrows was still unwilling to give up.

"We'll just tell the truth; we encountered someone far too powerful for us to oppose, so we had to let him go. This is the nature of the cultivation world. The strong can impose their will upon the weak as they please, and nothing can be done about it. Come to think of it, the Shimmering Golden Ring didn't always belong to our sect, either; our martial forefathers plundered it from another sect. We can only concede our bad luck now that it's been taken away from us as well. Let's go back. The sect still needs us, so we can't throw away our lives likes this." The mid-Nascent Soul Stage elderly man gave a wry smile before departing back the way they had come from.

The bushy-browed elderly man was rooted to the spot for a long while before heaving a resigned sigh as he also departed from the scene.

High up in the air a long distance away, the mysterious cultivator suddenly stopped after flying for tens of thousands of kilometers.

A series of crackles and pops erupted throughout his joints as he grew taller by around an inch. At the same time, azure spiritual light surfaced over his face, warping his appearance into that of a young man with a set of ordinary features.

This man was none other than Han Li.

He rustled a sleeve and a golden ring abruptly appeared his hand. He gently waved the golden ring, and countless projections were summoned.

"Not bad. In terms of defensive ability alone, this treasure ranks among the top three that I've collected during these past years." A pleased smile appeared on Han Li's face.

"It's about time you went back, Fellow Daoist Han. Otherwise, you'll be in complete despair if the spatial node suddenly collapses before you get back," the voice of a small child chuckled from within his sleeve.

"There's no need to remind me of that, Fellow Daoist Endless Sky; I was just preparing to make a trip back to the island. I've obtained some treasures and secret techniques during these past years, but there are only about four of five that are actually useful. Most of them are very renowned, but they certainly don't live up their reputations; they'll be next to useless once I enter the spatial node." Han Li's expression darkened slightly as he spoke.

"That's rather overly critical of you, Fellow Daoist Han. You're comparing the normal ancient treasures of your human world to spirit treasures like your Eight Spirit Ruler, so they'll naturally be quite lackluster in contrast. In any case, they're better than nothing. Besides, during your travels, you've managed to derive more insights from that half-page of the Golden Jade Tome as well. Perhaps these things will be able to save your life in your time of need," the small child disagreed.

"Perhaps." Han Li gave an absentminded reply as he clenched the fingers on the hand hidden up one of his sleeves before releasing them again.

Unbeknownst to the Endless Sky Beast, the most significant acquisition he had made during the past years wasn't one of the treasures or secret techniques he had obtained, and nor was it the insights he had derived from the Golden Jade Tome. Instead, it was something else...